<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Use Cases | Satellite Report</title>
    <link>/usecase/</link>
      <atom:link href="/usecase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Use Cases</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Use Cases</title>
      <link>/usecase/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Industry Mapping</title>
      <link>/usecase/music_industry_mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/usecase/music_industry_mapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The copyright and neighboring right royalty is the wage-like earning of the music performer, the composer and producer. In popular music performers usually play their own composition and sing their own lyrics. If the musician is self-published, all the three royalties directly pay the artist’s work. If a professional publisher is helping the artist as a composer, or a record producer as a recorded performer, they usually share the respective royalty revenues. In emerging markets fewer, in mature markets more composers are represented by publishers and performers by record labels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification-of-industries&#34;&gt;Classification of Industries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of the creative jobs is that they contain a wide range of activities. Economists and government policymakers classify industries with the &lt;em&gt;Nomenclature statistique des activités économiques dans la Communauté européenne&lt;/em&gt;, in short, with the NACE classification in Europe. This classification is largely harmonized on UN level and can be used to compare almost all economies in the world. The NACE classification has its origins in the economic structure of the middle 20th century, and it is more appropriate for the classification of manufacturing and trading activities, such as car manufacturing, or retail sale of cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry is not even recognized by the NACE classification. For example, musicians often perform music (NACE group 90), compose music (NACE group 90), and at the same time do sound recordings (NACE group 58) and teach music (NACE group 85). Many EU member states do not even create government economic statistics for the NACE 90 classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the main reason why music is not well represented in governmental statistics, which is mainly based on tax returns data from ‘clear’ activity groups, such as sound recordings only. Most creative enterprises, and music businesses are no excemptions, do not have a clear economic activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;microenterprises--freelancers&#34;&gt;Microenterprises &amp;amp; Freelancers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry, for various reasons, is not part of the NACE industry, and music industry data must be mapped from different data sources.  A further difficulty is that music industry, similarly to the other creative and cultural industries, mainly works in freelancer networks and microenterprises.  All over Europe, microenterprises are exempted from many statistical reporting, and they are filing simplified tax and financial reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government statistics are largely based on tax returns and other filings of corporate entities with at least 5 employees.  While most manufacturing or trading activities, or licensed service activities such as insurance or banking, are easy to classify, the creative industries are different.  &lt;strong&gt;Because most creative enterprises are smaller than 5 people, they do not file many data for the government or the tax authorities, and they often carry out heterogeneous activities&lt;/strong&gt;.  For example, the music industry is not even recognized by the NACE classification – the live music and compositions can be found in the NACE 90 class, and the sound recordings in the NACE 58 class, and many countries do not even create government economic statistics for the NACE 90 classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;standardized-mapping&#34;&gt;Standardized mapping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID has been mapping data sources for composer, producer and performer royalties, and other data sources since 2014, based on the standard mapping technique developed originally in the United States and later adopted to the EU ^[Hull, Geoffrey P., Thomas W. Hutchison, Richard Strasser, and Geoffrey P. Hull. 2011. &lt;em&gt;The Music Business and Recording Industry Delivering Music in the 21st Century.&lt;/em&gt; New York: Routledge; Leurdijk, Adnra, and Nieuwenhuis Ottilie. 2012. &lt;em&gt;Statistical, Ecosystems and Competitiveness Analysis of the Media and Content Industries. The Music Industry.&lt;/em&gt; 25277 EN. Edited by Jean Paul Simon. Luxembourg: Publications Office of the European Union, 2012: Joint Research Centre Institute for Prospective Technological Studies (IPTS).].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID designed and administered the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest data collection on how musicians work and earn their living.  Over the course of 6 years we collected anonymous data among musicians related to their touring habits, income, costs, recording expenses and income in various channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 100 stakeholders, among them many collective management organizations helped our work.  Some collective management organizations provided us with anonymous payout lists, which was essential to validate the representativeness of our samples.  We reconstructed the density function of actual payouts, and collected data until our anonymous responses showed a very accurately similar shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the music industry all over Europe is mainly made of microenterprise and freelancers, getting an overal picture of the music industry is very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Export</title>
      <link>/usecase/music_export/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/usecase/music_export/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Music export is complicated to define, because music has a live and recorded element.  In recorded music, the author, the performer and the producer are eligible for copyright and neighboring right royalties.  In live music, the author and the performer are eligible for revenues, and they may or may not have a different nationality, and the concert promoter and booking manager may earn profits in another country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding out the domestic country for the author, the performer and the producer may be a very difficult task. While language is very important in most genres of popular music and in world music, language affiliation is usually a help only in small nation repertoires.  But the language of a song is so important that it may be the target variable of cultural policy tools such as radio or audiovisual quotas.
In classical and world music, the author may not be known or eligible for royalties anymore.  In popular music and some jazz, the author and performer are usually the same artists.  Nevertheless, the complexity remains. In contemporary classical music, jazz and some genres of popular music, language is not an issue because the music is instrumental, or the human voice has no real natural language connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-export--music-import&#34;&gt;Music Export &amp;amp; Music Import&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our view, music export and music import cannot be separated from each other.  Every single European market is a net importer of recorded music, given that there are no music markets where the domestic music market share exceeds 50%.  In live music, domestic music traditionally is market leader in all markets, but the concentration of ticket revenues in large arena concerts and the growth of festivals is threatening the positions of domestic live music.  The competition among songs, label and national repertoires is increasing very significantly with the rise of global streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the recorded markets, radio and audiovisual quotas and an activist role of public broadcasters could maintain a 15-30 percent market share for local artists even in smaller markets. The rise of music streaming and SVOD streaming in audiovisual works makes many of these gatekeepers irrelevant unless they find their audience and role in the new streaming channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the live performances, some countries, especially Hungary, Serbia, Croatia and Poland found ways to create very significant export revenues for programming large festivals aimed at Western European audiences.  While these solutions create vital export revenues for the music ecosystem, i.e. for promoters and technicians, it creates less opportunity for local artists.  There is a growing pressure on domestic bands to extend their tour network abroad, given that the depth of domestic tour network is shrinking due to global and EU-wide small venue problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;artificial-intelligence-and-algorithms&#34;&gt;Artificial intelligence and algorithms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century the total global repertoire of the last 60 years is in simultaneous competition with each other. Close to 100 million sound recordings are available in most markets.  In this global competition, most music is sold by AI algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-ceemid-intelligence-can-help&#34;&gt;How CEEMID intelligence can help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teach new algorithms that help defending the declining domestic markets, and recommend vibrant, new local music to local audiences, and connect them on live performances, too;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extend market insight and tour scheduling for the whole European market, with cost, audience demography, audience taste, revenue forecast intelligence;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design quota schemes and public broadcaster strategies that maintain the public mandate in the 21st century;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design music grants that give the correct incentives to the right people.  Help both foreign market reach and domestic market cultivation with correct ex ante and ex post evaluations;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the complexity of the concept of ‘music export’ in the context of cultural affiliation, language, artist residence, potential separation of composer, performer and producer, music export and import is a difficult topic that requires professional, fact-driven advocacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data &amp; Re-use Of Public Sector Information</title>
      <link>/usecase/psi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/usecase/psi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been involved since 2003 in the creation of official and non-official statistics and in the re-use of public sector information.  CEEMID from the onset took benefit from the re-use of public sector information directive which had been replaced in 2019 with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=1561563110433&amp;amp;uri=CELEX:32019L1024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EU Open Data Directive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European governments, and the EU itself, collects information that is worth billions of euros for the commercial and non-governmental sector. While PSI is generally free, or very cheap in the EU, the re-use of these information sources usually requires deep knowledge and further investment, given that these public information sources were never designed for the secondary public or commercial need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID has built hundreds of indicators from various EU public information sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are creating new music and audiovisual industry related statistics from raw data collected for other purposes, such as inflation measurement or public policy assessment in the EU using our proprietary software and some open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our economic impact assessment tool is, for example, builds heavily on our 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iotables software&lt;/a&gt; that we released as an open source software within the framework of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ropengov.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rOpenGov&lt;/a&gt; collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data</title>
      <link>/usecase/big_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/usecase/big_data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was made out of necessity in EU member states when official statistics are missing key elements of the music or other creative industries.  We had been experimenting with big data sources since 2017, especially to find ways to break down statistics to regional or city level, and to find leading indictors or estimators where government statistics are not available, or available only with a very long time delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://webgate.ec.europa.eu/fpfis/mwikis/essnetbigdata/index.php/Main_Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ESSnet Big Data&lt;/a&gt; is a project within the European statistical system (ESS) jointly undertaken by 28 partners. Its objective is the integration of big data in the regular production of official statistics, through pilots exploring the potential of selected big data sources, and through building and implementing concrete applications. We are closely monitoring such developments, and aim to integrate ESSNet Big Data recommendations into the CEEMID workflow 
&lt;a href=&#34;/publication/creating_better_2015/&#34;&gt;similarly to&lt;/a&gt; earlier ESSnet Culture recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-trends&#34;&gt;Google Trends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Trends creates a fully anonymous sample of Google search traffic. Because of the way Google allows the use of Google Trends and scales results, it is very complicated to use Google Trends across regions and countries.  However, our experience shows that Google Trends is an excellent short-term forecasting tool for ticket sales.  It also means that it can serve as a good estimator for ticket sales for regions and territories where few reliable data sources exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/seasonality_plot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CEE concert seasonality analysis&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geolocational-data&#34;&gt;Geolocational data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3lW8bhQ2fbY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Impact Assessment of Music Industry</title>
      <link>/usecase/impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/usecase/impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Economic impact assessments, such as multiplier calculations, direct, indirect and induced employment-, tax-, value added effects calculations are very often needed for larger grants, or the design of grant calls; illegal state aid must be avoided, for example, when designing film tax shelters; or considering various policy options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such calculations require in the background very large amount of highly structure statistical data, which is very difficult to obtain and work with for non-specialist.   Such data must be accompanied by internal financial data or user survey data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iotables&#34;&gt;iotables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My open source 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iotables&lt;/a&gt; software, released within the scope of the rOpenGov collaboration, is aimed at correctly structuring data and conducting must of the algebraic work related to these tasks. Read 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/iotables_04/&#34;&gt;more about iotables&lt;/a&gt; among my blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am working together with 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://kulkal.cz/?lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KulKal&lt;/a&gt; to make this online cultural calculator usable in all EU member states in the future using some of the features of iotables. Our cooperation started with using some of iotables and CEEMID data in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sharedcities.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Shared Cities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;impact-assessment&#34;&gt;Impact assessment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic impact assessment, apart from the use of highly structured national accounts data and algebraic knowledge require organization or national association specific financial data, accounting data or user survey data.  Currently I am working on various applications to standardize these tools, so that each festival organizer, music export office, film fund and tax shelter and other similar organization can use it according to its needs.  While I do not believe that economic impact assessment for large grants or policy evaluation can be fully automated, the most painful part of the process, the gathering of correctly structured data and the most difficult calculations can be automated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creation of the economic impact analysis of the Hungarian film production and extending the Hungarian tax shelter in cooperation with OrienTax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic impact assessment of the Slovak music industry within the 
&lt;a href=&#34;/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ex ante&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/project/grants/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;grant assessement&lt;/a&gt; for Hungary&amp;rsquo;s Hangfoglaló program&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying Remuneration</title>
      <link>/usecase/pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/usecase/pcr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;private-copying-remuneration&#34;&gt;Private Copying Remuneration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PCR PCR PCR&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Access and Participation surveys</title>
      <link>/usecase/cap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/usecase/cap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cultural Access and Participation Surveys are standardized surveys designed to measure various market-based and non-market based (amateur, liturgical, etc.) cultural activities, including concerts, streaming subscriptions, singing, etc.  They are based on various quantative sociological models and had been standardized by the Eurostat working group 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/assets/eac/culture/library/reports/ess-net-report_en.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ESSNet-Culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEEMID CAP surveys are usually live interviews that allow cross-country comparison, and they are used both for market forecasting, market analytics, royalty and compensation value setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-europe-2013&#34;&gt;CAP Europe 2013&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the data of the CAP 2013 survey for cross-country comparisons and for model calibration, because it includes all EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cee_concert_demography_16x9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Comparative Demography with CAP EU 2013&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-europe-2007&#34;&gt;CAP Europe 2007&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the data of the CAP 2007 survey for understanding cross-country dynamics and long-term changes, because it includes all EU countries. For example, we can determine in which countries visit &lt;code&gt;Generation Z&lt;/code&gt; 20-years-old people more concerts or cinemas than their &lt;code&gt;Generation X&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Generation Y&lt;/code&gt; peers when they were 20-years-old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2019&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2019 survey fieldwork is under way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2018&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2018 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying, the value transfer to YouTube and other media platforms, and the development of the audidence for Hungarian films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2017&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2017 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying. A separate mini-CAP survey was designed to capture the value transfer to YouTube, which was later incorporated into the CAP Hungary 2018-2019 surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-croatia-2017&#34;&gt;CAP Croatia 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Croatia 2017 survey was designed for the creation of the Private Copying in Croatia report, which is prepared for the forthcoming Croatian Copyright legislation changes on private copying and the value gap.  The survey was conducted by Hendall on a sample of 800 respondents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-slovakaia-2015&#34;&gt;CAP Slovakaia 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Slovakia 2015 survey was designed as a part of a larger survey that also incorporated attitudes towards Slovak culture and non-standard survey questions designed by Focus.  The CAP Survey was used to create the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; and to make various legislative impact assessment presentations during the modification of the Slovak Copyright Law on private copying and radio quotas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2015&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2015 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors. It was used in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gvh.hu/sajtoszoba/sajtokozlemenyek/2016_os_sajtokozlemenyek/az_ures_hordozoi_dij_fogasztoi_visszaigenylesenek_.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;competition authority case&lt;/a&gt; related to the Hungarian private copying regime and in a consulting project related to better finding the audience of Hungarian cinemas in their domestic theatrical market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey was conducted by TNS Hoffmann (currently named Kantar Hoffmann.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2014&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2014 was a non-representative, large-sample online survey to pilot the later surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Professionals surveys</title>
      <link>/usecase/musicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/usecase/musicians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The three income streams model is essentially a value chain based model that was 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldcat.org/title/music-business-and-recording-industry-delivering-music-in-the-21st-century/oclc/969999538&amp;amp;referer=brief_results&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;developed in the United States&lt;/a&gt; and adopted by the European Commission’s Joint Research Center for European CCI policy purposes 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ftp.jrc.es/EURdoc/JRC69816.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;pdf download&lt;/a&gt;. We made minor adaptations in the three income model for applicability in Central Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While in the original American model sound recordings are the “main” income stream, currently, especially in Central Europe the live performance stream earns the most income for a typical musician. The author’s stream is the oldest, traditionally and analytically first part of the music industry that includes revenue streams based on musical works exploited by music publishers and via author’s CMO societies such as HDS. In the US it is called the publishing stream, but in Central Europe it is dominated by authors’ societies, so we modified the label.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/three_income_streams_croatia.png&#34; alt=&#34;The CEEMID Adoptation of the Three Income Stream Model&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ceemid-music-professionals-2019&#34;&gt;CEEMID Music Professionals 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEEMID Music Professionals Survey is under way in 12 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-professionals-hungary-2018&#34;&gt;Music Professionals Hungary 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying. Furthermore, we cooperated with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://mokk.bme.hu/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MOKK Centre for Media Research and Education&lt;/a&gt; in a not-yet published research about gender roles and career perspectives of women in the Hungarian music scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-professionals-hungary-2017&#34;&gt;Music Professionals Hungary 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-professionals-slovakia-2017&#34;&gt;Music Professionals Slovakia 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This survey was used  update the 
&lt;a href=&#34;/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-professionals-hungary-2015&#34;&gt;Music Professionals Hungary 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data and intelligence of CEEMID was used in Hungary to create an 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/cstp_15/&#34;&gt;ex ante evaluation&lt;/a&gt; of the new Cseh Tamás Program to support popular music development in Hungary. The programme is currently named Hangfoglaló.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-professionals-croatia-2015&#34;&gt;Music Professionals Croatia 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Music Professionals Croatia 2015 survey was designed for the creation of the Private Copying in Croatia report, which is prepared for the forthcoming Croatian Copyright legislation changes on private copying and the value gap. It was first presented on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/makk15/&#34;&gt;MAKK 2015 conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;musicians-slovakia-2015&#34;&gt;Musicians Slovakia 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This survey was used  to create the 
&lt;a href=&#34;/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; and to make various legislative impact assessment presentations during the modification of the Slovak Copyright Law on private copying and radio quotas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;musicians-hungary-2014&#34;&gt;Musicians Hungary 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This survey was used  to create the 
&lt;a href=&#34;/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34;&gt;Hungarian Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royalty Setting</title>
      <link>/usecase/royalty_setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/usecase/royalty_setting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The copyright and neighboring right royalty is the wage-like earning of the music performer, the composer and producer. In popular music performers usually play their own composition and sing their own lyrics. If the musician is self-published, all the three royalties directly pay the artist’s work. If a professional publisher is helping the artist as a composer, or a record producer as a recorded performer, they usually share the respective royalty revenues. In emerging markets fewer, in mature markets more composers are represented by publishers and performers by record labels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;international-comparisons&#34;&gt;International Comparisons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEEMID international comparison models are based on the implicit econometric model set out in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?language=en&amp;amp;num=C-177/16&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AKKA/LAA vs Konkurences padome case&lt;/a&gt;  which goes far beyond the regional comparison suggested by the earlier Czech 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?&amp;amp;num=C-351/12&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Léčebné lázně Mariánské Lázně v OSA case&lt;/a&gt; for comparing royalty tariffs in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EUCJ declared that “it is appropriate to compare its rates with those applicable in neighbouring Member States as well as with those applicable in other Member States adjusted in accordance with the PPP index, provided that the reference Member States have been selected in accordance with objective, appropriate and verifiable criteria and that the comparisons are made on a consistent basis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our view, setting a royalty tariff, especially when comparison of other market prices is taken into consideration, should follow the principles of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ifrs.org/issued-standards/list-of-standards/ifrs-13-fair-value-measurement/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IFRS 13 Fair Value Measurement&lt;/a&gt; international accounting standard.  This accounting standard was endorsed as an official interpretation of accounting principles by the EU Commission Regulation  Regulation 2012/125, which is in turn a binding interpretation in the light of the directly applicable 1126/2008 EC Regulation.   This document gives a practical guidance on how to use objective data in valuations.   Although the language of the standard is mainly aimed at large corporation with heterogenous balance sheets, as a canonical, cross-country reading of sound accounting principles it is applicable for establishing the fair value of an assets or liabilities, including intangible assets such as royalty-earning copyright and neighboring rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the top level of the hierarchy we find publicly observable prices in frequently traded assets, which is not applicable in our case.  The second level of the hierarchy contains more reliable, publicly verifiable data sources and the third level of the hierarchy non-public information that is objective.  Whenever possible, publicly available and verified information should be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of the music and audiovisual industries makes the use of Level 1 input data almost impossible in a European context, because the vast majority of the industry players are microenterprises and sole solicitors, and even larger entities such as collective management societies and TV stations usually fall in the scope of the EU small- and medium size enterprise category.  With few exceptions, this is the case with HORECA tariff payers, i.e. restaurants, pensions, hotels and other similar establishments.  Micro-, small and medium sized enterprises are usually subject to simplified and limited financial reporting, tax reporting rules and mandatory official statistical reporting rules.  Most of the EU economic statistics are created from tax and financial reports, and in other cases from mandatory statistical reports. Because creative and cultural enterprises usually do not fall into the threshold set for most enterprise statistics data collection, and because of the simplified tax and accounting reports, less official statistics can be created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of high-level valuation input data, we must use level 2 (public) and level 3 (private) data sources that are by nature subject to interpretation.  Such interpretation is subjective in the language of the standard because it is personally made by an objective analyst.  The reliability of the valuation depends not only on the quality of the data, which is the case with level 1 data, but on the sound analysis of a competent analyst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID made a large effort in the last 5 years to use high quality, publicly observable data and private data to create meaningful and objective social, economic and cultural indicators as set out in the EUCJ preliminary decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;market-comparators&#34;&gt;Market Comparators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best models are based on market data and use information on prices and quantities agreed by independent, arms-length contractual partners.  Our market comparator models process all collectively managed and estimated individually licensed uses of music and audiovisual content in a country. It is than possible to compare private copying values, value transfer to media platforms, or individual uses such as radio or television to the total market value of music listening per hour or film watching per hour.  These models require the most data input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used such estimates in the Slovak Music Industry Report, in the calculation of private copying benefits to consumers and value transfer to YouTube in Hungary and Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;direct-estimates--hypothetical-evaluations&#34;&gt;Direct Estimates &amp;amp; Hypothetical Evaluations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct estimates are measuring quantities of unknown uses and they relate them to known market prices.  Hypothetical evaluations ask the willingness of users to pay for uses.  These models are easier to create, require less information, but they can be more easily challenged by regulators, licensees or auditors, because they do not rely only on independent and arms-length transaction data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hedonic-pricing&#34;&gt;Hedonic Pricing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hedonic price models are econometric price models that establish the residua value of music in complex services like hoteling or restaurant services.  We have used hedonic price modelling to establish the value of music use in the HORECA sector.  Technically these models could be used to evaluate the use in television or radio but the data requirements are extensive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
