<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>valuation | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/valuation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/valuation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>valuation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dataandlyrics.com/media/icon_hu5bfde8608118b47b475864b70fd224b4_21674_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>valuation</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/valuation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are Looking for Partners in France</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-10-14-mama/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-10-14-mama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join us for a coffee on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/talk/digital-music-observatory-on-the-mama-convention-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MaMA Convention 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry has envied the television and film industry which has a single go-to-point for data when it needs them, the European Audiovisual Observatory. It started lobbying for a publicly financed music observatory. But we did not wait. The music industry has a tragic track record of failed centralized international data projects. We built Reprex out of a 12-country, decentralized music project. We learned how to utilize hidden, but already existing data and research funds well, and how to manage the data governance among the poisonous conflicts of interests between rich and poor countries, authors vs producers, producer’s vs performers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Digital Music Observatory is not theoretical, it is practical, because it is built around real-life court cases, damage claims, lobbying and PR arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Digital Music Observatory is comprehensive – it contains more than a thousand indicators from all European countries. We have enough data to test the biases of the Spotify or the YouTube algorithm – you would be surprised what the data tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has data available much sooner, in much higher quality and in a more practical format than in the Audiovisual one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-09-23-mce_reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-09-23-mce_reports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reprex was commissioned to prepare an analysis on the justified and not justified differences in music creators’ earnings.  We have posted our most important findings in an earlier blogpost (&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-18-mce/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era. United Kingdom Research Cooperation With the Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK Intellectual Property Office has published the entire report on the music creators’ earnings, and we have made our detailed analysis available in a side-publication. Reprex also signed an agreement with the researchers of the Music Creators’ Earnings project to deposit all data published in the report in the Digital Music Observatory, and to promote the building of the observatory further.
The research questions asked in this report are related to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/music-creators-earnings-in-the-digital-era&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creator Earnings&amp;rsquo; Project&lt;/a&gt; (MCE), exploring issues concerning equitable remuneration and earnings distributions. We were tasked with providing a longitudinal analysis of earnings development and relating our findings to equitable remuneration. The starting point of our work was centred around a very broadly defined problem: how much money music creators (rightsholders) earn from streaming, how these earnings are distributed, and how the earnings and their distribution have developed during the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highly globalized music industry generates two important international reports, as well as several national reports, but these are not suitable for the analysis of the typical or average rightsholder, nor for small labels and publishers who do not represent a large and internationally diversified portfolio of music works or recordings. Copyright and neighboring right revenues are collected in national jurisdictions. Because British artists are almost never constrained by their use of language, and the UK Music Industry is highly competitive in the global music markets, even relatively less known rightsholders earn revenues from dozens of national markets. The lack of market information on music sales volumes, prices for each jurisdiction, and the unaccounted for national, domestic, and foreign revenues makes the analysis of the rightholder’s earnings, or the economics of a certain distribution channel like music streaming or media platforms, impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While total earnings are reported by international and national organizations, they hide five important economic variables: changes in sales volumes, changes in prices, market share on various national jurisdictions (which have their own volume and price movements), the exchange rates applied, and the share of the repertoire exploited. Even worse, the global music industry has no comprehensive database of rightsholders, music works, and recordings – this is the data gap that we would like fill with the Digital Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; highlights some important lessons. First, we show that in the era of global music sales platforms it is impossible to understand the economics of music streaming without international data harmonization and advanced surveying and sampling. Paradoxically, without careful adjustments for accruals, market shares in jurisdictions, and disaggregation of price and volume changes, the British industry cannot analyze its own economics because of its high level of integration to the global music economy. Furthermore, the replacement of former public performances, mechanical licensing, and private copying remunerations (which has been available for British rightsholders in their European markets for decades) with less valuable streaming licenses has left many rightsholders poorer. Making adjustments on the distribution system without modifying the definition of equitable remuneration rights or the pro-rata distribution scheme of streaming platforms opens up many conflicts while solving not enough fundamental problems.  Therefore, we suggest participation in international data harmonization and policy coordination to help regain the historical value of music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_20121/dcms_economics_music_streaming.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of our Digital Music Observatory was brought to the UK policy debate on music streaming by the &lt;em&gt;Written evidence submitted by The state51 Music Group&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;em&gt;Economics of music streaming review&lt;/em&gt; of the UK Parliaments&amp;rsquo; DCMS Committee&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry requires a permanent market monitoring facility to win fights in competition tribunals, because it is increasingly disputing revenues with the world’s biggest data owners. This was precisely the role of the former CEEMID&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; program, which was initiated by a group of collective management societies. Starting with three relatively data-poor countries, where data pooling allowed rightsholders to increase revenues, the CEEMID data collection program was extended in 2019 to 12 countries.The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;final regional report&lt;/a&gt;, after the release of the detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian reports&lt;/a&gt; of CEEMID was sponsored by Consolidated Independent (of the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was eventually to formed into the &lt;em&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/em&gt; in 2020&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, following the planned structure of the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-16-european-music-observatory-feasibility/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, and validated in the world&amp;rsquo;s 2nd ranked university-backed incubator, the Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Validation Lab. In 2021, under the final name &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, it became open for any rightsholder or stakeholder organization or music research institute, and it is being launched with the help of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JUMP European Music Market Accelerator Programme&lt;/a&gt; which is co-funded by the Creative Europe Programme of the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2020, we started investigating how the music observatory concept could be introduced in the UK, and how our data and analytical skills could be used in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://digit-research.org/research/related-projects/music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era&lt;/a&gt; (in short: MCE) project, which is taking place paralell to the heated political debates around the DCMS inquiry. After the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt; gave permission for the UK Intellectual Property Office to reuse the data that was originally published as the experimental &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#recmarket&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Volume and Revenue Indexes&lt;/a&gt;, we came to a cooperation agreement between the MCE Project and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;. We provided a detailed historical analysis and computer simulation for the MCE Project, and we will host all the data of the &lt;em&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings Report&lt;/em&gt; in our observatory, hopefully no later than early July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-contributes-to-the-music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era-project-with-understanding-the-level-of-justified-and-unjustified-differences-in-rightsholder-earnings-and-putting-them-into-a-broader-music-economy-context&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen.png&#34; alt=&#34;The [Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      The &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started our cooperation with the two  principal investigators of the project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/prof-david-hesmondhalgh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof David Hesmondhalgh&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/hyojung-sun/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Hyojugn Sun&lt;/a&gt; back in April and will start releasing the findings and the data in July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;join-us&#34;&gt;Join us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you need high-quality data for your music business or institution? Are you a music researcher? Join our open collaboration Digital Music Observatory team as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/curator&#34;&gt;data curator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/developer&#34;&gt;developer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/team&#34;&gt;business developer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnote-references&#34;&gt;Footnote References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;state51 Music Group. 2020. “Written Evidence Submitted by The state51 Music Group. Economics of Music Streaming Review. Response to Call for Evidence.” UK Parliament website. &lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artisjus, HDS, SOZA, and Candole Partners. 2014. “Measuring and Reporting Regional Economic Value Added, National Income and Employment by the Music Industry in a Creative Industries Perspective. Memorandum of Understanding to Create a Regional Music Database to Support Professional National Reporting, Economic Valuation and a Regional Music Study.”&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel. 2021. “Launching Our Demo Music Observatory.” &lt;em&gt;Data &amp;amp; Lyrics&lt;/em&gt;. Reprex. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-18-mce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-18-mce/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_20121/dcms_economics_music_streaming.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; was brought to the UK policy debate on music streaming by the &lt;em&gt;Written evidence submitted by The state51 Music Group&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;em&gt;Economics of music streaming review&lt;/em&gt; of the UK Parliaments&amp;rsquo; DCMS Committee&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry requires a permanent market monitoring facility to win fights in competition tribunals, because it is increasingly disputing revenues with the world’s biggest data owners. This was precisely the role of the former CEEMID&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; program, which was initiated by a group of collective management societies. Starting with three relatively data-poor countries, where data pooling allowed rightsholders to increase revenues, the CEEMID data collection program was extended in 2019 to 12 countries.The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;final regional report&lt;/a&gt;, after the release of the detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian reports&lt;/a&gt; of CEEMID was sponsored by Consolidated Independent (of the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was eventually to formed into the &lt;em&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/em&gt; in 2020&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, following the planned structure of the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-16-european-music-observatory-feasibility/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, and validated in the world&amp;rsquo;s 2nd ranked university-backed incubator, the Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Validation Lab. In 2021, under the final name &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, it became open for any rightsholder or stakeholder organization or music research institute, and it is being launched with the help of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JUMP European Music Market Accelerator Programme&lt;/a&gt; which is co-funded by the Creative Europe Programme of the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2020, we started investigating how the music observatory concept could be introduced in the UK, and how our data and analytical skills could be used in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://digit-research.org/research/related-projects/music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era&lt;/a&gt; (in short: MCE) project, which is taking place paralell to the heated political debates around the DCMS inquiry. After the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt; gave permission for the UK Intellectual Property Office to reuse the data that was originally published as the experimental &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#recmarket&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Volume and Revenue Indexes&lt;/a&gt;, we came to a cooperation agreement between the MCE Project and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;. We provided a detailed historical analysis and computer simulation for the MCE Project, and we will host all the data of the &lt;em&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings Report&lt;/em&gt; in our observatory, hopefully no later than early July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-contributes-to-the-music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era-project-with-understanding-the-level-of-justified-and-unjustified-differences-in-rightsholder-earnings-and-putting-them-into-a-broader-music-economy-context&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen.png&#34; alt=&#34;The [Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      The &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started our cooperation with the two  principal investigators of the project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/prof-david-hesmondhalgh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof David Hesmondhalgh&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/hyojung-sun/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Hyojugn Sun&lt;/a&gt; back in April and will start releasing the findings and the data in July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;justified-and-unjustified-differences-in-earnings&#34;&gt;Justified and Unjustified Differences in Earnings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stating that the greatest difference among rightsholders’ earnings is related to the popularity of their works and recorded fixations can appear banal and trivial. Yet, because many payout problems appear in the hard-to-describe long tail, understanding the &lt;em&gt;justified&lt;/em&gt; differences of rightsholder earnings is an important step towards identifying the &lt;em&gt;unjustified&lt;/em&gt; differences. It would be a breach of copyright law if less popular, or never played artists, would receive significantly more payment at the expense of popular artists from streaming providers. The earnings must reflect the difference in use and the economic value in use among rightsholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our analysis we quantify differences using the actual data of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#ceemid-ci-volume-indexes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Indexes&lt;/a&gt;, created from hundreds of millions of data points, and computer simulations under realistic scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;justified-difference--changes-over-time&#34;&gt;Justified Difference &amp;amp; Changes Over Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the &lt;em&gt;justified&lt;/em&gt; differences we quantify four objective justifications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The variability of the domestic price of a stream over time&lt;/em&gt; shows a diminishing, but variable value of streams. Depending on the release date of a recording, and how quickly it builds up or loses the interest of the audience, the same number of streams can result in about 28% different earnings. In the period 2015-2019, later releases were facing diminishing revenues on streaming platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The variability of international market share&lt;/em&gt; and international streaming prices in &lt;em&gt;International Competitiveness&lt;/em&gt;. Compared to UK streaming prices, most international markets, particularly emerging markets, have a much greater variability of streaming prices. The variability of prices in advanced foreign markets such as Germany was similar to that of the British market, but in emerging markets and smaller advanced markets–such as the Netherlands–we measured a variability of around 50-80%. Artists who have a significant foreign presence, depending on their foreign market share, can experience 2-3 times greater differences in earnings than artists whose audience is predominantly British.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-in-our-simulated-results-the-depreciation-of-the-gbp-shielded-the-internationally-competitive-rightsholders-from-a-significant-part-of-the-otherwise-negative-price-change-in-streaming-markets&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/reports/mce/currency-environment-1.png&#34; alt=&#34; In our simulated results, the depreciation of the GBP shielded the internationally competitive rightsholders from a significant part of the otherwise negative price change in streaming markets.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      In our simulated results, the depreciation of the GBP shielded the internationally competitive rightsholders from a significant part of the otherwise negative price change in streaming markets.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The variability of the exchange rate&lt;/em&gt; that is applied when translating foreign currency revenues to the British pound in &lt;em&gt;Exchange Rate Effects&lt;/em&gt;. Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#ceemid-ci-volume-indexes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Indexes&lt;/a&gt; index covers the post-Brexit referendum period, when the British pound was generally depreciating against most currencies. This resulted in a GBP-denominated translation gain for artists with a foreign presence. We show that the variability of the GBP exchange rates can add &lt;em&gt;bigger justified differences&lt;/em&gt; among rightsholders’ earnings than the entire British price variation. The exchange rate movements are typically in the range of 30%, or at the level of the British domestic price variations in streaming prices. In our simulated results, this effect shielded the internationally competitive rightsholders from a significant part of the otherwise negative price change in foreign markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were also investigating the choice of &lt;em&gt;distribution model&lt;/em&gt;. , i.e., Both models, the currently used &lt;em&gt;pro-rata&lt;/em&gt; model and the &lt;em&gt;user-centric&lt;/em&gt; distribution, which has many proponents (and was introduced by SoundCloud in 2021), changes the earnings of artists. We think that both models represent a bad compromise, but they are legal, and a change of zero-sum distribution change could potentially increase the income of less popular and older artists at the expense of very popular and younger artists. More about this in our forthcoming report!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our understanding, there are some known and some hypothetical causes of &lt;em&gt;unjustified&lt;/em&gt; earning differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did not have systemic data on the &lt;em&gt;uncollected revenues&lt;/em&gt;–these are earnings that are legally made, but due to documentation, matching, processing, accounting, or other problems, the earnings are not paid. We could not even attempt to estimate this problem in the absence of relevant British empirical data. The problem is likely to be greater in the case of composers than in producer and performer revenues. In ideal cases, of course, the unclaimed royalty is near 0% of the earnings; it seems that on advanced markets the magnitude of this problem is in the single digits, and in emerging markets much greater, sometimes up to 50%. Royalty distribution is a costly business, and the smaller the revenue, the smaller the cost base to manage billions of transactions and related micropayments. We are working with a large group of eminent copyright researchers to understand this program better and provide regulatory solutions. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-05-16-recommendation-outcomes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recommendation Systems: What can Go Wrong with the Algorithm? - Effects on equitable remuneration, fair value, cultural and media policy goals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More analysis is required to understand how the algorithmic, highly autonomous recommendation systems of digital platforms such as Spotify, YouTube, Apple, and Deezer, among others, impact music rightsholders’ earnings. There are some empirical findings that suggest that such biases are present in various platforms, but due to the high complexity of recommendation systems, it is impossible to intuitively assign blame to pre-existing user biases, wrong training datasets, improper algorithm design, and other factors. We are working with our data curators, competition economist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/peter-ormosi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Peter Ormosi&lt;/a&gt;, antropologist and data scientist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/botond-vitos/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Botond Vitos&lt;/a&gt; and musicologist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-08-introducing-dominika-semanakova/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dominika Semaňáková - We Want Machine Learning Algorithms to Learn More About Slovak Music&lt;/a&gt; to understand what can go wrong here (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-08-teach-learning-machines/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Trustworthy AI: Check Where the Machine Learning Algorithm is Learning From&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is always a hypothetical possibility that organizations with monopolistic power try to corner the market or make the playing field uneven. The music industry requires a permanent market monitoring facility to win fights in competition tribunals, because it is increasingly disputing revenues with the world’s biggest data owners. We are working with our data curators, competition economist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/peter-ormosi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Peter Ormosi&lt;/a&gt; and copyright lawyer &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-02-data-curator-eszter-kabai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dr Eszter Kabai - New Indicators for Royalty Pricing and Music Antitrust&lt;/a&gt; to find potential traces of an uneven playing field (see: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/music_level_playing_field_2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solidarity&#34;&gt;Solidarity &amp;amp; Equitable Remuneration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Equitable remuneration&lt;/em&gt; is a legal concept which has an economic aspect. In international law, it simply means that men and women should receive equal pay for equal work. Within the context of international copyright law, it was introduced by the Rome Convention, and it means that equitable remuneration means the same payment for the same use, regardless of genre, gender or other unrelated characteristics of the rightsholder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the word equitable in everyday usage often implies some level of equality and solidarity, in the context of royalty payments, these terms should not be mixed.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-uses-harmonized-anonimous-surveys-conducted-among-musicians-to-find-out-about-their-living-conditions-compared-to-their-peers-in-other-countries-and-people-in-other-professions&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/comparative/difficulty_bills_levels.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) uses harmonized, anonimous surveys conducted among musicians to find out about their living conditions compared to their peers in other countries, and people in other professions.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; uses harmonized, anonimous surveys conducted among musicians to find out about their living conditions compared to their peers in other countries, and people in other professions.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solidarity is present in many royalty payout schemes, but it is unrelated to the legal concept of equitable remuneration. Music earnings are very heavily skewed towards a small number of very successful composers, performers, and producers. The music streaming licensing model has little elements of solidarity, unlike some of the licensing models that it is replacing–particularly public performance licensing. However, in those cases, the solidarity element is decided by the rightsholders themselves, and not by external parties like radio broadcasters or streaming service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The so-called socio-cultural funds that provide assistance for artists in financial need must be managed by rightsholders, not others, and the current streaming model makes the organizations of such solidaristic action particularly difficult. Our data curator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/katie-long/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katie Long&lt;/a&gt; is working on us to find metrics and measurement possibilities on solidarity among rightsolders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-size-of-the-pie-and-the-distribution-of-the-pie&#34;&gt;The Size of the Pie and the Distribution of the Pie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current debate in the United Kingdom is often organized around the submission of the &lt;em&gt;#BrokenRecord&lt;/em&gt; campaign to the DCMS committee, which calls for a legal re-definition of equitable remuneration rights&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This idea is not unique to the United Kingdom, in various European jurisdictions, performers fought similar campaigns for legislation or went to court, sometimes successfully, for example, in Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hot redistribution topic is the choice between the so-called &lt;em&gt;pro-rata&lt;/em&gt; versus &lt;em&gt;user-centric&lt;/em&gt; distribution of streaming royalties. We think that both models represent a bad compromise, but they are legal, and a zero-sum distribution change could potentially increase the income of less popular and older artists at the expense of very popular and younger artists. We instead propose an alternative approach of &lt;em&gt;artist-centric distribution&lt;/em&gt; that could be potentially a win-win for all rightsholder groups; further elaboration of the concept lies outside the scope of this report.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-uses-monitors-volumes-prices-and-revenues-on-the-total-market-and-compares-them-to-calculated-fair-values-by-understand-the-entire-music-economy-we-can-highlight-when-music-is-devaluing-in-various-uses-or-countries&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/reports/mce/listen_hours_treemap_en.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) uses monitors volumes, prices and revenues on the total market, and compares them to calculated fair values. By understand the entire music economy, we can highlight when music is devaluing in various uses or countries.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; uses monitors volumes, prices and revenues on the total market, and compares them to calculated fair values. By understand the entire music economy, we can highlight when music is devaluing in various uses or countries.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is to help focus the policy debate with facts around the economics of music streaming. The legal concept &lt;em&gt;equitable remuneration&lt;/em&gt; is inseparable from the economic concept of &lt;em&gt;fair valuation&lt;/em&gt;, and music streaming earnings cannot be subject to a valid economic analysis without analyzing &lt;em&gt;the economics of music&lt;/em&gt;. Streaming services are competing with digital downloads, physical sales, and radio broadcasting; and the media streaming of YouTube and similar services is competing with music streaming, radio, and television broadcasting as well as retransmissions. It is a critically important to determine if in replacing earlier services and sales channels, the new streaming licensing model (a mix of the mechanical and public performance licensing) is also capable of replacing the revenues for all rightsholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current streaming licensing model in Europe is a mix of mechanical and public performance rights. Therefore, when we are talking about music streaming, we must compare the streaming sub-market with the digital downloads, physical sales and private copying markets (mechanical licensing), and with the radio, television, cable and satellite retransmission markets (public performance licensing.) Our experience outside the UK suggests that these replacement values are very low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;join-us&#34;&gt;Join us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join our open collaboration Music Data Observatory team as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/new-curators/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data curator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/new-developers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;developer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/observatory-business-associate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;business developer&lt;/a&gt;. More interested in antitrust, innovation policy or economic impact analysis? Try our &lt;a href=&#34;https://economy.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Economy Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; team! Or your interest lies more in climate change, mitigation or climate action? Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Green Deal Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; team!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnote-references&#34;&gt;Footnote References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;state51 Music Group. 2020. “Written Evidence Submitted by The state51 Music Group. Economics of Music Streaming Review. Response to Call for Evidence.” UK Parliament website. &lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artisjus, HDS, SOZA, and Candole Partners. 2014. “Measuring and Reporting Regional Economic Value Added, National Income and Employment by the Music Industry in a Creative Industries Perspective. Memorandum of Understanding to Create a Regional Music Database to Support Professional National Reporting, Economic Valuation and a Regional Music Study.”&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel. 2021. “Launching Our Demo Music Observatory.” &lt;em&gt;Data &amp;amp; Lyrics&lt;/em&gt;. Reprex. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gray, Tom. 2020. “#BrokenRecord Campaign Submission (Supplementary to Oral Evidence).” UK Parliament website. &lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15512/html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15512/html/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2013-11-18-cisac_good_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2013-11-18-cisac_good_governance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can review the slides below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/MPGDNcEefEU04I&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel/sgeur13-1037-dantal&#34; title=&#34;Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications in tariff setting&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications in tariff setting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dániel Antal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contents&lt;/strong&gt;:
2. Private copying: blank carriers, technology-driven challenges&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological changes coupled with arbitrage opportunities on the Single Market undermine revenue collection in some jurisdictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benchmarking breaks down if race starts to the bottom. You can adjust your tariffs to the neighbor without in-depth analysis as long your neighbor charges the right amount. ght) owners. Instead of simple benchmarking of fees, basic market variables such as quantities (number of tracks copied in homes), price variables, artist incomes should be compared in an economically meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimating quantities, methodology, survey design Consumer surplus estimate requires reliable quantity estimates that can be best collected on an international basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private copying: various challenges make economic assessment unavoidable. Value of intellectual property changes: technological and cultural changes modify the use of private copies. Economics deals with subjective value that is not indifferent of use. Compensation estimates must be updated when you blank carriers or copying technology enters the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CVM, choice modeling and hedonic pricing results Well designed economic estimates not only justify tariffs, but can create better value proposition for royalty payers. CVM surveys result in well-behaved demand curves for music in public places. Tariffs can be directly validated. Choice modeling reveals that consumers demand music and are rather insensitive to its price. Tariff levels are generally approved. Hedonic pricing reveals the different value added by different restaurants, bars, etc. – crucial for good value proposition and risk sharing with differentiated tariffs. Source: Various surveys designed by Visegrad Investments, conducted by Gfk Hungary, Universitas and Artisjus territorial representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Econometric analysis differentiates high- and low-willing-to-pay customers Improving existing tariff differentiation can lead to a win-win situation. The same amount of royalty can be collected with less pain and less risk of loosing royalty payers, or even increase the number of customers who can experience high-quality 9 Economic analysis helps to create better tariff differentiation that is more accepted by payers without changing the average level of royalties, leading to less loss to royalty-free or cheap repertoire alternatives. Willingness-to-pay survey based on new hypothetical offerings reveal that better differentiated tariffs can significantly improve value proposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public performance: changes in the restaurant, entertainment, retail outlet industry makes periodical tariff review necessary. The structure of restaurant, leisure and retailing changed significantly over two decades, creating chains of restaurants or retail outlets that have significant bargaining power and professional purchasing management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot more information on the slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more in the &lt;a href=&#34;./usecase/&#34;&gt;Use cases&lt;/a&gt; of this website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
