<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open-data | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/open-data/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/open-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>open-data</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dataandlyrics.com/media/icon_hu5bfde8608118b47b475864b70fd224b4_21674_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>open-data</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/open-data/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are Looking for Partners in France</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-10-14-mama/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-10-14-mama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join us for a coffee on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/talk/digital-music-observatory-on-the-mama-convention-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MaMA Convention 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry has envied the television and film industry which has a single go-to-point for data when it needs them, the European Audiovisual Observatory. It started lobbying for a publicly financed music observatory. But we did not wait. The music industry has a tragic track record of failed centralized international data projects. We built Reprex out of a 12-country, decentralized music project. We learned how to utilize hidden, but already existing data and research funds well, and how to manage the data governance among the poisonous conflicts of interests between rich and poor countries, authors vs producers, producer’s vs performers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Digital Music Observatory is not theoretical, it is practical, because it is built around real-life court cases, damage claims, lobbying and PR arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Digital Music Observatory is comprehensive – it contains more than a thousand indicators from all European countries. We have enough data to test the biases of the Spotify or the YouTube algorithm – you would be surprised what the data tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has data available much sooner, in much higher quality and in a more practical format than in the Audiovisual one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-09-23-mce_reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-09-23-mce_reports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reprex was commissioned to prepare an analysis on the justified and not justified differences in music creators’ earnings.  We have posted our most important findings in an earlier blogpost (&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-18-mce/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era. United Kingdom Research Cooperation With the Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK Intellectual Property Office has published the entire report on the music creators’ earnings, and we have made our detailed analysis available in a side-publication. Reprex also signed an agreement with the researchers of the Music Creators’ Earnings project to deposit all data published in the report in the Digital Music Observatory, and to promote the building of the observatory further.
The research questions asked in this report are related to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/music-creators-earnings-in-the-digital-era&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creator Earnings&amp;rsquo; Project&lt;/a&gt; (MCE), exploring issues concerning equitable remuneration and earnings distributions. We were tasked with providing a longitudinal analysis of earnings development and relating our findings to equitable remuneration. The starting point of our work was centred around a very broadly defined problem: how much money music creators (rightsholders) earn from streaming, how these earnings are distributed, and how the earnings and their distribution have developed during the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highly globalized music industry generates two important international reports, as well as several national reports, but these are not suitable for the analysis of the typical or average rightsholder, nor for small labels and publishers who do not represent a large and internationally diversified portfolio of music works or recordings. Copyright and neighboring right revenues are collected in national jurisdictions. Because British artists are almost never constrained by their use of language, and the UK Music Industry is highly competitive in the global music markets, even relatively less known rightsholders earn revenues from dozens of national markets. The lack of market information on music sales volumes, prices for each jurisdiction, and the unaccounted for national, domestic, and foreign revenues makes the analysis of the rightholder’s earnings, or the economics of a certain distribution channel like music streaming or media platforms, impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While total earnings are reported by international and national organizations, they hide five important economic variables: changes in sales volumes, changes in prices, market share on various national jurisdictions (which have their own volume and price movements), the exchange rates applied, and the share of the repertoire exploited. Even worse, the global music industry has no comprehensive database of rightsholders, music works, and recordings – this is the data gap that we would like fill with the Digital Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; highlights some important lessons. First, we show that in the era of global music sales platforms it is impossible to understand the economics of music streaming without international data harmonization and advanced surveying and sampling. Paradoxically, without careful adjustments for accruals, market shares in jurisdictions, and disaggregation of price and volume changes, the British industry cannot analyze its own economics because of its high level of integration to the global music economy. Furthermore, the replacement of former public performances, mechanical licensing, and private copying remunerations (which has been available for British rightsholders in their European markets for decades) with less valuable streaming licenses has left many rightsholders poorer. Making adjustments on the distribution system without modifying the definition of equitable remuneration rights or the pro-rata distribution scheme of streaming platforms opens up many conflicts while solving not enough fundamental problems.  Therefore, we suggest participation in international data harmonization and policy coordination to help regain the historical value of music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_20121/dcms_economics_music_streaming.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of our Digital Music Observatory was brought to the UK policy debate on music streaming by the &lt;em&gt;Written evidence submitted by The state51 Music Group&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;em&gt;Economics of music streaming review&lt;/em&gt; of the UK Parliaments&amp;rsquo; DCMS Committee&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry requires a permanent market monitoring facility to win fights in competition tribunals, because it is increasingly disputing revenues with the world’s biggest data owners. This was precisely the role of the former CEEMID&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; program, which was initiated by a group of collective management societies. Starting with three relatively data-poor countries, where data pooling allowed rightsholders to increase revenues, the CEEMID data collection program was extended in 2019 to 12 countries.The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;final regional report&lt;/a&gt;, after the release of the detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian reports&lt;/a&gt; of CEEMID was sponsored by Consolidated Independent (of the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was eventually to formed into the &lt;em&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/em&gt; in 2020&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, following the planned structure of the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-16-european-music-observatory-feasibility/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, and validated in the world&amp;rsquo;s 2nd ranked university-backed incubator, the Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Validation Lab. In 2021, under the final name &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, it became open for any rightsholder or stakeholder organization or music research institute, and it is being launched with the help of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JUMP European Music Market Accelerator Programme&lt;/a&gt; which is co-funded by the Creative Europe Programme of the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2020, we started investigating how the music observatory concept could be introduced in the UK, and how our data and analytical skills could be used in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://digit-research.org/research/related-projects/music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era&lt;/a&gt; (in short: MCE) project, which is taking place paralell to the heated political debates around the DCMS inquiry. After the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt; gave permission for the UK Intellectual Property Office to reuse the data that was originally published as the experimental &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#recmarket&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Volume and Revenue Indexes&lt;/a&gt;, we came to a cooperation agreement between the MCE Project and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;. We provided a detailed historical analysis and computer simulation for the MCE Project, and we will host all the data of the &lt;em&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings Report&lt;/em&gt; in our observatory, hopefully no later than early July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-contributes-to-the-music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era-project-with-understanding-the-level-of-justified-and-unjustified-differences-in-rightsholder-earnings-and-putting-them-into-a-broader-music-economy-context&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen.png&#34; alt=&#34;The [Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      The &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started our cooperation with the two  principal investigators of the project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/prof-david-hesmondhalgh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof David Hesmondhalgh&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/hyojung-sun/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Hyojugn Sun&lt;/a&gt; back in April and will start releasing the findings and the data in July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;join-us&#34;&gt;Join us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you need high-quality data for your music business or institution? Are you a music researcher? Join our open collaboration Digital Music Observatory team as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/curator&#34;&gt;data curator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/developer&#34;&gt;developer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/team&#34;&gt;business developer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnote-references&#34;&gt;Footnote References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;state51 Music Group. 2020. “Written Evidence Submitted by The state51 Music Group. Economics of Music Streaming Review. Response to Call for Evidence.” UK Parliament website. &lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artisjus, HDS, SOZA, and Candole Partners. 2014. “Measuring and Reporting Regional Economic Value Added, National Income and Employment by the Music Industry in a Creative Industries Perspective. Memorandum of Understanding to Create a Regional Music Database to Support Professional National Reporting, Economic Valuation and a Regional Music Study.”&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel. 2021. “Launching Our Demo Music Observatory.” &lt;em&gt;Data &amp;amp; Lyrics&lt;/em&gt;. Reprex. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data - The New Gold Without the Rush</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-18-gold-without-rush/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-18-gold-without-rush/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If open data is the new gold, why even those who release fail to reuse it? We created an open collaboration of data curators and open-source developers to dig into novel open data sources and/or increase the usability of existing ones. We transform reproducible research software into research- as-service.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year, the EU announces that billions and billions of data are now “open” again, but this is not gold. At least not in the form of nicely minted gold coins, but in gold dust and nuggets found in the muddy banks of chilly rivers. There is no rush for it, because panning out its value requires a lot of hours of hard work. Our goal is to automate this work to make open data usable at scale, even in trustworthy AI solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-there-is-no-rush-for-it-because-panning-out-its-value-requires-a-lot-of-hours-of-hard-work-our-goal-is-to-automate-this-work-to-make-open-data-usable-at-scale-even-in-trustworthy-ai-solutions&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/slides/gold_panning_slide_notitle.png&#34; alt=&#34;There is no rush for it, because panning out its value requires a lot of hours of hard work. Our goal is to automate this work to make open data usable at scale, even in trustworthy AI solutions.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      There is no rush for it, because panning out its value requires a lot of hours of hard work. Our goal is to automate this work to make open data usable at scale, even in trustworthy AI solutions.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most open data is not public, it is not downloadable from the Internet – in the EU parlance, “open” only means a legal entitlement to get access to it. And even in the rare cases when data is open and public, often it is mired by data quality issues. We are working on the prototypes of a data-as-service and research-as-service built with open-source statistical software that taps into various and often neglected open data sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in the prototype phase in June and our intentions are to have a well-functioning service by the time of the conference, because we are working only with open-source software elements; our technological readiness level is already very high. The novelty of our process is that we are trying to further develop and integrate a few open-source technology items into technologically and financially sustainable data-as-service and even research-as-service solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-our-review-of-about-80-eu-un-and-oecd-data-observatories-reveals-that-most-of-them-do-not-use-these-organizationss-open-data---instead-they-use-various-and-often-not-well-processed-proprietary-sources&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/observatory_collage_16x9_800.png&#34; alt=&#34;Our review of about 80 EU, UN and OECD data observatories reveals that most of them do not use these organizations&amp;#39;s open data - instead they use various, and often not well processed proprietary sources.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Our review of about 80 EU, UN and OECD data observatories reveals that most of them do not use these organizations&amp;rsquo;s open data - instead they use various, and often not well processed proprietary sources.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are taking a new and modern approach to the &lt;code&gt;data observatory&lt;/code&gt; concept, and modernizing it with the application of 21st century data and metadata standards, the new results of reproducible research and data science. Various UN and OECD bodies, and particularly the European Union support or maintain more than 60 data observatories, or permanent data collection and dissemination points, but even these do not use these organizations and their members open data. We are building open-source data observatories, which run open-source statistical software that automatically processes and documents reusable public sector data (from public transport, meteorology, tax offices, taxpayer funded satellite systems, etc.) and reusable scientific data (from EU taxpayer funded research) into new, high quality statistical indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-we-are-taking-a-new-and-modern-approach-to-the-data-observatory-concept-and-modernizing-it-with-the-application-of-21st-century-data-and-metadata-standards-the-new-results-of-reproducible-research-and-data-science&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/slides/automated_observatory_value_chain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;We are taking a new and modern approach to the ‘data observatory’ concept, and modernizing it with the application of 21st century data and metadata standards, the new results of reproducible research and data science&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      We are taking a new and modern approach to the ‘data observatory’ concept, and modernizing it with the application of 21st century data and metadata standards, the new results of reproducible research and data science
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are building various open-source data collection tools in R and Python to bring up data from big data APIs and legally open, but not public, and not well served data sources. For example, we are working on capturing representative data from the Spotify API or creating harmonized datasets from the Eurobarometer and Afrobarometer survey programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open data is usually not public; whatever is legally accessible is usually not ready to use for commercial or scientific purposes. In Europe, almost all taxpayer funded data is legally open for reuse, but it is usually stored in heterogeneous formats, processed into an original government or scientific need, and with various and low documentation standards. Our expert data curators are looking for new data sources that should be (re-) processed and re-documented to be usable for a wider community. We would like to introduce our service flow, which touches upon many important aspects of data scientist, data engineer and data curatorial work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We believe that even such generally trusted data sources as Eurostat often need to be reprocessed, because various legal and political constraints do not allow the common European statistical services to provide optimal quality data – for example, on the regional and city levels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/ropengov/&#34;&gt;rOpenGov&lt;/a&gt; and other partners, we are creating open-source statistical software in R to re-process these heterogenous and low-quality data into tidy statistical indicators to automatically validate and document it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are carefully documenting and releasing administrative, processing, and descriptive metadata, following international metadata standards, to make our data easy to find and easy to use for data analysts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are automatically creating depositions and authoritative copies marked with an individual digital object identifier (DOI) to maintain data integrity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are building simple databases and supporting APIs that release the data without restrictions, in a tidy format that is easy to join with other data, or easy to join into databases, together with standardized metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We maintain observatory websites (see: &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Green Deal Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://economy.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Economy Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt;) where not only the data is available, but we provide tutorials and use cases to make it easier to use them. Our mission is to show a modern, 21st century reimagination of the data observatory concept developed and supported by the UN, EU and OECD, and we want to show that modern reproducible research and open data could make the existing 60 data observatories and the planned new ones grow faster into data ecosystems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working around the open collaboration concept, which is well-known in open source software development and reproducible science, but we try to make this agile project management methodology more inclusive, and include data curators, and various institutional partners into this approach. Based around our early-stage startup, Reprex, and the open-source developer community rOpenGov, we are working together with other developers, data scientists, and domain specific data experts in climate change and mitigation, antitrust and innovation policies, and various aspects of the music and film industry.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-our-open-collaboration-is-truly-open-new-data-curatorsauthorscuratordevelopersauthorsdeveloper-and-service-designersauthorsteam-even-volunteers-and-citizen-scientists-are-welcome-to-join&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_contributors.png&#34; alt=&#34;Our open collaboration is truly open: new [data curators](/authors/curator/),[developers](/authors/developer/) and [service designers](/authors/team/), even volunteers and citizen scientists are welcome to join.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Our open collaboration is truly open: new &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/curator/&#34;&gt;data curators&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/developer/&#34;&gt;developers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/team/&#34;&gt;service designers&lt;/a&gt;, even volunteers and citizen scientists are welcome to join.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our open collaboration is truly open: new &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/curator/&#34;&gt;data curators&lt;/a&gt;, data scientists and data engineers are welcome to join. We develop open-source software in an agile way, so you can join in with an intermediate programming skill to build unit tests or add new functionality, and if you are a beginner, you can start with documentation and testing our tutorials. For business, policy, and scientific data analysts, we provide unexploited, exciting new datasets. Advanced developers can &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/developer/&#34;&gt;join&lt;/a&gt; our development team: the statistical data creation is mainly made in the R language, and the service infrastructure in Python and Go components.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-18-mce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-18-mce/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_20121/dcms_economics_music_streaming.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; was brought to the UK policy debate on music streaming by the &lt;em&gt;Written evidence submitted by The state51 Music Group&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;em&gt;Economics of music streaming review&lt;/em&gt; of the UK Parliaments&amp;rsquo; DCMS Committee&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry requires a permanent market monitoring facility to win fights in competition tribunals, because it is increasingly disputing revenues with the world’s biggest data owners. This was precisely the role of the former CEEMID&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; program, which was initiated by a group of collective management societies. Starting with three relatively data-poor countries, where data pooling allowed rightsholders to increase revenues, the CEEMID data collection program was extended in 2019 to 12 countries.The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;final regional report&lt;/a&gt;, after the release of the detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian reports&lt;/a&gt; of CEEMID was sponsored by Consolidated Independent (of the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was eventually to formed into the &lt;em&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/em&gt; in 2020&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, following the planned structure of the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-16-european-music-observatory-feasibility/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, and validated in the world&amp;rsquo;s 2nd ranked university-backed incubator, the Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Validation Lab. In 2021, under the final name &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, it became open for any rightsholder or stakeholder organization or music research institute, and it is being launched with the help of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JUMP European Music Market Accelerator Programme&lt;/a&gt; which is co-funded by the Creative Europe Programme of the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2020, we started investigating how the music observatory concept could be introduced in the UK, and how our data and analytical skills could be used in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://digit-research.org/research/related-projects/music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era&lt;/a&gt; (in short: MCE) project, which is taking place paralell to the heated political debates around the DCMS inquiry. After the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt; gave permission for the UK Intellectual Property Office to reuse the data that was originally published as the experimental &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#recmarket&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Volume and Revenue Indexes&lt;/a&gt;, we came to a cooperation agreement between the MCE Project and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;. We provided a detailed historical analysis and computer simulation for the MCE Project, and we will host all the data of the &lt;em&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings Report&lt;/em&gt; in our observatory, hopefully no later than early July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-contributes-to-the-music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era-project-with-understanding-the-level-of-justified-and-unjustified-differences-in-rightsholder-earnings-and-putting-them-into-a-broader-music-economy-context&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen.png&#34; alt=&#34;The [Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      The &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started our cooperation with the two  principal investigators of the project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/prof-david-hesmondhalgh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof David Hesmondhalgh&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/hyojung-sun/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Hyojugn Sun&lt;/a&gt; back in April and will start releasing the findings and the data in July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;justified-and-unjustified-differences-in-earnings&#34;&gt;Justified and Unjustified Differences in Earnings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stating that the greatest difference among rightsholders’ earnings is related to the popularity of their works and recorded fixations can appear banal and trivial. Yet, because many payout problems appear in the hard-to-describe long tail, understanding the &lt;em&gt;justified&lt;/em&gt; differences of rightsholder earnings is an important step towards identifying the &lt;em&gt;unjustified&lt;/em&gt; differences. It would be a breach of copyright law if less popular, or never played artists, would receive significantly more payment at the expense of popular artists from streaming providers. The earnings must reflect the difference in use and the economic value in use among rightsholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our analysis we quantify differences using the actual data of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#ceemid-ci-volume-indexes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Indexes&lt;/a&gt;, created from hundreds of millions of data points, and computer simulations under realistic scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;justified-difference--changes-over-time&#34;&gt;Justified Difference &amp;amp; Changes Over Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the &lt;em&gt;justified&lt;/em&gt; differences we quantify four objective justifications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The variability of the domestic price of a stream over time&lt;/em&gt; shows a diminishing, but variable value of streams. Depending on the release date of a recording, and how quickly it builds up or loses the interest of the audience, the same number of streams can result in about 28% different earnings. In the period 2015-2019, later releases were facing diminishing revenues on streaming platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The variability of international market share&lt;/em&gt; and international streaming prices in &lt;em&gt;International Competitiveness&lt;/em&gt;. Compared to UK streaming prices, most international markets, particularly emerging markets, have a much greater variability of streaming prices. The variability of prices in advanced foreign markets such as Germany was similar to that of the British market, but in emerging markets and smaller advanced markets–such as the Netherlands–we measured a variability of around 50-80%. Artists who have a significant foreign presence, depending on their foreign market share, can experience 2-3 times greater differences in earnings than artists whose audience is predominantly British.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-in-our-simulated-results-the-depreciation-of-the-gbp-shielded-the-internationally-competitive-rightsholders-from-a-significant-part-of-the-otherwise-negative-price-change-in-streaming-markets&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/reports/mce/currency-environment-1.png&#34; alt=&#34; In our simulated results, the depreciation of the GBP shielded the internationally competitive rightsholders from a significant part of the otherwise negative price change in streaming markets.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      In our simulated results, the depreciation of the GBP shielded the internationally competitive rightsholders from a significant part of the otherwise negative price change in streaming markets.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The variability of the exchange rate&lt;/em&gt; that is applied when translating foreign currency revenues to the British pound in &lt;em&gt;Exchange Rate Effects&lt;/em&gt;. Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#ceemid-ci-volume-indexes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Indexes&lt;/a&gt; index covers the post-Brexit referendum period, when the British pound was generally depreciating against most currencies. This resulted in a GBP-denominated translation gain for artists with a foreign presence. We show that the variability of the GBP exchange rates can add &lt;em&gt;bigger justified differences&lt;/em&gt; among rightsholders’ earnings than the entire British price variation. The exchange rate movements are typically in the range of 30%, or at the level of the British domestic price variations in streaming prices. In our simulated results, this effect shielded the internationally competitive rightsholders from a significant part of the otherwise negative price change in foreign markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were also investigating the choice of &lt;em&gt;distribution model&lt;/em&gt;. , i.e., Both models, the currently used &lt;em&gt;pro-rata&lt;/em&gt; model and the &lt;em&gt;user-centric&lt;/em&gt; distribution, which has many proponents (and was introduced by SoundCloud in 2021), changes the earnings of artists. We think that both models represent a bad compromise, but they are legal, and a change of zero-sum distribution change could potentially increase the income of less popular and older artists at the expense of very popular and younger artists. More about this in our forthcoming report!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our understanding, there are some known and some hypothetical causes of &lt;em&gt;unjustified&lt;/em&gt; earning differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did not have systemic data on the &lt;em&gt;uncollected revenues&lt;/em&gt;–these are earnings that are legally made, but due to documentation, matching, processing, accounting, or other problems, the earnings are not paid. We could not even attempt to estimate this problem in the absence of relevant British empirical data. The problem is likely to be greater in the case of composers than in producer and performer revenues. In ideal cases, of course, the unclaimed royalty is near 0% of the earnings; it seems that on advanced markets the magnitude of this problem is in the single digits, and in emerging markets much greater, sometimes up to 50%. Royalty distribution is a costly business, and the smaller the revenue, the smaller the cost base to manage billions of transactions and related micropayments. We are working with a large group of eminent copyright researchers to understand this program better and provide regulatory solutions. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-05-16-recommendation-outcomes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recommendation Systems: What can Go Wrong with the Algorithm? - Effects on equitable remuneration, fair value, cultural and media policy goals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More analysis is required to understand how the algorithmic, highly autonomous recommendation systems of digital platforms such as Spotify, YouTube, Apple, and Deezer, among others, impact music rightsholders’ earnings. There are some empirical findings that suggest that such biases are present in various platforms, but due to the high complexity of recommendation systems, it is impossible to intuitively assign blame to pre-existing user biases, wrong training datasets, improper algorithm design, and other factors. We are working with our data curators, competition economist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/peter-ormosi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Peter Ormosi&lt;/a&gt;, antropologist and data scientist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/botond-vitos/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Botond Vitos&lt;/a&gt; and musicologist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-08-introducing-dominika-semanakova/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dominika Semaňáková - We Want Machine Learning Algorithms to Learn More About Slovak Music&lt;/a&gt; to understand what can go wrong here (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-08-teach-learning-machines/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Trustworthy AI: Check Where the Machine Learning Algorithm is Learning From&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is always a hypothetical possibility that organizations with monopolistic power try to corner the market or make the playing field uneven. The music industry requires a permanent market monitoring facility to win fights in competition tribunals, because it is increasingly disputing revenues with the world’s biggest data owners. We are working with our data curators, competition economist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/peter-ormosi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Peter Ormosi&lt;/a&gt; and copyright lawyer &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-02-data-curator-eszter-kabai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dr Eszter Kabai - New Indicators for Royalty Pricing and Music Antitrust&lt;/a&gt; to find potential traces of an uneven playing field (see: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/music_level_playing_field_2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solidarity&#34;&gt;Solidarity &amp;amp; Equitable Remuneration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Equitable remuneration&lt;/em&gt; is a legal concept which has an economic aspect. In international law, it simply means that men and women should receive equal pay for equal work. Within the context of international copyright law, it was introduced by the Rome Convention, and it means that equitable remuneration means the same payment for the same use, regardless of genre, gender or other unrelated characteristics of the rightsholder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the word equitable in everyday usage often implies some level of equality and solidarity, in the context of royalty payments, these terms should not be mixed.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-uses-harmonized-anonimous-surveys-conducted-among-musicians-to-find-out-about-their-living-conditions-compared-to-their-peers-in-other-countries-and-people-in-other-professions&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/comparative/difficulty_bills_levels.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) uses harmonized, anonimous surveys conducted among musicians to find out about their living conditions compared to their peers in other countries, and people in other professions.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; uses harmonized, anonimous surveys conducted among musicians to find out about their living conditions compared to their peers in other countries, and people in other professions.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solidarity is present in many royalty payout schemes, but it is unrelated to the legal concept of equitable remuneration. Music earnings are very heavily skewed towards a small number of very successful composers, performers, and producers. The music streaming licensing model has little elements of solidarity, unlike some of the licensing models that it is replacing–particularly public performance licensing. However, in those cases, the solidarity element is decided by the rightsholders themselves, and not by external parties like radio broadcasters or streaming service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The so-called socio-cultural funds that provide assistance for artists in financial need must be managed by rightsholders, not others, and the current streaming model makes the organizations of such solidaristic action particularly difficult. Our data curator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/katie-long/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katie Long&lt;/a&gt; is working on us to find metrics and measurement possibilities on solidarity among rightsolders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-size-of-the-pie-and-the-distribution-of-the-pie&#34;&gt;The Size of the Pie and the Distribution of the Pie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current debate in the United Kingdom is often organized around the submission of the &lt;em&gt;#BrokenRecord&lt;/em&gt; campaign to the DCMS committee, which calls for a legal re-definition of equitable remuneration rights&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This idea is not unique to the United Kingdom, in various European jurisdictions, performers fought similar campaigns for legislation or went to court, sometimes successfully, for example, in Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hot redistribution topic is the choice between the so-called &lt;em&gt;pro-rata&lt;/em&gt; versus &lt;em&gt;user-centric&lt;/em&gt; distribution of streaming royalties. We think that both models represent a bad compromise, but they are legal, and a zero-sum distribution change could potentially increase the income of less popular and older artists at the expense of very popular and younger artists. We instead propose an alternative approach of &lt;em&gt;artist-centric distribution&lt;/em&gt; that could be potentially a win-win for all rightsholder groups; further elaboration of the concept lies outside the scope of this report.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-uses-monitors-volumes-prices-and-revenues-on-the-total-market-and-compares-them-to-calculated-fair-values-by-understand-the-entire-music-economy-we-can-highlight-when-music-is-devaluing-in-various-uses-or-countries&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/reports/mce/listen_hours_treemap_en.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) uses monitors volumes, prices and revenues on the total market, and compares them to calculated fair values. By understand the entire music economy, we can highlight when music is devaluing in various uses or countries.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; uses monitors volumes, prices and revenues on the total market, and compares them to calculated fair values. By understand the entire music economy, we can highlight when music is devaluing in various uses or countries.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is to help focus the policy debate with facts around the economics of music streaming. The legal concept &lt;em&gt;equitable remuneration&lt;/em&gt; is inseparable from the economic concept of &lt;em&gt;fair valuation&lt;/em&gt;, and music streaming earnings cannot be subject to a valid economic analysis without analyzing &lt;em&gt;the economics of music&lt;/em&gt;. Streaming services are competing with digital downloads, physical sales, and radio broadcasting; and the media streaming of YouTube and similar services is competing with music streaming, radio, and television broadcasting as well as retransmissions. It is a critically important to determine if in replacing earlier services and sales channels, the new streaming licensing model (a mix of the mechanical and public performance licensing) is also capable of replacing the revenues for all rightsholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current streaming licensing model in Europe is a mix of mechanical and public performance rights. Therefore, when we are talking about music streaming, we must compare the streaming sub-market with the digital downloads, physical sales and private copying markets (mechanical licensing), and with the radio, television, cable and satellite retransmission markets (public performance licensing.) Our experience outside the UK suggests that these replacement values are very low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;join-us&#34;&gt;Join us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join our open collaboration Music Data Observatory team as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/new-curators/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data curator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/new-developers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;developer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/observatory-business-associate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;business developer&lt;/a&gt;. More interested in antitrust, innovation policy or economic impact analysis? Try our &lt;a href=&#34;https://economy.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Economy Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; team! Or your interest lies more in climate change, mitigation or climate action? Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Green Deal Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; team!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnote-references&#34;&gt;Footnote References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;state51 Music Group. 2020. “Written Evidence Submitted by The state51 Music Group. Economics of Music Streaming Review. Response to Call for Evidence.” UK Parliament website. &lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artisjus, HDS, SOZA, and Candole Partners. 2014. “Measuring and Reporting Regional Economic Value Added, National Income and Employment by the Music Industry in a Creative Industries Perspective. Memorandum of Understanding to Create a Regional Music Database to Support Professional National Reporting, Economic Valuation and a Regional Music Study.”&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel. 2021. “Launching Our Demo Music Observatory.” &lt;em&gt;Data &amp;amp; Lyrics&lt;/em&gt;. Reprex. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gray, Tom. 2020. “#BrokenRecord Campaign Submission (Supplementary to Oral Evidence).” UK Parliament website. &lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15512/html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15512/html/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprex is Contesting all Three Challenges of the EU Datathon 2021 Prize</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-05-21-eu-datathon-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-05-21-eu-datathon-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reprex, a Dutch start-up enterprise formed to utilize open source software and open data, is looking for partners in an agile, open collaboration to win at least one of the three EU Datathon Prizes. We are looking for policy partners, academic partners and a consultancy partner. Our project is based on agile, open collaboration with three types of contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our competing prototypes we want to show that we have a research automation technology that can find open data, process it and validate it into high-quality business, policy or scientific indicators, and release it with daily refreshments in a modern API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for institutions to challenge us with their data problems, and sponsors to increase our capacity. Over then next 5 months, we need to find a sustainable business model for a high-quality and open alternative to other public data programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-eu-datathon-2021-challenge&#34;&gt;The EU Datathon 2021 Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To take part, you should propose the development of an application that links and uses open datasets.&lt;/em&gt; - our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data curator team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your application &amp;hellip; is also expected to find suitable new approaches and solutions to help Europe achieve important goals set by the European Commission through the use of open data.&lt;/em&gt;” - this application is developed by our &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;technology contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your application should showcase opportunities for concrete business models or social enterprises.&lt;/em&gt; - our &lt;a href=&#34;https://economy.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;service development team&lt;/a&gt; is working to make this happen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use open source software and open data. The applications are hosted on the cloud resources of &lt;a href=&#34;#reprex&#34;&gt;Reprex&lt;/a&gt;, an early-stage technology startup currently building a viable, open-source, Open data business model to create reproducible research products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working together with experts in the domain as curators (check out our guidelines if you want to join: &lt;a href=&#34;https://curators.dataobservatory.eu/data-curators.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Data Curators: Get Inspired!&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our development team works on an open collaboration basis. Our indicator R packages, and our services are developed together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/ropengov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rOpenGov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission-statement&#34;&gt;Mission statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to win an &lt;a href=&#34;https://op.europa.eu/en/web/eudatathon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EU Datathon prize&lt;/a&gt; by processing the vast, already-available governmental and scientific open data made usable for policy-makers, scientific researchers, and business researcher end-users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;To take part, you should propose the development of an application that links and uses open datasets. Your application should showcase opportunities for concrete business models or social enterprises. It is also expected to find suitable new approaches and solutions to help Europe achieve important goals set by the European Commission through the use of open data.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim to win at least one first prize in the EU Datathon 2021. We are contesting &lt;strong&gt;all three&lt;/strong&gt; challenges, which are related to the EU’s official strategic policies for the coming decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenge-1-a-european-grean-deel&#34;&gt;Challenge 1: A European Grean Deel&lt;/h2&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-our-green-deal-data-observatory-connects-socio-economic-and-environmental-data-to-help-understanding-and-combating-climate-change&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Our Green Deal Data Observatory connects socio-economic and environmental data to help understanding and combating climate change.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/GD_Observatory_opening_page_hucc13bb64069da5f1e36667b8db70b016_264112_57c130dac4ded4a481b6bb652578a723.webp 400w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/GD_Observatory_opening_page_hucc13bb64069da5f1e36667b8db70b016_264112_47561f8fdb4837762153f21c3e070e9a.webp 760w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/GD_Observatory_opening_page_hucc13bb64069da5f1e36667b8db70b016_264112_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/GD_Observatory_opening_page_hucc13bb64069da5f1e36667b8db70b016_264112_57c130dac4ded4a481b6bb652578a723.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;350&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Our Green Deal Data Observatory connects socio-economic and environmental data to help understanding and combating climate change.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenge 1: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/european-green-deal_en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A European Green Deal&lt;/a&gt;, with a particular focus on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_20_2323&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The European Climate Pact&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/info/food-farming-fisheries/farming/organic-farming/organic-action-plan_en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Organic Action Plan&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/IP_21_111&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New European Bauhaus&lt;/a&gt;, i.e., mitigation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climate change and environmental degradation are an existential threat to Europe and the world. To overcome these challenges, the European Union created the European Green Deal strategic plan, which aims to make the EU’s economy sustainable by turning climate and environmental challenges into opportunities and making the transition just and inclusive for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;http://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Green Deal Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is a modern reimagination of existing ‘data observatories’; currently, there are over 70 permanent international data collection and dissemination points. One of our objectives is to understand why the dozens of the EU’s observatories do not use open data and reproducible research. We want to show that open governmental data, open science, and reproducible research can lead to a higher quality and faster data ecosystem that fosters growth for policy, business, and academic data users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provide high quality, tidy data through a modern API which enables data flows between public and proprietary databases. We believe that introducing Open Policy Analysis standards with open data, open-source software, and research automation, can help the Green Deal policymaking process. Our collaboration is open for individuals, citizens scientists, research institutes, NGOS, and companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenge-2-a-europe-fit-for-the-digital-age&#34;&gt;Challenge 2: A Europe fit for the digital age&lt;/h2&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-our-economy-data-observatory-will-focus-on-competition-small-and-medium-sized-enterprizes-and-robotization&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Our Economy Data Observatory will focus on competition, small and medium sized enterprizes and robotization.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/edo_opening_page_hu9b38541034ae4cd72d69db63a8d7d582_438937_f7d6ad48d03f26f90491141e445c0fab.webp 400w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/edo_opening_page_hu9b38541034ae4cd72d69db63a8d7d582_438937_b69b8300496d31f31709eb8daf02a16f.webp 760w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/edo_opening_page_hu9b38541034ae4cd72d69db63a8d7d582_438937_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/edo_opening_page_hu9b38541034ae4cd72d69db63a8d7d582_438937_f7d6ad48d03f26f90491141e445c0fab.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;336&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Our Economy Data Observatory will focus on competition, small and medium sized enterprizes and robotization.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenge 2: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/economy-works-people_en#:~:text=Individuals%20and%20businesses%20in%20the,needs%20of%20the%20EU%27s%20citizens.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;An economy that works for people&lt;/a&gt;, with a particular focus on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/economy-works-people/internal-market_en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Single market strategy&lt;/a&gt;, and particular attention to the strategy’s goals of 1. Modernising our standards system, 2. Consolidating Europe’s intellectual property framework, and 3. Enabling the balanced development of the collaborative economy strategic goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big data and automation create new inequalities and injustices and have the potential to create a jobless growth economy. Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://economy.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Economy Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is a fully automated, open source, open data observatory that produces new indicators from open data sources and experimental big data sources, with authoritative copies and a modern API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our observatory monitors the European economy to protect consumers and small companies from unfair competition, both from data and knowledge monopolization and robotization. We take a critical Small and Medium-Sized Enterprises (SME)-, intellectual property, and competition policy point of view of automation, robotization, and the AI revolution on the service-oriented European social market economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to create early-warning, risk, economic effect, and impact indicators that can be used in scientific, business, and policy contexts for professionals who are working on re-setting the European economy after a devastating pandemic in the age of AI. We are particularly interested in designing indicators that can be early warnings for killer acquisitions, algorithmic and offline discrimination against consumers based on nationality or place of residence, and signs of undermining key economic and competition policy goals. Our goal is to help small and medium-sized enterprises and start-ups to grow, and to furnish data that encourages the financial sector to provide loans and equity funds for their growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenge-3-a-europe-fit-for-the-digital-age&#34;&gt;Challenge 3: A Europe fit for the digital age&lt;/h2&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-our-digital-music-observatory-is-not-only-a-demo-of-the-european-music-observatory-but-a-testing-ground-for-data-governance-digital-servcies-act-and-trustworthy-ai-problems&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Our Digital Music Observatory is not only a demo of the European Music Observatory, but a testing ground for data governance, Digital Servcies Act, and trustworthy AI problems.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen_hu92ab229c45ce6811fae4daab656e9cd8_255495_ec85a96366983581855edd8646628bea.webp 400w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen_hu92ab229c45ce6811fae4daab656e9cd8_255495_f956c0ab61fc958984be8487ab6a3eee.webp 760w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen_hu92ab229c45ce6811fae4daab656e9cd8_255495_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen_hu92ab229c45ce6811fae4daab656e9cd8_255495_ec85a96366983581855edd8646628bea.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;395&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Our Digital Music Observatory is not only a demo of the European Music Observatory, but a testing ground for data governance, Digital Servcies Act, and trustworthy AI problems.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenge 3: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/europe-fit-digital-age_en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A Europe fit for the digital age&lt;/a&gt;, with a particular focus &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/europe-fit-digital-age/excellence-trust-artificial-intelligence_en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/europe-fit-digital-age/european-data-strategy_en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Data Strategy&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/europe-fit-digital-age/digital-services-act-ensuring-safe-and-accountable-online-environment_en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Services Act&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/digital-skills-and-jobs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Skills&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/connectivity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Connectivity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; (DMO) is a fully automated, open source, open data observatory that creates public datasets to provide a comprehensive view of the European music industry. It provides high-quality and timely indicators in all four pillars of the planned official European Music Observatory as a modern, open source and largely open data-based, automated, API-supported alternative solution for this planned observatory. The insight and methodologies we are refining in the DMO are applicable and transferable to about 60 other data observatories funded by the EU which do not currently employ governmental or scientific open data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music is one of the most data-driven service industries where most sales are currently executed by AI-driven autonomous systems that influence market shares and intellectual property remuneration. We provide a template that enables making these AI-driven systems accountable and trustworthy, with the goal of re-balancing the legitimate interests of creators, distributors, and consumers. Within Europe, this new balance will be an important use case of the European Data Strategy and the Digital Services Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DMO is a fully functional service that can serve as a testing ground of the European Data Strategy. It can showcase the ways in which the music industry is affected by the problems that the Digital Services Act and European Trustworthy AI initiatives attempt to regulate. It is being built in open collaboration with national music stakeholders, NGOs, academic institutions, and industry groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Product/Market Fit was validated in the world’s 2nd ranked university-backed incubator program, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. We are currently developing this project with the help of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/automated-music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JUMP European Music Market Accelerator&lt;/a&gt; program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;problem-statement&#34;&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EU has an 18-year-old open data regime and it makes public taxpayer-funded data in the values of tens of billions of euros per year; the Eurostat program alone handles 20,000 international data products, including at least 5,000 pan-European environmental indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As open science principles gain increased acceptance, scientific researchers are making hundreds of thousands of valuable datasets public and available for replication every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EU, the OECD, and UN institutions run around 100 data collection programs, so-called ‘data observatories’ that more or less avoid touching this data, and buy proprietary data instead. Annually, each observatory spends between 50 thousand and 3 million EUR on collecting untidy and proprietary data of inconsistent quality, while never even considering open data.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-our-automated-data-observatories-are-modern-reimaginations-of-the-existing-observatories-that-do-not-use-open-data-and-research-automation&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Our automated data observatories are modern reimaginations of the existing observatories that do not use open data and research automation.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/observatory_collage_16x9_800_hu47f74f5cdae63c7248c2367b9d148671_353025_0079ea9844f6c5e52b52fd0e627467a2.webp 400w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/observatory_collage_16x9_800_hu47f74f5cdae63c7248c2367b9d148671_353025_ecd6d08ba5e9bac19c8173546f036651.webp 760w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/observatory_collage_16x9_800_hu47f74f5cdae63c7248c2367b9d148671_353025_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/observatory_collage_16x9_800_hu47f74f5cdae63c7248c2367b9d148671_353025_0079ea9844f6c5e52b52fd0e627467a2.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Our automated data observatories are modern reimaginations of the existing observatories that do not use open data and research automation.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with the current EU data strategy is that while it produces enormous quantities of valuable open data, in the absence of common basic data science and documentation principles, it seems often cheaper to create new data than to put the existing open data into shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an absolute waste of resources and efforts. With a few R packages and our deep understanding of advanced data science techniques, we can create valuable datasets from unprocessed open data. In most domains, we are able to repurpose data originally created for other purposes at a historical cost of several billions of euros, converting these unused data assets into valuable datasets that can replace tens of millions’ worth of proprietary data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we want to achieve with this project – and we believe such an accomplishment would merit one of the first prizes - is to add value to a significant portion of pre-existing EU open data (for example, available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.europa.eu/data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data.europa.eu/data&lt;/a&gt;) by re-processing and integrating them into a modern, tidy database with an API access, and to find a business model that emphasises a triangular use of data in 1. business, 2. science and 3. policy-making. Our mission is to modernize the concept of &lt;code&gt;data observatories.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/data/open-gov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/data/open-gov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many countries in the world allow access to a vast array of information,
such as documents under freedom of information requests, statistics,
datasets. In the European Union, most taxpayer financed data in
government administration, transport, or meteorology, for example, can
be usually re-used. More and more scientific output is expected to be
reviewable and reproducible, which implies open access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-whats-the-problem-with-open-datadataopen-govopen-data-problems&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_2021/photo-1490004047268-5259045aa2b4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[What’s the Problem with Open Data?](/data/open-gov/#open-data-problems)&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/data/open-gov/#open-data-problems&#34;&gt;What’s the Problem with Open Data?&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-how-we-add-valuedataopen-govopen-data-value-added&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_2021/photo-1590247813693-5541d1c609fd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[How We Add Value?](/data/open-gov/#open-data-value-added)&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/data/open-gov/#open-data-value-added&#34;&gt;How We Add Value?&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-is-there-value-in-itdataopen-govis-there-value-left-in-open-data-if-its-money-on-the-street-why-nobodys-picking-it-up&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_2021/photo-1533580909002-a2f298d005eb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Is There Value in It?](/data/open-gov/#is-there-value-left-in-open-data) If it’s money on the street, why nobody’s picking it up?&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/data/open-gov/#is-there-value-left-in-open-data&#34;&gt;Is There Value in It?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/br&gt;If it’s money on the street, why nobody’s picking it up?
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-datasets-should-work-together-to-give-informationdataopen-govdata-integrationdata-is-only-potential-information-raw-and-unprocessed&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_2021/photo-1605143185650-77944b152643.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Datasets Should Work Together to Give Information](/data/open-gov/#data-integration)Data is only potential information, raw and unprocessed.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/data/open-gov/#data-integration&#34;&gt;Datasets Should Work Together to Give Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Data is only potential information, raw and unprocessed.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-data-problems&#34;&gt;What’s the Problem with Open Data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Data is stuff. It is raw, unprocessed, possibly even untouched by human
hands, unviewed by human eyes, un-thought-about by human minds.”&lt;/em&gt; [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most open data cannot be just &lt;a href=&#34;#open-data-faq&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;downloaded.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often, you need to put more than $100 value of &lt;a href=&#34;#is-there-value-left-in-open-data&#34;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; into processing, validating, documenting a dataset that is worth $100. But you can share this investment with our data observatories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open data is almost always lacking of documentation, and no clear references to validate if the data is reliable or not corrupted. This is why we always &lt;a href=&#34;#open-data-value-added&#34;&gt;start&lt;/a&gt; with reprocessing and redocumenting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-our-review-of-about-80-eu-un-and-oecd-data-observatories-reveals-that-most-of-them-do-not-use-these-organizationss-open-data---instead-they-use-various-and-often-not-well-processed-proprietary-sources&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/observatory_collage_16x9_800.png&#34; alt=&#34;Our review of about 80 EU, UN and OECD data observatories reveals that most of them do not use these organizations&amp;#39;s open data - instead they use various, and often not well processed proprietary sources.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Our review of about 80 EU, UN and OECD data observatories reveals that most of them do not use these organizations&amp;rsquo;s open data - instead they use various, and often not well processed proprietary sources.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-18-gold-without-rush/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Data - The New Gold Without the
Rush&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-data-value-added&#34;&gt;How We Add Value?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We believe that even such generally trusted data sources as Eurostat
often need to be reprocessed, because various legal and political
constraints do not allow the common European statistical services to
provide optimal quality data – for example, on the regional and city
levels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With
&lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/authors/ropengov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rOpenGov&lt;/a&gt;
and other partners, we are creating open-source statistical software
in R to re-process these heterogenous and low-quality data into tidy
statistical indicators to automatically validate and document it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metadata is a potentially informative data record about a
potentially informative dataset. We are carefully documenting and
releasing administrative, processing, and descriptive metadata,
following international metadata standards, to make our data easy to
find and easy to use for data analysts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are automatically creating depositions and authoritative copies
marked with an individual digital object identifier (DOI) to
maintain data integrity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-there-value-left-in-open-data&#34;&gt;Is There Value in Open Data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A well-known story tells of a finance professor and a student who come across a $100 bill lying on the ground. As the student stops to pick it up, the professor says, “Don’t bother—if it were really a $100 bill, it wouldn’t be there.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this is not the case with open data.  Often, you need to put more than $100 into processing, validating, documenting a dataset that is worth $100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the EU, open data is governed by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=1561563110433&amp;amp;uri=CELEX:32019L1024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Directive on open data and the re-use of public sector information - in short: Open Data Directive (EU) 2019 / 1024&lt;/a&gt;. It entered into force on 16 July 2019. It replaces the &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/ALL/?uri=CELEX:32003L0098&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Public Sector Information Directive&lt;/a&gt;, also known as the &lt;em&gt;PSI Directive&lt;/em&gt; which dated from 2003 and was subsequently amended in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Data&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;em&gt;potentially&lt;/em&gt; useful data that can &lt;em&gt;potentially&lt;/em&gt; replace costlier or hard to get data sources to build information. It is analogous to potential energy: work is required to release it. We build automated systems that reduce this work and increase the likelihood that open data will offer the &lt;em&gt;best value for money&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most open data is not publicy accessible, and available upon request. Our real curatorial advantage is that we know where it is and how to get this request processed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most European open data comes from tax authorities, meteorological
offices, managers of transport infrastructure, and other
governmental bodies whose data needs are very different from yours.
Their data must be carefully evaluated, re-processed, and if
necessary, imputed to be usable for your scientific, business or
policy goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of open science data is problematic in different ways:
usually understanding the data documentation requires
domain-specific specialist knowledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/data/open-science/&#34;&gt;Open science
data&lt;/a&gt; is even more scattered and difficult to
access than technically open, but not public governmental data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-integration&#34;&gt;From Datasets to Data Integration, Data to Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Data is only potential information, raw and unprocessed, prior to
anyone actually being informed by it.” ^[2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are building simple databases and supporting APIs that release
the data without restrictions, in a tidy format that is easy to join
with other data, or easy to join into databases, together with
standardized metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-our-service-flow-and-value-chain&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/slides/automated_observatory_value_chain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Our service flow and value chain&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Our service flow and value chain
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-data-faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-downloading-does-not-work&#34;&gt;Why Downloading Does Not Work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most open data is not available on the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it is available, it is not in a form that you can easily import into a spreadsheet application like Excel or OpenOffice, or into a statistical application like SPSS or STATA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even the data quality of trusted web sources, like the Eurostat website, can be very low. Eurostat just publishes what it gets from governments, and often has no mandate to fix errors.  The data is full with missing information, and in the case of regional statistics, faulty region codes and region names that make matching your data or placing them on a map impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjusting euros with millions of euros, correctly translating dollars to euros, pounds to kilograms requires plenty of work. This is a very error-prone process when done by humans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-open-data-be-used-in-machine-learning-and-ai&#34;&gt;Can Open Data be Used in Machine Learning and AI?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most public and open data sources have many missing observations; machine learning models usually cannot hanlde missingness. These points must be carefully imputed with approximations, which can be very challenging when the data has geographical dimension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removing missing values makes samples extremely biased and your model will learn from omissions, not information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;photo-credits&#34;&gt;Photo Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the Problem with Open Data?&lt;/em&gt; illustration is a photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/8hJQKRIQZMY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cristina Gottardi&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;em&gt;How We Add Value?&lt;/em&gt; illustration is a photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/IEiAmhXehwE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nana Smirnova&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;em&gt;Is There Value Left in It?&lt;/em&gt; is a photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/GcnPjvqRL18&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Imelda&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Datasets Should Work Together to Give Information&lt;/em&gt; is a photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/huRn8ECqADI&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lucas Santos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnote-references&#34;&gt;Footnote References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Pomerantz, Jeffrey. 2021. “Metadata.” MIT Press essential knowledge
series. MIT Press. Cambridge, Massachusetts ; London, England : The MIT
Press, [2015]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Pomerantz, Jeffrey. 2021. “Metadata.” MIT Press essential knowledge
series. MIT Press. Cambridge, Massachusetts ; London, England : The MIT
Press, [2015]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprex Open Data Day 2021</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/talk/reprex-open-data-day-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/talk/reprex-open-data-day-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opendataday.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Data Day&lt;/a&gt;  is an annual celebration of open data all over the world. It is an opportunity to show the benefits of open data and encourage the adoption of open data policies in government, business, and civil society. Reprex is a start-up that utilizes open data with open-source reproducible research: please challenge us with your data requests and participate in our web events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Reprex Open Data Day 2021&lt;/code&gt; will be two informal conversations based on a series of run up introductory blogposts centered around two themes. Because important guests became ill in the last days, we are going to consolidate the two talks into one with less structure.  We want to create an informal, inclusive, collaborative online event on International Open Data Day 2021. Please, grab a tea, coffee, or even a beer, and join us for an informal conversation. We hope that we will finish the afternoon with ideas on new, open-data driven collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;9.30 EST / 15.30 CET&lt;/code&gt;:  &lt;strong&gt;Open collaboration in business, policy and science.&lt;/strong&gt;   Creating evidence-based policy, business strategy or scientific research with small contributions with independent components with incentives.  Short introduction with examples:  joining environmental sensory data and public opinion data on maps; creating harmonized datasets across the Arab world.  Survey harmonization, mapping, data products.  &lt;strong&gt;Scaling up open collaboration: making small organizations competitive with big tech in the big data era.&lt;/strong&gt;  Data sharing, data pooling, data altruism and observatories. The new European trustworthy AI and data governance agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/presentations/reprex_open_data_day_2021.html#/reprex&#34;&gt;click through&lt;/a&gt; a short presentation to familiarize yourself with our topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you &lt;a href=&#34;https://meet.jit.si/ReprexOpenDataDay2021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case studies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are connecting raw survey data about Climate Awareness in Eurobarometer surveys.  Here is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpubs.com/antaldaniel/734594&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproduction code&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;intermediate to advanced R needed&lt;/em&gt;.) You should use the &lt;em&gt;development&lt;/em&gt; version of our &lt;a href=&#34;retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; package at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/antaldaniel/retroharmonize&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;github.com/antaldaniel/retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are tracking changes in the boundaries of provinces, states, counties, parishes with our regions open source software &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpubs.com/antaldaniel/regions-OOD21&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproduction code here&lt;/a&gt;. You will need our &lt;a href=&#34;regions.dataobservatory.eu&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; package which is available on CRAN or in the rOpenGov GitHub repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will talk about how to join this with air pollution data and put it on the map with &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-03-ood_interview_maps/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Milos Popovic&lt;/a&gt;, who prepared this nice choropleth animation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/gif/eu_climate_change.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Milos Popovic&amp;amp;rsquo;s maps made from the case study.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will discuss data observatories (permanent data collection programs), open collaboration (open-source inspired way of cooperation among small and large independent actors) and data altruism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any questions: send Daniel a message on &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt;, Whatsapp or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Hello on International &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OpenDataDay2021?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#OpenDataDay2021&lt;/a&gt; from🌷 the Hague!&lt;br&gt;- We have brought some new data to the light about 🌡climate change awareness &lt;br&gt;- We created some tutorials how to harmonize survey and geographical data&lt;br&gt;- Join us at 9.30 EST/15.30 CET 👇&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/7J7pvi3sPC&#34;&gt;https://t.co/7J7pvi3sPC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ODD2021?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#ODD2021&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/DwkGQaDhW1&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/DwkGQaDhW1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; dataandlyrics (@dataandlyrics) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dataandlyrics/status/1368149535436996609?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data Day Interview: Mapping Data with Milos Popovic</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-03-ood_interview_maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 22:23:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-03-ood_interview_maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Milos Popovic is a researcher, a data scientist, Marie Curie postdoc &amp;amp; Top 10 dataviz &amp;amp; R contributor on Twitter according to NodeXL. He took part in policy debates about terrorism and military intervention and appeared on a number of TV channels including N1 (the CNN affiliate in the Western Balkans), Serbian National Television and Al-Jazeera Balkans. My research interests are at the intersection of civil war dynamics and postwar politics in the Balkans. He is going to join the Data &amp;amp; Lyrics team on International Open Data Day to help us put harmonized environmental degradation perception and environmental sensory data on maps. We asked him four questions about his passion, mapping data. Please join us 6 March 2021 9.30 EST / 15.30 CET for an informal digital coffee.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a researcher, why are you so much drawn into maps? Is this connected to your interest in territorial conflicts, or you have some other inspiration?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a great question that really makes me pause and look back at the past 5 years. My mapping story started out of curiosity: I found interesting data on the post-WWII violence in Serbia and thought how cool it would be to make a map in R. I quickly made an unimpressive choropleth map and noticed some unexpected patterns. Then I realized just how much unused violence and census data sits out there while we have no clue about geographic patterns. So, it began. I started off with map-making but my curiosity took me to the world of georeferencing and geospatial analysis. In the process, I created over 300 maps hosted on my website as well as dozens of shapefiles from the scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to think that my interest is linked to growing up in a war-torn country. But, as my map-making evolved, I discovered that my passion is to use maps as a way to democratize the data: to take the scores of unused, and often buried datasets, place them on the map and share the dataviz with people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you show us an example of the best use of mapped data, and the best map that you have personally created? What is their distinctive value?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m immensely proud of my work that required making the shapefiles from the scratch. For instance, my shapefile of over 1500 Kosovo cadastral settlements came into being after I turned dozens of high-resolution raster files into a shapefile fully compatible with Open Street Maps. After months of hard work, I managed to merge the shapefile with the 2011 Kosovo census and present several laser-focused demographic maps to my audience. Same goes for the settlement shapefile of &lt;em&gt;Republika Srpska&lt;/em&gt; [the Serb-speaking entity of Bosnia-Herzegovina — the editor], which I made out of a pdf file and merged with the 2013 census data. Whereas most existing maps take a bird’s eye view, my work offers a more fine-grained view of the local dynamics to stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another similar undertaking was my transformation of the pre-WWII German military map of Yugoslavia into a unique shapefile of a few hundred Yugoslav municipalities. I combined this shapefile with the 1931 census data, 80 years after it was first published (better late than never!). It took me almost a year to complete this tremendous project but I enjoyed every bit of it. I have teamed up with &lt;a href=&#34;https://aleksandarpopovic.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;my brother&lt;/a&gt; who is a web developer and we even made &lt;a href=&#34;https://milosp.info/maps/interactive/census1931/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;an interactive map of Yugoslavia based on the 1931 census&lt;/a&gt;.[&lt;em&gt;The screenshot of this interactive map is the top image in the post &amp;ndash; the editor&lt;/em&gt;] We hope this project would serve not only scholars but also history enthusiasts to better understand a history of the country that is no more.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-check-out-miloss-beautiful-static-and-interactive-maps-on-httpsmilospinfohttpsmilospinfo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Check out Milos’s beautiful static and interactive maps on [https://milosp.info/]([https://milosp.info/)&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-03-03-ood_interview_maps/milos_popovic_internet_never_hu60318c7103cd3cda99083a1606023875_427407_41f50802dd0acae2c711028c6b253301.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-03-03-ood_interview_maps/milos_popovic_internet_never_hu60318c7103cd3cda99083a1606023875_427407_466825eaeae382dc3e698e203ad5c129.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-03-03-ood_interview_maps/milos_popovic_internet_never_hu60318c7103cd3cda99083a1606023875_427407_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-03-ood_interview_maps/milos_popovic_internet_never_hu60318c7103cd3cda99083a1606023875_427407_41f50802dd0acae2c711028c6b253301.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;626&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Check out Milos’s beautiful static and interactive maps on &lt;a href=&#34;[https://milosp.info/&#34;&gt;https://milosp.info/&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think about collaboration based on open data and open-source software that processes such data?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a fantastic opportunity for small teams to bypass traditional gatekeepers such as state institutions or big companies and use open source apps for the benefit of their local communities. For example, the access to Open Street Map allows small teams to map pressing communal issues as crime, deceases, or environmental degradation and come up with innovative solutions. In my work, too, I used OSM has helped me create several fine-grained maps that shed more light on local problems in Serbia such as pollution, car accidents or violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are hoping to bring together environmental, sensory data and public attitude data on environmental issues? How can mapping help? What do you expect from this project?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than ever, we are compelled to figure out how maladies spreads locally. Without mapping the hotspots, our understanding of the consequences of, for example, viral transmission or pollution is shrouded with a lot of uncertainty. We might have no clue how environmental issues shape public attitudes in localities until we use the mapping to turn on the light. Mapping would help this project pin down geographic clusters that require immediate attention from the private and public stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please [join us](&lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/talk/reprex-Open&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://reprex.nl/talk/reprex-Open&lt;/a&gt; data-day-2021/) for a digital coffee, tea or beer on International Open Data Day - we will put never seen data on maps, and discuss how to build successful open collaborations, with little, independent contributions to build large data observatories. Make sure you check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://milosp.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Milos&amp;rsquo; amazing website&lt;/a&gt;, too!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save The Date: Open Data Day 2021 on 6th March</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-03-save-the-date-odd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 09:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-03-save-the-date-odd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open data is not only a cheap resource for scientists or NGOs, but a serious business opportunity for the business sector, too. The European Union has been promoting the business reuse of data collected at the taxpayer’s expense since 2003 – and our team members have been involved since the beginning. This is a particularly good deal opportunity for small businesses and organizations that do not have a big data infrastructure or budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;Open Data Day 2021&lt;/strong&gt;, our goal is to demonstrate how our open-source software can connect different sources and types of data to generate new knowledge about environmental sustainability by combining several perspectives: from air pollution sensors, public perceptions and opinions, and government policies. We will show how to connect environmental sensory data, environmental spending, and opinion polling data about the environment together with open-source software from open data sources, to follow the four highlighted topics of #ODD21. We’ll offer tutorials, webinars, and Q&amp;amp;A based around these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-we-will-show-how-to-use-open-access-survey-data-and-how-to-plot-results-on-a-map-this-dataset-was-used-in-an-empirical-study-on-the-structural-conditions-of-book-piracy-in-global-and-european-academiahttpsreprexnlpublicationscholarly_pirate_libraries_2020-published-in-plos-one&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;We will show how to use open access survey data, and how to plot results on a map. This dataset was used in an [empirical study on the structural conditions of book piracy in global and European academia](https://reprex.nl/publication/scholarly_pirate_libraries_2020/) published in PLOS One.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      We will show how to use open access survey data, and how to plot results on a map. This dataset was used in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/publication/scholarly_pirate_libraries_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;empirical study on the structural conditions of book piracy in global and European academia&lt;/a&gt; published in PLOS One.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who would think that you can use &amp;ldquo;raw inflation data components&amp;rdquo; to create &lt;em&gt;cultural&lt;/em&gt; indicators? Working with open data often feels like working with raw diamonds, because most open data was originally collected and processed for a different use that you would have in mind. But this is our expertise – if you want to see public financing, opinion polling or sensory information about environmental and sustainability issues, &lt;strong&gt;do challenge us&lt;/strong&gt;. Be part of our Open Data Day, tell us about your research needs, and we’ll bring some open data to the surface to start the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opendataday.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Data Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Our Event Page](&lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/talk/Open&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://reprex.nl/talk/Open&lt;/a&gt; data-day-2021/)  &amp;ndash; with more details about guests and topics every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save The Date: Open Data Day 2021 on 6th March</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-12-opendataday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 09:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-12-opendataday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open data is not only a cheap resource for scientists or NGOs, but a serious business opportunity for the business sector, too. The European Union has been promoting the business reuse of data collected at the taxpayer’s expense since 2003 – and our team members have been involved since the beginning. This is a particularly good deal opportunity for small businesses and organizations that do not have a big data infrastructure or budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;Open Data Day 2021&lt;/strong&gt;, our goal is to demonstrate how our open-source software can connect different sources and types of data to generate new knowledge about environmental sustainability by combining several perspectives: from air pollution sensors, public perceptions and opinions, and government policies. We will show how to connect environmental sensory data, environmental spending, and opinion polling data about the environment together with open-source software from open data sources, to follow the four highlighted topics of #ODD21. We’ll offer tutorials, webinars, and Q&amp;amp;A based around these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-we-will-show-how-to-use-open-access-survey-data-and-how-to-plot-results-on-a-map-this-dataset-was-used-in-an-empirical-study-on-the-structural-conditions-of-book-piracy-in-global-and-european-academiahttpsreprexnlpublicationscholarly_pirate_libraries_2020-published-in-plos-one&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;We will show how to use open access survey data, and how to plot results on a map. This dataset was used in an [empirical study on the structural conditions of book piracy in global and European academia](https://reprex.nl/publication/scholarly_pirate_libraries_2020/) published in PLOS One.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      We will show how to use open access survey data, and how to plot results on a map. This dataset was used in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/publication/scholarly_pirate_libraries_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;empirical study on the structural conditions of book piracy in global and European academia&lt;/a&gt; published in PLOS One.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who would think that you can use &amp;ldquo;raw inflation data components&amp;rdquo; to create &lt;em&gt;cultural&lt;/em&gt; indicators? Working with open data often feels like working with raw diamonds, because most open data was originally collected and processed for a different use that you would have in mind. But this is our expertise – if you want to see public financing, opinion polling or sensory information about environmental and sustainability issues, &lt;strong&gt;do challenge us&lt;/strong&gt;. Be part of our Open Data Day, tell us about your research needs, and we’ll bring some open data to the surface to start the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opendataday.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Data Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Our Event Page](&lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/talk/Open&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://reprex.nl/talk/Open&lt;/a&gt; data-day-2021/)  &amp;ndash; with more details about guests and topics every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Audience: Size Of Music Discovery Age Populations In Europe</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-20-music-discovery-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 15:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-20-music-discovery-population/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is various global and national research available on the music discovery demography.  People usually discover new music in their young age as they are forming their own personal identity with their peer group.  This process mainly happens in the school, where similarly aged, educated young people spend much of their day together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music discovery phase is strongly related to the time when most people get their music education: their skills to listen to music, play music or sing, and to compose new music. Investment into music education pays of in later age: people with more diverse music education, for example, with the ability to play music, tend to visit concerts more or discover more music in later life stages.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-annual-growth-top-chart-and-total-growth-lower-chart-of-the-15-24-years-old-population-in-select-european-countries&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;comparative/music_discovery_population.png&#34; alt=&#34;The annual growth (top chart) and total growth (lower chart) of the 15-24 years-old population in select European countries.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The annual growth (top chart) and total growth (lower chart) of the 15-24 years-old population in select European countries.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For practical reasons and supported by academic research, we chose the age group 15-24 as the key age group for music discovery.  We placed the national population of the music discovery age group in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.music.dataobservatory.eu/music-society.html#audiences&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music &amp;amp; Society&lt;/a&gt; pillar of the Demo Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changes across Europe are dramatic: in Latvia and the Baltic states, the music discovery age population decreased by 60% since the countries (re-)gained independence in 1991. Musicians and their organizations must work hard in these countries on developing export strategies if they want to maintain the market and audience of their music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some European countries, for example, the Netherlands and Turkey have significantly increased their future audiences. In Turkey this is mainly related to population growth, in the Netherlands to immigration. Countries with a growing young population have a strong position for their music business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all lost in the Baltics and other countries where the &lt;code&gt;music discovery age population &lt;/code&gt; is shrinking.  Much of the lost young population migrated to the United Kingdom and other parts of Europe. If artists and their association in these countries find a way to connect with these new diaspora, their market loss will be far less dramatic. Connecting to the diaspora is the most natural way to start exporting new music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the data from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.music.dataobservatory.eu/music-society.html#audiences&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earlier this year we introduced some in-depth comparison of music audiences in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/audience.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;. Central European Music Industry Report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo credit &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:TeenStar_2013_Winner.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LauraMayM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product/Market Fit Validation in Yes!Delft</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 15:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate our product market/fit in two segments, business/policy research and scientific research, with a supporting role given to data journalism. Because we want to follow a bootstrapping strategy, we must focus on those clients where we find the highest value proposition, which is of course easier said than done.  We see much interest in our offering from other continents, therefore we truly welcome the opportunity that we can do this on a truly global business canvas in one of the worlds’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/news/yesdelft-among-the-top-5-business-incubators-in-the-world/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;top five incubators&lt;/a&gt;, the number 2 university-backed incubator in the world, second to none in Europe, in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/focus-areas/artificial-intelligence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain&lt;/a&gt; Validation Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Europe hundreds of thousands of microenterprises, such as record labels, video producers or book publishers are facing data and AI giants like Google’s YouTube, Apple Music, Spotify, Netflix or Amazon. If the recommendation engines of these giants do not recommend their songs, films or books, then their investments are doomed to fail, because about half of the global sales are driven by AI algorithms. When they make a claim for the missing money, they will immediately find themselves in a dispute with gigabytes of data that they can only handle with a data scientist, even though they do not even have an IT professional or an HR professional to make the hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An awful lot of money, creativity and real values are at stake, and we want to be on the creator’s side, their technician’s side, their manager’s side when they want to get a fair share from the pie and they want to help these industry leader to make the pie grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unesco.org/new/en/culture/themes/creativity/arts-education/research-cooperation/observatories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UNESCO&lt;/a&gt; and the EU have been promoting as an organizational solution the fragmentation problem with the so-called data observatories that are pooling the business, policy, and scientific research needs of various domains, like music. This is an idea that we really like, and we believe that our research automation solutions can help these observatories to grow faster as ecosystems, create better quality and more timely data and research products and a far lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define ourselves as a reproducible research company inspired by the philosophy of open collaboration, based on open-source software and open data. We want to explore various revenue models around these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not committed to open source licensing if more permissive licensing policies provide us with better opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to explore various data-as-service models, because we do not want to be locked into the position of cheap open data vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to deploy AI applications that really help earning money in these sectors with playlisting, recommendation engines, forecasting applications, or royalty valuations, because our open collaboration approach brings up enough data sooner to than its alternatives, because it manages inherent conflicts of interests, fragmentation, and decentralization better than hierarchical solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January CEEMID reached its peak: we introduced a 12-country &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproducible research project&lt;/a&gt; made with only freelancers in Brussels, presented as best use case of evidence-based policy design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February Daniel visited the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/yes-delft-co-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft Co-Lab&lt;/a&gt; to find out who would be the best co-founder to re-launch CEEMID as an enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April we started to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;release our data&lt;/a&gt; as open data for validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month ago we &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started-up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we launched the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few other &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/annex.html#other-observatories&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data observatories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.palato.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Palato&lt;/a&gt; in the Hague, where we took our selfie and had an absolutely amazing dinner after the pitch. Check them out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching Our Demo Music Observatory</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 08:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, on 15 September 2020, we officially launched our &lt;code&gt;minimal viable product&lt;/code&gt; as we promised to partners back in February. This was a particularly difficult period for everybody. We aspired to deliver by September in a very different environment, our hopes for commissioned work went up in flames with the pandemic, and our targeted users, musicians and music entrepreneurs, talent managers, music venues lost most of their income. The organizations helping them, granting authorities, export offices and collective management societies are overwhelmed with the problem. During these troublesome times, our team expanded, attracted great new talent, and kept working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first product is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, a collaborative, automated research-based &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/faq/observatories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;observatory&lt;/a&gt; for the music industry, one that is particularly hard hit by the COVID19 crisis. Not only great artists, composers, technicians, managers fell victim to the virus, but musicians lost about 50–90% of their income from live music. This translates to a 100% loss for the live music technicians and managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fQJHflWPS34&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

See our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;earlier blogpost&lt;/a&gt; on what you see on the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry was never a place for great job security. For putting up a show, you usually need a network of 10–200 artists, technicians and managers to work together as freelancers without all those social benefits that many people enjoy in other walks of life. We have been trying to figure out how to help this microenterprise and freelancer-network based industry with research for five years. Our aim is to make them competitive when they are talking with their buyers: Google, Apple, Spotify, who are really heavy-weight data and AI pros. Our better plan their tours, when they will be back on the road, to understand what sort of audiences and purchasing power waits for them in different European cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are launching at a time when the music industry is crying for help.Therefore, we have decided to make our demo observatory open and unfinished. Over the last 7 years, we have built up about 2000 music and creative sector indicators to be used for business KPIs, forecasting targets, grant evaluations, royalty valuations, concert demography target group analysis and other professional uses. We would like to open up, based on your needs, about 50 well-designed indicators, and pledge to keep it daily refreshed, corrected, documented, citaable, downloadable. Also, feel free to use our most valuable source code—use it for your own purposes, even modify it, as long as you keep it open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our smaller partners, we follow what musicians do these days on Bandcamp: name your price. We make a pledge to our small partners: if you need reliable data to plan your next grant calls, calculate royalties, compensations, predict hit candidates, give us the job—and name your price. Post-corona, you can take for a dollar the best music from Bandcamp. You can take our research products, for a limited period, for any amount you name, as long as  it is for a good cause and serves the industry, musicians, technicians or managers. In return, we ask for your feedback. Help us validate whether we are on the right track, tell us how we can cooperate after the pandemic, in better times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our larger and better funded partners? We ask you to pay the price we name, because we believe that it is a well-justified, fair and competitive price, set by pricing experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appreciate it if you take a look at our offering, or if you pass this blogpost on to your colleagues in the industry.  Our main target audience initially are music professional in broader Europe, but we are planning to cover all major global markets very soon, too. Feedback from the U.S., Australia, Canada, Colombia, Brazil &amp;amp; Argentina is particularly welcome as we have great plans over there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-we-are&#34;&gt;Who we are?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; our operations on 1 September 2020 on the basis of &lt;a href=&#34;http://documentation.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt;, a pan-European data observatory that created about 2000 music and creative industry indicators for its users. In the coming days, we are gradually opening up about 50 &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music industry&lt;/a&gt; and 50 broader creative industry indicators in a fully reproducible workflow, with daily re-freshed, re-processed, well-formatted and documented indicators for business and policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate this approach in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious university-backed incubator programs, in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/yes-programs/ai-blockchain-validation-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI/Blockchain Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re finalist on their selection, and all help before 23 September from our friends in the music industry is more than appreciated. If we get there, we can rely on probably the best pros in Europe to make our offering better tailored and financially sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-in-touch&#34;&gt;Get in touch!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the very simple and extremely secure &lt;strong&gt;keybase.io&lt;/strong&gt;, a kind of mix of Whatsapp, Skype, Google Drive, One Drive and zoom. You can get in touch on that platform with us in anytime &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/team/reprexcommunity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily contact on LinkedIn &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/k%C3%A1tya-nagy-a9447730/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kátya&lt;/a&gt; and of course, we have a usually working &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;email contact form&lt;/a&gt;, too. Our email is name.surname at our main domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-credits&#34;&gt;Video credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data acquisition and processing: Daniel Antal, CFA and Marta Kołczyńska, PhD (&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/economy.html#demand&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;survey data&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation automation: Sandor Budai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video art: Line Matson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/moonmoonmoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating An Automated Data Observatory</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are building data ecosystems, so called observatories, where scientific, business, policy and civic users can find factual information, data, evidence for their domain.  Our open source, open data, open collaboration approach allows to connect various open and proprietary data sources, and our reproducible research workflows allow us to automate data collection, processing, publication, documentation and presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our scripts are checking data sources, such as Eurostat&amp;rsquo;s Eurobase, Spotify&amp;rsquo;s API and other music industry sources every day for new information, and process any data corrections or new disclosure, interpolate, backcast or forecast missing values, make currency translations and unit conversions. This is shown illustrated with an &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-07-25-reproducible_ingestion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;earlier post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fQJHflWPS34&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For direct access to the file visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/video/making-of-dmo.mp4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the video we show automated the creation of an observatory website with well-formatted, statistical data dissemination, a technical document in PDF and an ebook can be automated.  In our view, our technology is particularly useful technology in business and scientific researech projects, where it is important that always the most timely and correct data is being analyzed, and remains automatically documented and cited. We are ready deploy public, collaborative, or private data observatories in short time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data processing costs can be as high as 80% for any in-house AI deployment project. We work mainly with organization that do not have in house data science team, and acquire their data anyway from outside the organization. In their case, this rate can be as high as 95%, meaning that getting and processing the data for deploying AI can be 20x more expensive than the AI solution itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI solutions require a large amount of standardized, well processed data to learn from.  We want to radically decrease the cost of data acquisition and processing for our users so that exploiting AI becomes in their reach. This is particularly important in one of our target industries, the music industries, where most of the global sales is algorithmic and AI-driven. Artists, bands, small labels, publishers, even small country national associations cannot remain competitive if they cannot participate in this technological revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; our operations on 1 September 2020 on the basis of &lt;a href=&#34;http://documentation.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt;, a pan-European data observatory that created about 2000 music and creative industry indicators for its users. In the coming days, we are gradually opening up about 50 &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music industry&lt;/a&gt; and 50 broader creative industry indicators in a fully reproducible workflow, with daily re-freshed, re-processed, well-formatted and documented indicators for business and policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate this approach in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious university-backed incubator programs, in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/yes-programs/ai-blockchain-validation-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI/Blockchain Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-credits&#34;&gt;Video credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data acquisition and processing: Daniel Antal, CFA and Marta Kołczyńska, PhD (&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/economy.html#demand&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;survey data&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation automation: Sandor Budai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video art: Line Matson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/moonmoonmoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting-up</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-08-24-start-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-08-24-start-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big day has come: the co-founders singed off the documents at the public notary and started the registration of a reproducible research start-up in Leiden.  We got a lot of support from our friends! Your encouragement gives us a lot of energy to accomplish our first milestones, and to get Reprex B.V. going!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex means &amp;lsquo;reproducible example&amp;rsquo; in data science.  When you are stuck with a problem, creating a reproducible example allows other computer scientists, statisticians, programmers or data users to solve it. In 80% of the cases, you usually find the solution while creating a generalized example.  In the 20% other cases, you can reach out for help easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming days, we are launching demo versions of our headline products, data observatories. &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; will be a fully automated online service that every day collects, processes, cleans, and publishes scientifically valid data about European music.  Very soon after we will launch two other observatories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative and cultural sector, NGOs, most research institutions, data journalism teams are usually very small, and they do not have internal IT or data science capacities.  We would like to provide them a transparent, high quality, and fully open source solution to acquire data, process it without errors, document it and make sense of it. We would like to embrace the idea of open collaboration among creative enterprises, scientific researchers, NGOs, data journalists and policymakers with our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work will comply with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/opa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Policy Analysis&lt;/a&gt; standards developed by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkeley Initiative for Transparency in the Social Sciences&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cega.berkeley.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Effective Global Action&lt;/a&gt; and the four principles of &lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/reproducible/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproducible research&lt;/a&gt;: reviewability, replicability, confirmability and auditability.  We believe that these standards apply in reproducible finance, empirical evidence presentation in courts, or advocating sound policies and producing high-quality journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;help&#34;&gt;Do you want to help our start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to enter into the Validation Lab of one of the best artificial intelligence incubators in early September. Talented team members, letters of intents and assignments from organizations will give a lot of credibility to our start &lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/team/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Meet our team »&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put as in contact with people who love to write code in R and interested in automating business and social science research and primary data collection such as surveying. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/#featured&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out what sort of code we create »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduce us to people who need data and information to make better informed decision and analysis in music, film, book publishing, photography services or socially responsible finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share contacts of data journalists who would like to develop stories from big survey programs like &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/commfrontoffice/publicopinion/index.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.afrobarometer.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Afrobarometer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latinobarometro.org/lat.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lationbarometro&lt;/a&gt;, or base their storytelling on data and its visualizations. &lt;a href=&#34;http://retroharmonize.satellitereport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;See our survey harmonization examples »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know such people?  Send over this post or connect us in an email or social media message!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks again for your good wishes and encouragements, and hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regionalized Cultural Access and Participation (Books And Libraries) And Science Attitudes Variables</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-22-regional-eurobarometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-22-regional-eurobarometer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My new R package, Eurobarometer, helps the creation of data panels and regionalized statistics from the Pan-European survey’s microdata. This allows the creation of many new statistical indicators for the CEEMID Music Observatory and for many market and policy research tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example dataset (Antal 2020) was created from the microdata of the
Eurobarometer 79.2 survey using the development version of the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/antaldaniel/eurobarometer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer R package&lt;/a&gt;.
The dataset can be downloaded from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3759811&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;. It will be used in a forthcoming academic publication about book piracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-access--participation-variables&#34;&gt;Cultural Access &amp;amp; Participation Variables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The read a book variable is a weighted sum of the responses that chose
from &lt;code&gt;QB1 How many times in the last twelve months have you read a book?&lt;/code&gt; any answer apart from “not in the last 12 months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Individuals Who Read A Book&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/book-1_huad9c8ca1ac123ea603b393913ed6c9b6_15231_0f46bf2e6d77690f30a9cfc8dceac69c.webp 400w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/book-1_huad9c8ca1ac123ea603b393913ed6c9b6_15231_69e16455ece7be7c15c980e56e8a70b9.webp 760w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/book-1_huad9c8ca1ac123ea603b393913ed6c9b6_15231_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/book-1_huad9c8ca1ac123ea603b393913ed6c9b6_15231_0f46bf2e6d77690f30a9cfc8dceac69c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;672&#34;
               height=&#34;480&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;library-access&#34;&gt;Library Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The library access variable is a weighted sum of the responses that
chose from &lt;code&gt;QB1 How many times in the last twelve months have you visited a public library?&lt;/code&gt; any answer apart from “not in the last 12 months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Individuals Who Visited A Library&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/library-1_hucf5e91ad06e8cd1b7173e66e87447c3f_15424_8ab92babe5248eece4a90c8f8109270e.webp 400w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/library-1_hucf5e91ad06e8cd1b7173e66e87447c3f_15424_a392b911ba33d344235977a317c7e6e3.webp 760w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/library-1_hucf5e91ad06e8cd1b7173e66e87447c3f_15424_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/library-1_hucf5e91ad06e8cd1b7173e66e87447c3f_15424_8ab92babe5248eece4a90c8f8109270e.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;672&#34;
               height=&#34;480&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;limited-library-access&#34;&gt;Limited Library Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limited library access is a weighted sum of the responses that chose from the question block
&lt;code&gt;QB2 And for each of the following activities, please tell me why you haven’t done it or haven’t done it more often in the last 12 months? ... Visited a public library&lt;/code&gt; the answer option &lt;code&gt;Limited or poor quality of this activity in the place where you live.&lt;/code&gt; In this case, the number of respondents is rather low and this is not a very reliable statistic on regional level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Individuals Who Have Poor Local  Library&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1_hu76348619a4c3edd6259cb2ccdab4bf25_14818_a96b675543fb179812b64b3e5aa71278.webp 400w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1_hu76348619a4c3edd6259cb2ccdab4bf25_14818_8682b8a04c46cd6ab4378e4b4eed02d9.webp 760w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1_hu76348619a4c3edd6259cb2ccdab4bf25_14818_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1_hu76348619a4c3edd6259cb2ccdab4bf25_14818_a96b675543fb179812b64b3e5aa71278.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;672&#34;
               height=&#34;480&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;science--technology-attitudes&#34;&gt;Science &amp;amp; Technology Attitudes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supports open access variable is a weighted sum of yes answer
options to the &lt;code&gt;QD 17 Do you think that the results of publicly funded research should be made available online free of charge?&lt;/code&gt;
question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Individuals Who Have Poor Local  Library&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/openaccess-1_hu78e9af4f523c50bd6bdf56dcf39999e7_15157_0b50d2a21c8de06eb7bb8003bbb81711.webp 400w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/openaccess-1_hu78e9af4f523c50bd6bdf56dcf39999e7_15157_93aff408dd8e9a767cdfc2bcb37f0d7f.webp 760w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/openaccess-1_hu78e9af4f523c50bd6bdf56dcf39999e7_15157_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/openaccess-1_hu78e9af4f523c50bd6bdf56dcf39999e7_15157_0b50d2a21c8de06eb7bb8003bbb81711.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;672&#34;
               height=&#34;480&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demography&#34;&gt;Demography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet access question is a weighted sum of responses to the
answer option for &lt;code&gt;D46 Which of the following do you have? - An Internet connection at home&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Individuals Who Have Internet Access At Home&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/internetaccess-1_hu60a121608a52e0f87fe1495f400b20f6_14759_54300931acaf75f2c5ae2037300d6532.webp 400w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/internetaccess-1_hu60a121608a52e0f87fe1495f400b20f6_14759_2a8b4bb69fe73c7d6db25bd2e4bd7b76.webp 760w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/internetaccess-1_hu60a121608a52e0f87fe1495f400b20f6_14759_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/internetaccess-1_hu60a121608a52e0f87fe1495f400b20f6_14759_54300931acaf75f2c5ae2037300d6532.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;672&#34;
               height=&#34;480&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet access question is a weighted sum of responses to the
answer option for &lt;code&gt;D15 What is your current occupation? - student&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Regional Student Population&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/students-1_hued54839c27f773f0ad6efda4b2dd8360_14587_448e9fb4998cf00c50bee7fc850bcf10.webp 400w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/students-1_hued54839c27f773f0ad6efda4b2dd8360_14587_ba82f15f068d640ea6c1ec466f69c198.webp 760w,
               /media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/students-1_hued54839c27f773f0ad6efda4b2dd8360_14587_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/students-1_hued54839c27f773f0ad6efda4b2dd8360_14587_448e9fb4998cf00c50bee7fc850bcf10.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;672&#34;
               height=&#34;480&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-source--data-processing&#34;&gt;Data Source &amp;amp; Data Processing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source of the data is the microdata file stored in GESIS for the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dbk.gesis.org/dbksearch/sdesc2.asp?db=e&amp;amp;no=5688&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurobarometer 79.2
survey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data file contains the microdata for the Eurobarometer 79.2 survey (TNS Opinion &amp;amp; Social 2013), which includes a Cultural Access and Participation Survey (see (Haan and Broek 2012; Bína, Vladimir et al.2012)) and a Science &amp;amp; Technology Attitude survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey samples are designed to represent the national population,
with the exceptions of Northern Ireland, the former East- and
West-Germany, and the Turkish community on Cyprus. These samples are
designed to be representative for these populations, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For weighting we used the w1 weights, which allow for
post-stratification based on gender, education level and community size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of the Republic of Cyprus, Estonia, Latvia, Luxembourg and
Malta regionalization is not necessary because the entire countries are equivalent to a single NUTS2 region in terms of size and homogeneity. In these countries the weighting produces representative statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, due to a problem with the original data file, no regional information is available for the Republic of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Germany, Great Britain and Italy, data can be summarized on the level of NUTS1 territories, and we are imputing these values into the constituent (smaller sub-)regions on NUTS2 levels. In the case of the remaining countries it can be summarized on NUTS2 levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the survey samples are designed to be nationally representative, the regional sub-samples are not necessarily representative, and often they are very small. For post stratification purposes, we created a “dirty weighting”, Using the national w1 post-stratification weights, but centered to an average value of 1 for each region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that this causes problems on more detailed answer options (on the level levels of the questionnaire’s question hierarchy.) Except for the science attitudes and the library quality questions, we used relatively simple questions that are less affected by the small,
potentially biased sample size&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A better option would be the creation of new, regional
post-stratification weights. We believe that this would be a very
interesting, but very big research task that would potentially need the cooperation of the survey’s producer, Kantar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: &lt;em&gt;This was originally posted on Daniel&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2020-04-22-regional-eurobarometer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://eurobarometer.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt; became a much more useful and ex post survey harmonization tool after Marta joined the development efforts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel, Antal. 2020. “Regionalized Cultural Access and Participation
(Books And Libraries) And Science Attitudes Variables 2013.” Zenodo.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3759811&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3759811&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bína, Vladimir, Chantepie, Philippe, Deboin, Valérie, Kommel, Kutt,
Kotynek, Josef, and Robin, Philippe. 2012. “ESSnet-CULTURE, European
Statistical System Network on Culture. Final Report.” Edited by Frank,
Guy.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haan, Jos de, and Andries van den Broek. 2012. “Nowadays Cultural
Participation - an Update of What to Look for and Where to Look for It.”
In &lt;em&gt;ESSnet-CULTURE, European Statistical System Network on Culture.
Final Report.&lt;/em&gt;, 397–417. Luxembourg.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TNS Opinion &amp;amp; Social. 2013. “Cultural Access and Participation. Special Eurobarometer 399 Report.” European Commission.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/public_opinion/archives/ebs/ebs_399_en.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/public_opinion/archives/ebs/ebs_399_en.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First CEEMID Regional Open Data Release</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internet use: participating in social networks (creating user profile, posting messages or other contributions to facebook, twitter, etc.) [percentage of individuals]&lt;/em&gt; shows the development of social media use in the past 10 years in very high detail.  Social media is one of the most important ways to communicate with fans and find audiences for gigs, performances and to share new releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Social media use 2011-2019&#34;
           src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/dataanimation/internet_use_social_networks.gif&#34;
           loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chosen dataset is highlighting several new priorities of CEEMID.  This indicator, which is based on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsso.eurostat.ec.europa.eu/nui/show.do?dataset=isoc_r_iuse_i&amp;amp;lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurostat statistical product&lt;/a&gt;, has a much higher data quality than the Eurostat release, it is easier to use, and goes beyond the detail of national statistics.  It contains data on 411 territories in Europe, including countries, provinces and smaller regions, even some metropolitan areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset is available on the European open research data repository, &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/record/3754574#.XpimX8gzbIU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;. It will be updated annually. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3754574&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/DOI/10.5281/zenodo.3754574.svg&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The processing information is available in the dataset.  First, we have used our open source software to correct the regional boundary changes during the decade (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-02-13-regional_eurostat/&#34;&gt;Programatic Approach To Work With European Regional Data Panels&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When data was missing in the end of the dataset, we used the last observation carry forward, when in the beginning, the next observation carry backwards data.  Gaps in the data were interpolated using linear interpolation. Whenever data was available on a larger (provincial level), we imputed it to the smaller regional units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data contains standard national / regional references according the European NUTS2013 standard for backwards compatibility. Further documentation will be available on our methodology on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;documentation.ceemid.eu&lt;/a&gt; wiki website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last, the data was put into a table that complies with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstatsoft.org/article/view/v059i10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidy data&lt;/a&gt; principles for easier processing on computers and immediate use in spreadsheet applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use this in your article? Further research? Collaboration? Let&amp;rsquo;s get in touch on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or via &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;danielantal.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;












&lt;div class=&#34;gallery-grid&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-regionalopendatarelease&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_238711_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;542&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-regionalopendatarelease&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_246037_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;542&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-regionalopendatarelease&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_250355_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;542&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-regionalopendatarelease&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_247818_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;542&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-regionalopendatarelease&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_247520_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;542&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-regionalopendatarelease&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/regionalopendatarelease/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_243997_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;542&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!---
[[gallery_item]]
album: &#34;gallery&#34;
image: &#34;ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34;
caption: &#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2011)&#34;

[[gallery_item]]
album: &#34;gallery&#34;
image: &#34;ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34;
caption: &#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2015)&#34;

[[gallery_item]]
album: &#34;gallery&#34;
image: &#34;ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34;
caption: &#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2019)&#34;

[[gallery_item]]
album: &#34;gallery&#34;
image: &#34;metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34;
caption: &#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2011)&#34;

[[gallery_item]]
album: &#34;gallery&#34;
image: &#34;metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34;
caption: &#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2015)&#34;


[[gallery_item]]
album: &#34;gallery&#34;
image: &#34;metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34;
caption: &#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2019)&#34;

---&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
