<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Czechia | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/czechia/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/czechia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Czechia</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dataandlyrics.com/media/icon_hu5bfde8608118b47b475864b70fd224b4_21674_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Czechia</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/czechia/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;I lived in the mountains for six years, and I loved it because it was a place where you needed to rely on yourself to survive.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-15-marie_de_la_montagne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-15-marie_de_la_montagne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- HERE I WOULD INCLUDE A BREIF INTRODUCTION ABOUT WHO MARIE IS AND WHY WE&#39;RE INTERVIEWING HER
Please go ahead and extend it

--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marie works in Prague, and helps musicians&amp;rsquo; careers, particularly in TV and feature film synchronization.  She is also a performing artists, whose music is connected to different parts of Europe. We interviewed her because of our shared interest in how music crosses borders.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, you&amp;rsquo;re currently living in Prague, after spending several years located in France, London, and Berlin. What was this journey like for you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got locked down in Prague actually. I intended to move to Berlin after leaving London, as my pianist lives there and has kids. It seemed like the best next destination, but it just didn’t work out. Lockdown came out of the blue and I decided to stay in Czech Republic. I eventually found an apartment in Prague and a job I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do all my life, so I think this is it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now work for a label and I am in charge of our sync &amp;amp; publishing department. My professional focus is still abroad for the most part which helps me work towards my ambitions, yet also come back to my roots. I feel like this is what I really needed for my creativity to strive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- HERE I WOULD INCLUDE A BREIF INTRODUCTION ABOUT WHO MARIE IS AND WHY WE&#39;RE INTERVIEWING HER--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where would you like to find an audience for your music?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a great question, one that is hard to answer in my case since I am local in several places. I would say that because my songs are in English and draw inspiration from Irish and British folk music - I started writing when I found Lisa Hannigan and her melody based songs - they will resonate with people in these territories more than they probably will in Czechia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider myself a storyteller. My music is a space to communicate emotions about experiences we might not always talk about. I love performing live and I can see myself doing this anywhere, but mostly in Europe. I feel very close to all the countries I’ve lived in, so France and even the UK. I always build a small fanbase where I live, and then uproot again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  This is the script to include a jpg or png file.  If it is large, it will be ready for zooming in. --&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-marie-on-stage&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/listen_local_interviews/Marie_de_la_Montagne_with_band.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Marie on stage&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Marie on stage
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to spend more time in Central and Eastern Europe too. I feel like I neglected these countries and quite unfairly so. This has been a challenge as touring is always an expense, and since I collaborate with a pianist who has two children, there are practical aspects that I have to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I am not performing much these days. I channeled all my passion for it into my work with other artists and have been a booker, a manager, a filmmaker, a producer, an event organiser, and just kept on learning about the industry whilst swimming in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen Local tries to connect local musicians with local music. Can we say that you are looking for audiences that can be reached from Berlin and Prague, so Western Czechia and the Southeastern part of Germany? Our app is designed to find out where you music mind find audience, and for music lovers, to find artists who are close enough  to visit on a small venue gig.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you could say this is the territory where I would like people to listen to my music. I released my songs which were recorded eight years after we wrote them. Spotify became more dominant in release strategy and I had very little understanding of how it worked, what to pay attention to and how much time goes into release planning. I just decided to put the songs up, and let them live their own life. Now that I know much more about digital, I want to be more intentional about the songs I put out and how I do it. I love visual expression, I love collaboration, and I feel that the spaces I choose to live in &amp;ndash; which I choose because they are beautiful &amp;ndash; play an important role in this. I want to tell the story of how everything lead to where I am now. I always figured it was important to highlight small artist locally and where they performed so that audiences could connect with them and follow them long after, so what you are doing is great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  This code is copy pasted from Spotify.  You can adjust the height to look better.  --&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/artist/7qkfyK1GehyVxF42lDhO5V&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;433&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Having moved around, what do you consider home, in a spiritual or physical sense?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France is really my sacred place. It is a place where I feel insanely inspired and at home. Even from miles away, it gives me a sense of confidence and freedom. I lived in the mountains for six years, and I loved it because it was a place where you needed to rely on yourself to survive. There is no industry there so anything I wanted to exist, I had to create everything myself. And that was amazing, because I proved to myself that I could do anything I decided to. When you are in a city, you always have to ask permissions. As a woman in this industry, no one listens to you. You have to work triple hard for people to let you say or do something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come back to the mountains for consolation, really. I even changed my French surname to mean “from the mountains,” as a way for people to stop focusing on where I am from and more on what I do. It worked, and I became Marie De La Montagne. I identified with that name so much, I had a hard time using my civil surname in my professional life when I became a publisher. Me and my colleague had a lot of laughs about it. It just seemed so strange to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other source of inspiration in music is in America. A lot of people might judge me for saying that, but America doesn’t do what I  mentioned above. I don’t feel so smothered when I work with my American colleagues. When I started to work with supervisors and people around the entertainment industry, I saw new potential, and my storytelling side resonated there. So I aligned myself at that, and wish to connect all these places creatively and also use the opportunities they offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you recommend some music from the region of France where you feel at home? Or some music from the US that inspired you much recently? We are interested in how musical inspiration comes to our artists, physically. We want to understand how music travels via word of mouth, algorithms, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can point you to a few artists that I met and find so inspiring. Definitely Amistat, a twin duo who have Czech roots, lived in Australia, and now live in Germany. We worked together for about two years, and I could listen to their song Love &amp;amp; Light on repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  This code is copy pasted from YouTube.  You can adjust the height to look better.  --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;395&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JcaOd1mSPYo&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also love &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0pylMlxf_0jE256FLv9ZMg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dirt Miller&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8dfUJJ-3op3B5wF5uono0w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lauren Ruth Ward&lt;/a&gt;, both of whom I met in Los Angeles, and I think that they are geniuses. Their songwriting, their social media artistry, and their vocals are mad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  Please add links similarly  --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many artists in Prague who have their own approach to songwriting and I am a huge fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqMfd-lCgyHkd2EYbjwaxDA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Aiko’s&lt;/a&gt;. I love Bookie Baker, especially when they play live. Karel Havlíček who just released a neoclassical album Spoken is someone who inspires me so much with his understanding of being an artist. Out of the artists I met whilst I was in France - check out Jake Morley, Nyna Loren, Fionnuala McKenna, Rob Longstaff, The Pedestrians&amp;hellip; so many great artists! Many of these artists came with us on tour which we filmed, so you can check out the videos we made online as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  This code is copy pasted from YouTube.  You can adjust the height to look better.  --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;395&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yATAUcdvLHY&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are currently not performing much, instead you are helping other artists.  What is your day job?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My day job now is building a sync &amp;amp; publishing company under a big independent label, which isn’t an easy task and exactly what I love about it. I need to have these big projects that build on the values I mentioned above. We offer all kinds of deals which evolve around artist development. My main focus is synchronization in TV and film, though mostly not in the Czech market. The industry here is not as standardized as it is abroad, and as you probably know through your research, this comes at a great disadvantage for the artists. I want to challenge that, as I feel like music is universal, and the industry is a tool not a master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In your work supporting artists, do you ever use data to help them find an audience?  What are your challenges?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yes! Data are my daily companion. But the challenges are everywhere, starting with artists not even knowing that they need data and what for. And clearing data is incredibly timeconsuming. I keep striving to find ways to understand the insides of the industry better using data so I can compensate for the disadvantages that the Czech market faces by default - language, historical disconnection from the markets around, the small size of the market, and so on. I also know a few people who are very passionate about this topic and new trends in music, in legal, in digital… There are so many ways you can look at this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We really would need more time to talk :)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-about-marie-de-la-montagne&#34;&gt;More about Marie de la Montagne&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find more of about Marie and her work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/mariedelamontagne/?hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt; or her &lt;a href=&#34;https://mariedelamontagne.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and make sure to check out her music!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other artists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Kestner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Duka Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katarzia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-18-where-they-understand-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twentees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Youniverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-04-04-wdekrey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Willemijn de Krey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a label:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tiny Rooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: Katarzia</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 15:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-katarzia-photography-by-ladislav-kyllar&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Katarzia. Photography by Ladislav Kyllar&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-11-25-katarzia/katarzia_avatar_hud68522c4bd457ff5afa5d5ebf9bd39ef_5502842_e23424738ddff70eaec2e3c531d4c84b.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-11-25-katarzia/katarzia_avatar_hud68522c4bd457ff5afa5d5ebf9bd39ef_5502842_6c33c8a80c9b9876902342a873af4ef1.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-11-25-katarzia/katarzia_avatar_hud68522c4bd457ff5afa5d5ebf9bd39ef_5502842_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/katarzia_avatar_hud68522c4bd457ff5afa5d5ebf9bd39ef_5502842_e23424738ddff70eaec2e3c531d4c84b.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;326&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Katarzia. Photography by Ladislav Kyllar
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katarzia, or &lt;em&gt;Katarína Kubošiová&lt;/em&gt;, is a Slovak singer, lyricist and producer. In 2020 she released her fourth album &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slnkorecords.sk/en/katarzia/celibat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Celibát&lt;/a&gt; with the main themes of loneliness and self-appreciation. Album was created in collaboration with the producer &lt;em&gt;Jonatán Pastirčák&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katarzia started her career as a folk singer. In the past years she moved on towards electronic music. She describes her current sound can as a mix of folk and electropop. The tour to promote her newest album &lt;em&gt;Celibát&lt;/em&gt; had been planned for spring 2020, unfortunately due to the Covid-19 pandemic had to be postponed indefinitely. As many other artists, Katarzia thinks that the current situation is not easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the moment, I am not working on any new projects. I am looking for a new job. Once the pandemic is over, I would like to stay where I am now, and return to the clubs to play for my audience. As I sing in Slovak, I know where my place is – I don&amp;rsquo;t want to perform abroad, of course, unless I turn to techno music. On a more personal level, I would like to live in New York – not as a musician, tough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katarzia is originally from Nitra, Slovakia and she has been living in Prague for a couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I live in Dejvice – there is a nice clubroom there, but I don&amp;rsquo;t visit that much. I enjoy going to National Theatre, Dejvice Theatre, Meetfactory, Archa Theatre and Rudolfinum. All the old classics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the restrictions during the pandemic, Katarzia managed to shoot a video for her song &lt;em&gt;Hoří i voda&lt;/em&gt; from &lt;em&gt;Celibát&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xVPDZEa0wjU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music video is a short film, directed by Jay Walker, an American who lives and works in Prague. &lt;a href=&#34;http://girlsinfilm.net/network&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Girls in film&lt;/a&gt; –- an organization that supports women in the film industry –- participated in the production of the video. The song is about women rights and equality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous albums:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generácia Y (2013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agnostika (2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antigona (2018).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/artist/5EssQRYnIgCOcvPauVySR1&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; is developing transparent algorithms and open source solutions to find new audiences for independent music. We want to correct the injustice and inherent bias of market leading big data algorithms. If you want&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;your music and audience&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;to be analysed in Listen Local, fill&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in. We will include you in our demo application for local music recommendations and our analysis to be revealed in December.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-artists&#34;&gt;Other artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Kestner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-18-where-they-understand-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twentees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-04-04-wdekrey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Willemijn de Krey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Youniverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-15-marie_de_la_montagne/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marie de la Montagne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a label:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tiny Rooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp; The Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativeflip.creativehubs.net/2019/12/03/flipping-the-odds/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference&lt;/a&gt; – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel&amp;rsquo;s presentation was focused around the question on invisibility of the CCI sector in the economic, education and labour policymaking, and the low level of data use in fact-based cultural policy design, and the following policy design problems. Our CEE Music Industry Report 2020 created with the help and support of Consolidated Independent was used as a use case for the problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post is an edited version of Daniel&amp;rsquo;s presentation and the subsequent panel discussion with the stakeholders and organizers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEE Report builds on the results of the first &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://czdev.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Czech&lt;/a&gt; music industry reports are compared with Armenian, Austrian, Bulgarian, Lithuanian, Serbian and Slovenian data and findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/publications/cee_report_2020_frontcover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Central &amp;amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;invisibility&#34;&gt;Invisibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measurement problems and the ‘invisibility’ of creative and cultural industries is a consequence of the fact that these industries are predominantly comprised of microenterprises and individual, freelancing entrepreneurs.  Even larger entities, such as collective management organizations can be classified as small enterprises.
In the EU, small- and medium enterprises, and especially microenterprises usually have reduced reporting duties to the statistical authorities and tax authorities (which is the most important secondary source of government statistics in anonymized, aggregated form.)  This means that the supply side is not visible for policymakers. The recommendation is to conduct sample-based surveys among these microenterprises, but very few member states do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem is that on the demand side, not all member states create statistics.  ESSNet-Culture created recommendations how to measure cultural access and participation, which is a broader term than cultural consumption, as it includes non-market forms, for example, liturgical music, amateur acting, and so on.  The European Commission sometimes makes excellent, but not detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/usecase/cap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CAP surveys&lt;/a&gt;, which are the most important sources of Eurostat’s relevant pan-European statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID has been making such surveys, both on the supply side (in music and film) and in the audience side (in music, film, theatre, opera, and artistic activities) in several member states, and has plenty of experience with using the EU-mandated CAP surveys of 2007 and 2013. The CEE report relies on the latter date set in first part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/audience.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;audience analysis&lt;/a&gt;. Our work was already presented in 2015 as a best use case in &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/creating_better_2015/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Creating better national cultural statistics with Eurobarometer datasets and ESSNet-Culture technical recommendations&lt;/a&gt; at GESIS, which maintains the Eurobarometer archives, on the Eurobarometer Symposium &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gesis.org/fileadmin/upload/events/EB-Symposium/Announcement_EB_Symposium.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Four Decades of Surveying Europe –
Perspectives on Academic Research with the European Commission’s Eurobarometer Surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the EU the lowest hanging fruit would be to critically assess the past surveys, including the partial CAP survey made in 2017 for the cultural heritage part of culture, and the national surveys conducted by CEEMID and its partners, and to mandate an annual or biannual CAP survey within the Eurobarometer series, probably as a specially sampled “Special Eurobarometer”.  This would very significantly reduce the costs compared to a country-to-country basis, and probably could be shared by other institutions, for example, with the European Audiovisual Observatory.  This alone would greatly increase the demand / consumption side information on the services of creative and cultural enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the panel discussion Consolidated Independent highlighted the problem of leaving sample-based statistics making to the industry itself, which leads to myopical incentives to create ‘policy-based evidence’ that is cherry picked by industry trade associations to fit their often not very well thought out policy agenda.  In our view, the most important role of a future European Music Observatory would be to set standards to data collection and integration.  The music industry is  one of the most data-rich industries globally, but the publicly available, verified, trustworthy information is scarce both for policy-making and for business planning among microenterprises who have know specialized research know-how. Our already existing, representative &lt;a href=&#34;http://survey2019.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;national surveys&lt;/a&gt; should and could be extended to the whole Europe with the quality control and visibility offered by such an Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;industry-organization&#34;&gt;Industry organization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very significant challenge with evidence-based policymaking, or, in fact, with any policy making is that the extremely fragmented nature of the industry makes national and EU-level consultations very difficult.  Most of the workforce is neither a classical employer nor employee but works as a freelancer or a micro-entrepreneur. Their views are very rarely represented by trade unions or employee associations or chambers of commerce. Despite all efforts on EU level to make the social dialogue more representative for atypical and flexible work forms, the problems and the views of the creative and cultural sectors are largely unrepresented in policy debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prime example of this problem is the very heavy over-taxation of the music industry that we have shown in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt; national music industry reports, and in other documents in Croatia.  The problem is not only characteristic for the music industry, but generally all CCIs because they share similar economic properties: no real chance to use tax breaks, high level of labour input and high level of value added.  While policy makers and granting authorities spend much time on trying to improve the financing of this sector, in fact, reducing over-taxation would make a much more imminent impact on the liquidity, profitability and growth opportunities of the sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in the making of economic and tax policies, the fragmented creative and cultural industries hardly can represent their special situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;policy-issues&#34;&gt;Policy issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from taxation issues, which significantly reduce the liquidity, profitability and growth opportunities of these sectors in many EU countries, particularly in the CEE, where corporate taxes are low but value-added taxes are high, there are other important policy problem that reduce the long-term growth capacity of the sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very small enterprise size leads to missing strategic human resources (HR) and research and development (R&amp;amp;D) functions in almost all enterprises – including simple market research activities.  Companies with 1-2 employees do not have specialized management and support functions, and thus they have a very strong handicap in HR and R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of this problem is the motion picture and TV industry.  These industries were comprised of medium-sized enterprises in the 1980s with significant in-house education functions. The current structure of these industries, however, resembles music, with almost all enterprises staying below the 5-person threshold.  In our experience, based on development needs assessments in the Hungarian motion picture and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://czdev.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Czech music industry&lt;/a&gt;, this creates an acute skills and labor shortage.  Missing skills cannot be well replaced by recruitment, or with strategic HR development via life-long learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to very reduced opportunities to participate in, and create life-long learning schemes, there are very little chances to engage in market research and R&amp;amp;D.  While the music industry, for example, is one of the most data-driven industries in the world, the microenterprise size does not allow that these enterprises commission market research or hire data scientists. This leads to very asymmetrical relationships with the main distributors of music and media content on platforms that are owned by global data companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations&#34;&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel made a few concrete recommendations in the panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating the European Music Observatory, and the creation of similar industry initiatives, and commissioning collaborative (multi-stakeholder) market research, as CEEMID works in many countries, can only replace the missing market research function in the extremely fragmented industries, such as motion picture production, the music industry, but to a certain degree architecture and design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A low-hanging fruit would be a critical assessment of the previous Pan-European CAP surveys and the comparable national CAP surveys conducted by CEEMID and its partners following the ESSNet Culture recommendations and the inclusion of the CAP surveys in an annual or bi-annual form in the Eurobarometer (Special) series. A Special Eurobarometer may be more suitable because usually a non-proportional weighting of the sample gives the best value for money in these surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critically reviewing the participation of micro-enterprises in the current forms of social dialogue and looking for formal or informal ways to increase participation in policy making can gradually lead to more creative-friendly economic regulation and tax policies.  The Hungarian Music Industry Report 2015 and the Slovak Music Industry Report 2019 contains very interesting case studies for this problem that we briefly summarize in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEE Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critically reviewing the few examples from mainly Nordic member states where collective agreements and other collaborative institutions allow microenterprises and freelancers to participate in life-long learning problems can help designing policies that will gradually reduce the huge skill gap of the CCIs in management know-how, data know-how, or renew their technical skills necessary in the production of their services and content. Our work with the Hungarian National Film Fund and surveys among more than a thousand film makers can give much insight into this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-links&#34;&gt;Further links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research findings were earlier presented and discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Vienna&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prague&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-11-18-bush/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Budapest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/slovak_report19/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bratislava&lt;/a&gt; with stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow Creative FLIP project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/creativeflip_eu?lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/ceereport_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/ceereport_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativeflip.creativehubs.net/2019/12/03/flipping-the-odds/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference&lt;/a&gt; – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEE Report builds on the results of the first &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://czdev.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Czech&lt;/a&gt; music industry reports are compared with Armenian, Austrian, Bulgarian, Lithuanian, Serbian and Slovenian data and findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research findings were earlier presented and discussed in Vienna, Prague, Budapest and Bratislava with stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the earlier presentations in the &lt;a href=&#34;#posts&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; section of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Central European Music Industry Report is the result of a co-operation that started among stakeholders in three EU countries five years ago to measure the economic value added of music – the basis of a modern royalty pricing system. This gave birth to CEEMID, originally the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Databases, a data integration programme that now in 2020, covers all of Europe. CEEMID fulfils similar roles to the planned European Music Observatory and supports all pillars of the future pan-European system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comparison of Western and Eastern music audiences reveals key demographic differences that make the unchanged adoption of business practices from mature markets in the region questionable. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/audience.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt; of this report will show these differences and their consequences on music markets, in terms of visiting and acquisition likelihood, frequency, seasonality and purchasing capacity. This is an example of how CEEMID fulfils the role of Pillar 3 (music, society and citizenship) in the planned European Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/supply.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt; contrasts market demand with the supply strategies of musicians. CEEMID has been surveying music professionals, including artists, technicians and managers about their working conditions, market conditions and plans for five years across a growing number of countries. In 2019 we invited 100 national and regional stakeholders to distribute our surveys. In some countries, our surveys already have several years of historic data, making the resulting musician database probably the largest ever source of data about how music is produced and how musicians live. We are constantly looking for partners to roll out this survey to new countries in new languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEE region has comparative advantages in big music events like festivals, and it has become one of the most important hubs for cultural tourism in the world. We explain this phenomenon in Chapter 4 by showing the differences in demand composition, demography and supply of venues in the second chapter. The lack of a modern and dense network of permanent music venues gave rise to magnificent music festivals in the CEE. Open’er, Sziget and Exit are among the biggest and best festivals in the world, closely followed by several smaller festivals in all countries. The share of festivals in the live music market is many times higher than in Western Europe and they provide vital export revenues to the local music economies. However, they play a limited role in finding new audiences for local artists, as they are increasingly programming for Western audiences by providing shows of international hits. They can only very partially fill in the gaps left by the small venue problem that hit the emerging markets harder than the UK or Australia, where policy action had been already taken to reverse the decline of the availability of smaller live music venues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the recording side, our analysis shows that modern digital services are growing at a faster rate than in mature markets. Because of lower repertoire competition, streaming quantities are similar for a typical Austrian, Czech, Hungarian, Polish or Slovak track than in the mature markets. However, revenue growth is limited because of the interplay of several analysed factors. Our analysis of the live and recorded music markets shows that CEEMID fulfils the roles of the Pillar 1 (music economy) of the planned European Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recorded music sales revenue in the region comes from streaming platforms, just like in the mature markets. Successful sales strategies require a solid knowledge of the global marketplace and the ability to understand and train sales algorithms. Micro-enterprises, such as independent labels, have very limited ability to cope with these functions, given that they do not have market research or R&amp;amp;D functions. CEEMID and Consolidated Independent have started initiating open, national R&amp;amp;D consortia to create the necessary concentration in data assets, analytical capacity and budgets to close this gap. As a first step, CEEMID and Consolidated Independent have created a large, independent music dataset based on hundreds of millions of royalty statement entries to create our market indexes, styled after stock market and bond market indexes. Streaming opportunities are fast changing as roll-out of streaming services is happening at a different rate in various territories; subscription charges and the exchange rate to the producer’s currency vary and repertoire competition emerges in the market. Our volume and revenue indexes in &lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/export.html#recexport&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 5.3&lt;/a&gt; are aimed at creating sales algorithms that optimize sales volumes and expected revenues. We believe that this analysis also reveals that CEEMID partially fulfils the roles of Pillar 2 (music diversity and circulation) and feeds important data into Pillar 4 (innovation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The region has far bigger untapped potential than most music business executives believe. Households in the region spend a significantly lower share of their recreational budget on music than their Western, Southern or Nordic peers. The region has a lot of untapped cultural purchasing power because servicing is particularly challenging in both the live and recorded sides of the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This upside potential cannot be tapped without better pricing. Royalty levels are often very low in the region. Due to many combined effects analysed in this short report, the gap between royalties earned in the CEE and Western Europe is several times bigger than the difference in GDP or national average wage. These gaps are partly caused by special interests preventing collective management from charging appropriate tariffs for restaurants, media companies or electronic appliance importers and manufacturers, and partly by unfavourable taxation of cultural products and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was designed to create economic evidence on royalty pricing, private copying compensation and the creation of economic value added in the industry. In the first Hungarian Music Industry Report of ProArt and in the first Slovak Music Industry Report we have shown that economic and taxation policies of the CEE countries aimed to support car and electronics manufacturing create a distorted, unfavourable economic regime for creative industries. We want to help local stakeholders with economic evidence to correct these discriminatory policies during the overhaul of the EU VAT system. We have been helping various national organizations with economic evidence, presented in the light of latest EU jurisprudence, to improve their pricing activities. Our thousands of indicators were also used in ex ante evaluations of granting schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, all EU member states will change their copyright administration legislation because of the national implementations of the 2019/790 Digital Single Market directive. CEEMID provides evidence in several countries about the size and impact mechanism of the value transfer, and generally the widespread use of the copyright exemption for private copying. We believe that the thousands of pan-European music industry indicators that we have aggregated over the five years will play a vital role in these regulatory processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID fulfils its roles with a very thorough exploitation of the EU’s 17-years-old Open Data regime with the re-use of public sector information, and a very careful mapping of the music industry. These maps help us conduct annual surveys among musicians and the audience, and they help us connect (always with pre-approval and with a user mandate) to industry databases. We do not only cover the EU countries, but increasingly (potential) candidate countries and neighbourhood countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our vision, this data collection and integration, i.e. Pillars 1-3 should be available for all music stakeholders, should remain public and publicly funded. The last Pillar of the observatory, innovation, is where private entities should compete. The founders of CEEMID and Consolidated Independent believe that this report demonstrates the business and policy benefits of such a system with the analysis of the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European music markets. We believe that this way CEEMID is in a position to serve most of the planned functions of the envisioned European Music Observatory, and we are looking for ways to make either our thousands of indicators, or our data collection and integration software open source and available for all stakeholders in the EU and its neighbours. CEEMID was born out of necessity to level out the different levels of public research and statistical coverage of the EU member states. In our view, private entities in the future should focus their investments in Pillar 4 of the planned observatory, i.e. competing in innovation with creating new models, algorithms and services based on data that is available throughout the European Union without giving further advantage to the already mature markets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Czech Music Development Program &amp; Comparative Market Research</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was presenting some highlights from the work we started with in the organization of SoundCzech with 25 music professionals representing more than 20 stakeholders in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/2019_10_09_praha/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; evaluation workshop in the context of the comparative &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the full presentation, including slides not shown in the workshop &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/presentation/nouvelle-prague&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The presentation is a self-contained big file of 20Mb, takes time to load.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work is done in a collaborative manner with the open Research Consortium started by SoundCzech, CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent.  We would like to invite any Czech stakeholders, or even individuals to join our efforts.  Because in the music sector, all organization are microenterprise or small enterprise sized, they usually have no significant market research, innovation and strategic HR management capacities. We hope to give them in each country useful tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very interesting part of the discussion in the morning was around transparency and potential conflict between stronger and weaker markets. Thank you for all colleagues who came on a Saturday morning after great showcase concerts the night before, and let&amp;rsquo;s stay in touch!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
