<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spotify | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>/tag/spotify/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/spotify/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Spotify</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 11:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Spotify</title>
      <link>/tag/spotify/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?</title>
      <link>/publication/music_level_playing_field_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/music_level_playing_field_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our article, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/music-streaming-is-it-a-level-playing-field/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?&lt;/a&gt; is published in the February 2021 issue of CPI Antitrust Chronicle, which is fully devoted to competition policy issues in the music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dramatic growth of music streaming over recent years is potentially very positive. Streaming provides consumers with low cost, easy access to a wide range of music, while it provides music creators with low cost, easy access to a potentially wide audience. But many creators are unhappy about the major streaming platforms. They consider that they act in an unfair way, create an unlevel playing field and threaten long-term creativity in the music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our paper describes and assesses the basis for one element of these concerns, competition between recordings on streaming platforms. We argue that fair competition is restricted by the nature of the remuneration arrangements between creators and the streaming platforms, the role of playlists, and the strong negotiating power of the major labels. It concludes that urgent consideration should be given to a user-centric payment system, as well as greater transparency of the factors underpinning playlist creation and of negotiated agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the entire issue and the full text of our article on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Competition Policy International&lt;/a&gt; in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2-Music-Streaming-Is-It-a-Level-Playing-Field-By-Daniel-Antal-Amelia-Fletcher-14-Peter-L.-Ormosi.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What If Your Stream Count Would Count For The Artists?</title>
      <link>/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 09:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contrary to what many believe, your music streaming history plays a relatively small role in the payouts of the artists whose songs you are listening to. The streaming platforms use a MCPS, or market-centred payout system, which is biased towards large market listeners. Contrary to UCPS, or user-centred payout systems, where all streams by all users are tallied up to determine the final distribution of subscription and advertisement revenues, MCPS uses weighted averaging that very heavily favours major music distributors and the biggest global stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We analyze these competition policy problems with Amelia Fletcher and Peter L. Ormosi in our forthcoming publication in a special issue of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Competition Policy International&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Music streaming: is it a level playing field?&lt;/em&gt;. But in the meantime, an interesting impact assessment emerged from France, because the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cnm.fr/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Centre National de la Musique&lt;/a&gt; commissioned Deloitte to make an impact assessment on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cnm.fr/le-cnm-evalue-limpact-dun-changement-eventuel-de-mode-de-remuneration-par-les-plateformes-de-streaming/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a possible change&lt;/a&gt;. Deezer provided a full overview of its 2019 payouts, while Spotify gave a sample of 100,000 artist payouts, and the other streaming services — for example, Apple Music — refused to cooperate with the French government-backed institution. You can read an English language summary and an excellent commentary from Emmanuel Legrand on his blog: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://legrandnetwork.blogspot.com/2021/02/user-centric-model-would-not-lead-to.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;User-centric model would not lead to significant changes in the distribution of music streaming royalties&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-which-genres-would-be-winners-and-losers-in-the-fair-payout&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/featured_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Which genres would be winners and losers in the fair payout?&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/featured_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;437&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Which genres would be winners and losers in the fair payout?
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fair distribution would completely alter the revenues of different genres. The biggest winner would be classical music, but various forms of pop, rock, jazz and disco artists would earn 15–25% more revenue. Currently, rap and hip-hop take about an extra 20% royalty revenue at the expense of these genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The streaming providers, which are directly or indirectly part-owned by major labels, are playing down the results, claiming that the difference would translate only to a few euros per artists at the bottom of the pyramid. In a sense, this is true, because streaming royalties are generally very low. But averaging is extremely misleading, because it includes millions of songs that are out-of-date or for another reason are never heard. In fact, entire scenes and labels would earn about 10% more revenue globally, considering that streaming revenues add up to half or even more of their total recording revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Is Not Recommended On Spotify?</title>
      <link>/post/2020-11-17-recommendation-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 11:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-11-17-recommendation-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are analysing how recommendations work for the artists involved in our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; experiment. We created a testing database with their music and other artists from their cities, regions and countries. We need new recommendation engines to dig out from a pile of international hits the local artists.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Avoid landing on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt;, in the universe of never listened-to-songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Understand how artists and their songs can find audience in the region relevant to their career goals, tour destinations, export opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our preliminary analysis is not representative for nationality, though we believe that we will find serious regional, linguistic and national patterns. We are using examples from Spotify. To be fair to Spotify, while their algorithm has many problems, their API is at least very open, as opposed to Apple Music where we do not really know what is going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our main concern is that some artists and their songs seem to be never recommended. Moreover, if artists and songs from a city, region or country are rarely or never recommended, then they risk losing their home market: the local audience will be recommended music that is coming outside of the city, region or country.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-artist-has-more-related-artists-as-number-popularity-and-number-of-followers-grows-nationality-may-affect-related-artists&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/streaming/spotify_related_artists_corrplot_no_title.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Artist has more related artists as number popularity and number of followers grows. Nationality may affect related artists.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/streaming/spotify_related_artists_corrplot_no_title.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Artist has more related artists as number popularity and number of followers grows. Nationality may affect related artists.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important way recommendations work is via &lt;code&gt;related artists&lt;/code&gt;. If an artist has &lt;em&gt;no related artists&lt;/em&gt;, it is very unlikely that either via user browsing interaction or via the algorithm that artists or her songs will be discovered by anybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want &lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;your music and audience&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to be analysed in Listen Local, fill out&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. We will include you in our demo application and our analysis to be revealed in December.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because big data algorithms learn from user behaviour, more popular, more often selected songs, and songs selected by more users are more likely to be recommended.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-algorithm-can-learn-more-about-popular-music-because-the-song-is-more-often-selected-by-a-larger-number-of-people&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/streaming/spotify_related_artists_popularity.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;The algorithm can learn more about popular music, because the song is more often selected by a larger number of people&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/streaming/spotify_related_artists_popularity.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The algorithm can learn more about popular music, because the song is more often selected by a larger number of people
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the algorithm finds more related music, it means that it &amp;ldquo;learned&amp;rdquo; the repertoire of the artist. Artists with very little popularity tend to be related to 20-30 artists, but at a popularity level of 40-60 they are related to 30-40 artists. Seems simple, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that much. If you want the algorithm to learn your music well, you really have to go &amp;ldquo;viral&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-artist-with-less-than-1000-followers-risk-not-being-to-recommended-at-all-doubling-your-chances-to-be-discovered-requires-1000x-more-followers&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/streaming/spotify_related_artists_followers.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Artist with less than 1000 followers risk not being to recommended at all. Doubling your chances to be discovered requires 1000x more followers.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/streaming/spotify_related_artists_followers.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Artist with less than 1000 followers risk not being to recommended at all. Doubling your chances to be discovered requires 1000x more followers.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doubling your routes to being recommended via other artists&#39; music requires exponential growth.  You need to have &lt;code&gt;1000x&lt;/code&gt; more followers to double the routes leading to your artist profile and recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have shown, the current recommendation engines are re-enforcing the existing status quo, and they can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;re-enforce the marginal status&lt;/a&gt; of subcultures, artists from a nation, city or region. In other words, as we often say, &lt;code&gt;big data creates injustice&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; for larger organizations and with our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; analytics and recommendations for artists, managers and labels, we want to fight exactly this injustice. We are creating &lt;code&gt;transparent&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;open source&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;responsible&lt;/code&gt; tools and algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Demo Music Observatory Dataset: Domestic Market Share On Spotify National Charts</title>
      <link>/post/2020-11-09-spotify-national-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 18:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-11-09-spotify-national-charts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The conversion to a subscription-based sales model with Spotify, Apple Music, YouTube Music, Deezer, Pandora and similar services was hailed by some to beat piracy and bringing back growth to the recording industry.  However, there are very few labels and artists who actually feel that they are profiting from this conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#recmarket&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; we have shown the paradox of streaming growth: while the streaming market appears to be growing, for the individual rightsholder, artists, or label, neither the volumes nor the revenues show much of a growth.  There are many factors contributing to the fact that for the ‘typical’ artist streaming does not bring revenue growth, and one of them is the increasing competition with the major label released music, particularly from the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/CEE_Report_files/figure-html/medianvalue-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;CEEMID-CI Revenue Index for Typical Recordings&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the user base of Spotify and similar services did not expand at the same rate as the available repertoire, so more and more songs were competing for not so many users, many of them ending up on the never played 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt; list. In other words, competition has been steadily growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Europe, almost everybody would like to get to the U.S. (getting harder and harder) or the UK (getting somewhat more accessible).  Some have a strong market background at home, others lost their home market without gaining foreign markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some smaller markets are somewhat protected from the competition often have low revenues because of the lower subscription fee and slower roll-out of the services. In the first years of the introduction of these services, like in Croatia or Russia this year, it is critically important to use this period to gain experience with holding or increasing local market shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The local music industry must find ways to train algorithms, promote local music contain that is relevant for the new audiences who use streaming platforms.  Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local Initiative&lt;/a&gt; aims build new data integrations that can help training data that reverses this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Music Observatory project is aiming to track all indicators that &lt;em&gt;jointly&lt;/em&gt; determine streaming success: subscription fees, exchange rates, subscription numbers, use hours, levels of competition, typical playing volumes, typical stream prices, and likelihood of crossing borders to export markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is to find a validated business model to bring to light the roughly 2000 indicators collected by our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/annex.html#ceemid-history&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID project&lt;/a&gt; for music pricing, AI, licensing, monitoring, grant evaluation, export market targeting and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/innovation.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;similar uses&lt;/a&gt;. We would like to transfer these data assets to a future  European Music Observatory. We are giving away in these weeks about 50 automatically maintained, well documented, high-quality indicators with history and timely new data publications for potential users and founding partners of the European Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We placed the following dataset in our observatory, to be refreshed weekly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/plots/spot_nat50_select.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Domestic market share on Spotify National Top 50, select countries&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download the entire dataset in different formats 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/music-diversity.html#domestic-market-share---spotify&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/music-diversity.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Diversity &amp;amp; Circulation&lt;/a&gt; pillar (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/index.html#pillars-of-the-demo-observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;all pillars&lt;/a&gt;) of our Demo Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We share the view that &lt;code&gt;big data creates injustice&lt;/code&gt;. Organizations that control large amounts of data, for example, the entire listening history of hundreds of millions of people in all major countries of the world, can train algorithms and robots that drive most of the music sales in the world. They can make your investment into a sound recording successful or doomed. They can circumvent or help a local content regulation, reinforce, or disable a national cultural policy goal. We want &lt;code&gt;big data to work for small venues, independent labels, startups, great and undiscovered artists&lt;/code&gt;. We believe that you cannot make a successful album launch, a market entry or introduce a successful cultural policy without large amounts of well processed and correctly analysed data. We want to create a Music Observatory that integrates the small data of many small bands, small labels, small venues, small countries, and mount correct the injustice. Make algorithms transparent and the competition fair.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Market Growth on European Markets</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-24_streaming-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019-09-24_streaming-market/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have never been a great fan of the headline figures reported by the recording industry about streaming growth.  I always felt that however dynamic are those charts, artists keep complaining that they do not feel these developments.  So I started to decompose those growth figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Global Music Report quotes national streaming revenues on a dollar basis, which contains a lot of currency exchange noise.  And behind the national total there are too many factors: subscriber base growth and repertoire growth and the subscription fee.  The interplay of these forces is unpredictable. Whenever a local artist or producers sees a 10% reported national growth, they can never be sure if this will likely cause their sale to grow or shrink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the changes in the subscriber base and the available competing repertoire, it is important to see if the artist’s segment is growing, and if the competition is growing. The sales platforms will never reveal such data, and anyway, there is a competition among many sales platforms.
I was looking for an analogy for a similar problem. Securities are a bit similar to songs, they will produce later cash flows, and they are competing for an always changing number of investors and with a constantly changing competition in the investible universe.  Songs and their royalty flows exhibit similarities with both equity and bonds, and I believe that a good solution is the creation of song indexes, similarly to stock and bond indexes that represent the performance of various security classes.
After many hours of work with the state51 data science team, and at least as much processing work for the servers, we came up with a dataset that contained data from about 700 million royalty statements. I designed a sampling method that is far from perfect, but I think it gives a first birds-eye view on the European markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dataanimation/animated_median_quantity_plot.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Growth of the &amp;lsquo;typical&amp;rsquo; songs streams on various markets&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every country and every month, we selected those exploited songs that were in the middle of the exploitation range: as many songs were less listened to as many were more listened too.  For simplicity, I call those selected songs the ‘typical songs’ for each streaming platform and royalty territory.  I added together the streaming quantities on the three major platforms. For every territory and month, this could have been the sales of a ‘typical’ song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like stock and bond indexes, we can create even more relevant indexes for certain rightsholders.  In the Central European Music Industry Report, we will present for each territory a ‘domestic’ and a ‘foreign’ index, because the sales potential of a Slovak song in Slovakia or in Austria is very different from a British song in Slovakia or Austria.  In Slovakia, a Slovak song is on a home territory and in Austria in a near territory, while the British song is on one of the almost 200 territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These findings will be open to discussion on&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/waves_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Waves Music Showcase Festival and Conference&lt;/a&gt; [click for details] &lt;em&gt;on 27 September 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If we take a look at the streaming charts of the region, we usually find that the vast majority of the streamed songs are foreign songs - except for Austria, U.S. songs.  For comparison, we added a similar, middle-income emerging market (Argentina) and a rich, small-population English-speaking country, Australia to the chart. These countries seem to be in a similar position to the CEE countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dataanimation/domestic_market_share_animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Market shares August-September 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably, the strongest countries of songwriting are the United States and Brazil - these are the countries that have ran out of the ISRC recording identifier range. Their charts are full with their domestic songs, but they are not alone.  Japan, France, and the bigger EU countries, France, Germany and Poland have very strong domestic performance, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are many factor at play here. Large countries with large artist populations generate a lot more recordings, so they local fans always have thousands of new songs to select from.  In small countries, the total annual creations, from pop to jazz, from authentic folk to classical amounts to a few thousand tracks. But it is not only size that matters.  Sweden&amp;rsquo;s population is similar to that of Austria, Hungary and Czechia, yet the Swedish repertoire performs better in Sweden, and as we will see in the next chart, abroad, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created a second data animation to visualize how hits were travelling across the borders in the summer of 2ö19. To make the chart easier to read, we omitted the United States, Brazil and Japan as countries of origin, and concentrated only on intra-European hit flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dataanimation/cross_border_plot-animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Cross-border hits August-September 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second week of September 2019 was not an exceptional week. Most EU countries&#39; producers did not score any hits in any other EU countries&#39; Spotify Top 50 hits.  The UK exported many great hits to all over Europe, as usual, but there were other important hit flows. These hits mainly follow cultural proximity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France exported hits to the two Francophone countries of Europe, Belgium and Romania, and furthermore to Greece, a Southern country with particularly unique chart composition. Germany exported many hits to Austria, another German-speaking country, and some hits to other Germanic countries. Dutch producers placed a few hits in the Germanic countries and in Belgium, where the Dutch-speaking Flemish community has its own radios, TVs, press and hitlists. The Netherlands is a powerhouse of electronic popmusic that are not bound by language which finds audience in several countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strength and competitive position of the national market where an artists is most known and has a fan base is usually a determining factor of track performance and revenue.  The overall revenue prospects and competition situation of a Hungarian or Croatian song is very different from a British or even a Polish song.  But overall, most European recordings are not bound to a domestic country. Because of cultural proximity, the presence of native minorities or new immigrant diasporas, even small-language songs are being listened to on a much wider territory than the artists&#39; original country. Some relatively small EU countries, such as Sweden and the Netherlands successfully export their music on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, as the streaming services slowly overtake all other forms of use, the charts above depict a very fundamental market change.  Whereas in the traditional channels of physical sales, digital downloads and broadcasting, the CEE countries, like other small- and medium-sized EU countries, enjoyed 30-50% market share, among the streaming hits their producer&amp;rsquo;s share is below 10%. It is not unusual to find only domestic recordings in physical sales hitlists, while domestic songs rarely enter the streaming charts in the region, with the exception of Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional sales channels protected CEE markets in several ways.  After EU accession most import duties are gone, but physical products have very significant logistics costs, which gives local producers a competitive edge.  Because physical products are increasingly sold on concerts and festivals, where the market share of domestic performers is usually very high, the traditional, mechanically licensed sales had a protected market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The broadcasting channel, which used the be the most important promotion channel, too, was protected in many European countries by national content quotas, or supported with generously funded national, regional, local public broadcasters who gave a preference to national composers, producers and performers. These market barriers are not present in the streaming markets, which poses many questions. Our research is aiming to answer these questions, but it took several years to build a data infrastructure that can help producing an accurate market overview.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/eu_cross_border_hits_20190915.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;European hits on an other European country&amp;amp;rsquo;s Spotify hitlist, 15 September 2019.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/eu_cross_border_hits_20190915_hu87f5dcff746518fbceefbd4abed84ec5_40449_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;266&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;National repertoire market shares on national Spotify hitlists, 15 September 2019.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915_hu781d82e369311575b56de92db7530f5f_19890_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;266&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These findings will be open to discussion on&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/waves_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Waves Music Showcase Festival and Conference&lt;/a&gt; [click for details] &lt;em&gt;on 27 September 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
