<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pricing | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/pricing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/pricing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>pricing</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>pricing</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/pricing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After much delay, the first measurement of licensed use of music, audiovisual content, home copying and value transfer to media platforms in Croatia for a practical update of the private copying remuneration in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the whole study in English, a Croatian language summary and a press release in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The models presented are simplified models of the Hungarian and Slovak models, with less detailed data. However, they show clearly that in less developed markets, compensation for unlicensed use remains a key issue. Only a very small fraction of households pay for music and film, and creators, performers, film writers are massively undercompensated in the Croatia, Bulgaria, Romania, Poland or the Baltic states of the EU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My study, Private Copying in Croatia, argues that the cultural and welfare benefits of this private copying regime are enormous and important to create a good quality of life in Croatia for all age groups, but especially for young people, and it must be maintained. Furthermore, it is very advantageous for the tech sector, because their products are mainly used with unlicensed music and film copies, given that only a very small portion of the population pays for downloads, or subscribes to services like Spotify, Deezer or Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even for those who are not interested in royalties, the first 3 chapters offer a very interesting introduction on how people listen to music, how musicians make music and how people copy it in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was a continuation of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2016-04-20_makk15/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;mapping of the Croatian music sector&lt;/a&gt;. I have created more detailed valuation and use studies of private copying and YouTube in Hungary (2015, 2017, 2018, 2019) and currently preparing similar studies in other countries, including Slovakia, as a continuation of the work started with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; and generally my home copying work started in 2012 with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/cisac_goodg_13/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I presented my market view and experience with distinguished colleagues from the Baltic states, Central Europe and the Balkan, representatives of WIN and IFPI and the international indie distributor State 51. We had a lively discussion on why emerging markets are emerging so slowly in the new digital music business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a decade of decline due to piracy and change in business model, the global music business is steadily growing.  However, defying some economic expectation, to growth is stronger in mature markets than in most emerging markets, and most of the global growth came from the United States. The dollar-based IFPI Global Music Report hides the fact that mature and emerging Europe is truly lagging behind the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European music scene is very fragmented, has many languages and the lack of critical market size often leads to neglect by innovative global players. In a world where most music is soled by big data driven algorithms in subscription streams, the lack of large repertoires, data analytics capabilities and critical audience masses puts the smaller European repertoires into a competitive disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/gallery/digital_gap.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Digital gap: share in household recreational spending and digital music revenues.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/gallery/digital_gap_hu791651d5ca2404d74016b85aa8de3dcd_59241_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;380&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/gallery/featured.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;The source of growth has been mainly the United States so far.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/gallery/featured_hu0603511b481da77ae47104f64292b1ac_44645_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a very interesting discussion that will lead to hopefully many new initiatives on a number of problems, including low market prices in collectively managed and private channels, distribution problems, the difficulties and opportunities in regional cooperation and a number of other topics. 
The presentation and the working paper is not public, but the similar workshops in the future may help growing a more mature network of CEE industry players and the adoption of new business models, pricing and promotion methods and more coordinated planning and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2013-11-18-cisac_good_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2013-11-18-cisac_good_governance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can review the slides below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/MPGDNcEefEU04I&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel/sgeur13-1037-dantal&#34; title=&#34;Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications in tariff setting&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications in tariff setting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dániel Antal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contents&lt;/strong&gt;:
2. Private copying: blank carriers, technology-driven challenges&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological changes coupled with arbitrage opportunities on the Single Market undermine revenue collection in some jurisdictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benchmarking breaks down if race starts to the bottom. You can adjust your tariffs to the neighbor without in-depth analysis as long your neighbor charges the right amount. ght) owners. Instead of simple benchmarking of fees, basic market variables such as quantities (number of tracks copied in homes), price variables, artist incomes should be compared in an economically meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimating quantities, methodology, survey design Consumer surplus estimate requires reliable quantity estimates that can be best collected on an international basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private copying: various challenges make economic assessment unavoidable. Value of intellectual property changes: technological and cultural changes modify the use of private copies. Economics deals with subjective value that is not indifferent of use. Compensation estimates must be updated when you blank carriers or copying technology enters the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CVM, choice modeling and hedonic pricing results Well designed economic estimates not only justify tariffs, but can create better value proposition for royalty payers. CVM surveys result in well-behaved demand curves for music in public places. Tariffs can be directly validated. Choice modeling reveals that consumers demand music and are rather insensitive to its price. Tariff levels are generally approved. Hedonic pricing reveals the different value added by different restaurants, bars, etc. – crucial for good value proposition and risk sharing with differentiated tariffs. Source: Various surveys designed by Visegrad Investments, conducted by Gfk Hungary, Universitas and Artisjus territorial representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Econometric analysis differentiates high- and low-willing-to-pay customers Improving existing tariff differentiation can lead to a win-win situation. The same amount of royalty can be collected with less pain and less risk of loosing royalty payers, or even increase the number of customers who can experience high-quality 9 Economic analysis helps to create better tariff differentiation that is more accepted by payers without changing the average level of royalties, leading to less loss to royalty-free or cheap repertoire alternatives. Willingness-to-pay survey based on new hypothetical offerings reveal that better differentiated tariffs can significantly improve value proposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public performance: changes in the restaurant, entertainment, retail outlet industry makes periodical tariff review necessary. The structure of restaurant, leisure and retailing changed significantly over two decades, creating chains of restaurants or retail outlets that have significant bargaining power and professional purchasing management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot more information on the slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;./usecase/&#34;&gt;Use cases&lt;/a&gt; of this website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
