<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>/tag/music/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>music</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 08:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>music</title>
      <link>/tag/music/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching Our Demo Music Observatory</title>
      <link>/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 08:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, on 15 September 2020, we officially launched our &lt;code&gt;minimal viable product&lt;/code&gt; as we promised to partners back in February. This was a particularly difficult period for everybody. We aspired to deliver by September in a very different environment, our hopes for commissioned work went up in flames with the pandemic, and our targeted users, musicians and music entrepreneurs, talent managers, music venues lost most of their income. The organizations helping them, granting authorities, export offices and collective management societies are overwhelmed with the problem. During these troublesome times, our team expanded, attracted great new talent, and kept working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first product is the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, a collaborative, automated research-based 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/faq/observatories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;observatory&lt;/a&gt; for the music industry, one that is particularly hard hit by the COVID19 crisis. Not only great artists, composers, technicians, managers fell victim to the virus, but musicians lost about 50–90% of their income from live music. This translates to a 100% loss for the live music technicians and managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fQJHflWPS34&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

See our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;earlier blogpost&lt;/a&gt; on what you see on the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry was never a place for great job security. For putting up a show, you usually need a network of 10–200 artists, technicians and managers to work together as freelancers without all those social benefits that many people enjoy in other walks of life. We have been trying to figure out how to help this microenterprise and freelancer-network based industry with research for five years. Our aim is to make them competitive when they are talking with their buyers: Google, Apple, Spotify, who are really heavy-weight data and AI pros. Our better plan their tours, when they will be back on the road, to understand what sort of audiences and purchasing power waits for them in different European cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are launching at a time when the music industry is crying for help.Therefore, we have decided to make our demo observatory open and unfinished. Over the last 7 years, we have built up about 2000 music and creative sector indicators to be used for business KPIs, forecasting targets, grant evaluations, royalty valuations, concert demography target group analysis and other professional uses. We would like to open up, based on your needs, about 50 well-designed indicators, and pledge to keep it daily refreshed, corrected, documented, citaable, downloadable. Also, feel free to use our most valuable source code—use it for your own purposes, even modify it, as long as you keep it open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our smaller partners, we follow what musicians do these days on Bandcamp: name your price. We make a pledge to our small partners: if you need reliable data to plan your next grant calls, calculate royalties, compensations, predict hit candidates, give us the job—and name your price. Post-corona, you can take for a dollar the best music from Bandcamp. You can take our research products, for a limited period, for any amount you name, as long as  it is for a good cause and serves the industry, musicians, technicians or managers. In return, we ask for your feedback. Help us validate whether we are on the right track, tell us how we can cooperate after the pandemic, in better times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our larger and better funded partners? We ask you to pay the price we name, because we believe that it is a well-justified, fair and competitive price, set by pricing experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appreciate it if you take a look at our offering, or if you pass this blogpost on to your colleagues in the industry.  Our main target audience initially are music professional in broader Europe, but we are planning to cover all major global markets very soon, too. Feedback from the U.S., Australia, Canada, Colombia, Brazil &amp;amp; Argentina is particularly welcome as we have great plans over there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-we-are&#34;&gt;Who we are?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; our operations on 1 September 2020 on the basis of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://documentation.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt;, a pan-European data observatory that created about 2000 music and creative industry indicators for its users. In the coming days, we are gradually opening up about 50 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music industry&lt;/a&gt; and 50 broader creative industry indicators in a fully reproducible workflow, with daily re-freshed, re-processed, well-formatted and documented indicators for business and policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate this approach in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious university-backed incubator programs, in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/yes-programs/ai-blockchain-validation-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI/Blockchain Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re finalist on their selection, and all help before 23 September from our friends in the music industry is more than appreciated. If we get there, we can rely on probably the best pros in Europe to make our offering better tailored and financially sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-in-touch&#34;&gt;Get in touch!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the very simple and extremely secure &lt;strong&gt;keybase.io&lt;/strong&gt;, a kind of mix of Whatsapp, Skype, Google Drive, One Drive and zoom. You can get in touch on that platform with us in anytime 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/team/reprexcommunity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily contact on LinkedIn 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/k%C3%A1tya-nagy-a9447730/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kátya&lt;/a&gt; and of course, we have a usually working 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;email contact form&lt;/a&gt;, too. Our email is name.surname at our main domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-credits&#34;&gt;Video credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data acquisition and processing: Daniel Antal, CFA and Marta Kołczyńska, PhD (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/economy.html#demand&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;survey data&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation automation: Sandor Budai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video art: Line Matson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/moonmoonmoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Music Professionals Survey Wave</title>
      <link>/post/2020-music-professional-survey-wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-music-professional-survey-wave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID is conducing its 8th survey programme this among musicians, music professionals, and music managers. This is the largest empirical research program in the world about how people work and earn their living in the music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are teaming up with some music organizations and research universities to form a Music Observatory, which will support all participant countries musicians with free data for royalty calculation, advocacy at government, tour scheduling and tour planning.  This year we particularly focus on effective COVID19 relief measures, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the results of last years&#39; results:

&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; - free download in PDF, epub, or browse the html version.

&lt;a href=&#34;post/2020-01-30-ceereport/&#34;&gt;CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp;amp; The Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are asking music organizations to send out our questionnaires to their members, and we ask musicians to forward our questionnaires to music technicians and managers, too. After the fieldwork is done, we are sending back statistically analysed data, reports to the participating countries, and assist local music organizations to make the best use of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;which-countries-are-covered-this-year&#34;&gt;Which countries are covered this year?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous year we covered emerging Europe Austria, Czechia, Croatia, Hungary, Lithuania, Serbia, Slovakia, Slovenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we are aiming to cover some of our regularly surveyed countries, and a number of new, mainly developed markets. The countries will be announced shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granting And Policy Evaluation For Musicians In Hungary</title>
      <link>/post/2015-11-12-cstp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2015-11-12-cstp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The data and intelligence of CEEMID was used in Hungary to create an ex ante evaluation of the new Cseh Tamás Program to support popular music development in Hungary.  Our mandate was to create concrete granting proposals that have a high chance of making a change in terms of the later royalty earning capabilities of artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first phase of the project, we made two workshops with the eight fields development method to understand the challenges and existing working practices that result in a low level of royalties paid out in Hungary. This methodology requires a groupwork of all stakeholders and professionals of the industry. In this case, we worked in groups of 30-40, covering various artists, stage, light, sound technicians, producers, managers and even band transporters.  One group predominantly was Budapest-based and one in Eastern Hungary, to have a different view on working and market conditions in the metropolitan city and in the countryside. While royalties are not applicable for live music, it was well understood by the granting authority and the music industry that royalties cannot grow without a healthy live music sector in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the workshop, the consultant with several aides facilitates a very structured conversation that starts with a desired state of the industry which is not described by slogans but by actual characterizations of a desired working environment.   Instead of envisioning that “everybody gets a grant”, we describe the ideal project planning and management cycle of a new tour or record to see how a granting can fit into this workflow and what type of grants add effective assistance to realize goals.  For each goal and change we envision how that effects the work of the performing artists, her manager, the technician crew, even the schedule of the tour bus driver.  We discuss if the change makes any material change in the way we can prepare for a new album release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the latter stages what sort of changes we envision in day practices, programmers, institutions and what concrete steps are needed to be made to get there.  As a controlling step, we assign indicators that can be objectively judged, and which can show the degree of change if recommended actions are taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage of the eight-fields methodology, which was originally developed to support EU and global aid program design is that it allows conflicting viewpoints, finding consensus, and display very highly detailed policy and program scenarios already in a day. It is generally a very enjoyable experience for artists and professionals.  If the workshop takes place over 2 days, a first draft program is already presented on the second morning and by the end of the day participants usually have a detailed program.  In this case, we came up with dozens of concrete proposals, many of which could be addressed to the stakeholders themselves without any action taken from the granting authority.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/01-featured.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Workshop in the Design Terminal, Budapest&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/01-featured_hu48dff82355c51cb9da72e1905faaf94d_108737_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/02-mindmap.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Creating the mindmap&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/02-mindmap_hu54f47b9031cb6332641cf1916acdc576_98341_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/03-mindmap.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Excerpt of mindmap&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/03-mindmap_hu83e8e21014b7b14b6bb8e4256a9d2c34_145989_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/04-professions.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Participating professions&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/04-professions_hud961f54fec5297723fa4ca07fa483799_954022_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next stage we carried out the annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey with additional questions where artists, managers and technicians could rate the proposals.  They could also optionally give their next year development priorities in the fields of live performances, recordings and composition, in the context of their current work, pre-existing financing and professional assistance of financial assistance needs.  In Hungary, more than 1000 music professionals filled out the survey in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the workshop and the survey, we could present a very comprehensive policy and granting program, with preliminary estimates on granting needs, ideal and minimum grant sizes, and grant contractual conditions to avoid grant calls that cannot be contracted out to winners due to unrealistic prerequisites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results, with suggested cultural policy indicators, program indicators and budgetary outlines were presented to the granting authority of the Cseh Tamás Program (currently named: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hangfoglalo.hu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hangfoglaló Popular Music Support Program&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
