<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United-Kingdom | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/united-kingdom/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/united-kingdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>United-Kingdom</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dataandlyrics.com/media/icon_hu5bfde8608118b47b475864b70fd224b4_21674_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>United-Kingdom</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/united-kingdom/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empirical Analysis of Music Streaming Revenues and Their Distribution</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/mce_empirical_streaming_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/mce_empirical_streaming_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Owing to the global nature of music earnings, the various currency translation and royalty payments applied, and because there is no global comprehensive database of rights-holders, works, and recordings, it is impossible to calculate average (mean) or typical (median) earnings with any accuracy. Even an estimate would require a very complex methodology. Understanding the earnings of an average rights-holder would require a careful disaggregation of volume, price, exchange rate, and distribution changes, and international data harmonisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimating average or typical income requires advanced empirical sampling or surveying methods. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; (previously CEEMID) has worked on developing such methods, with the support of the state51 music group. We commissioned a report from the Digital Music Observatory on the earnings of UK rights-holders and this can be found here at &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/record/5554089&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;the Digital Music Observatory&amp;rsquo;s Zenodo repository&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Among the Observatory’s findings are that use of streaming services is generally growing in terms of volume, but the price is diminishing, which leads to diminishing or flat earnings for a typical or average British rights-holder; that in the 2015-2019 period, falling prices were partly or fully compensated by favourable changes in the exchange rate of the British pound with major currencies used in the global music business (the US dollar, the euro and the Japanese yen), but since 2020 there may have been changes in the opposite direction; and that for various methodological reasons, without international data harmonisation, and survey harmonisation, it is impossible to take a fully representative, unbiased sample of music
creator earnings in the United Kingdom alone.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Music Creator&amp;rsquo;s Earnings in the Digital Era, p28.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exectuive-summary-of-our-research-document&#34;&gt;Exectuive Summary of Our Research Document&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research questions asked in this report are related to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/music-creators-earnings-in-the-digital-era&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creator Earnings&amp;rsquo; Project&lt;/a&gt; (MCE), exploring issues concerning equitable remuneration and earnings distributions. We were tasked with providing a longitudinal analysis of earnings development and relating our findings to equitable remuneration. The starting point of our work was centred around a very broadly defined problem: how much money music creators (rightsholders) earn from streaming, how these earnings are distributed, and how the earnings and their distribution have developed during the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highly globalized music industry generates two important international reports, as well as several national reports, but these are not suitable for the analysis of the typical or average rightsholder, nor for small labels and publishers who do not represent a large and internationally diversified portfolio of music works or recordings. Copyright and neighboring right revenues are collected in national jurisdictions. Because British artists are almost never constrained by their use of language, and the UK Music Industry is highly competitive in the global music markets, even relatively less known rightsholders earn revenues from dozens of national markets. The lack of market information on music sales volumes, prices for each jurisdiction, and the unaccounted for national, domestic, and foreign revenues makes the analysis of the rightholder’s earnings, or the economics of a certain distribution channel like music streaming or media platforms, impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While total earnings are reported by international and national organizations, they hide five important economic variables: changes in sales volumes, changes in prices, market share on various national jurisdictions (which have their own volume and price movements), the exchange rates applied, and the share of the repertoire exploited. Even worse, the global music industry has no comprehensive database of rightsholders, music works, and recordings. Many rights are represented by heirs or passive investors. And because of the enormous number of works and recordings, in any given royalty payment period, most works/recordings are not used and not compensated. The lack of a known population and distribution makes usual indicators as average or median earnings arithmetically impossible to compute, and the large number of disused works and recordings makes even the estimation of the typical (median) value useless for economic analysis. The estimation of the arithmetic mean is equally problematic, because it is distorted by the earnings of very few global stars. To understand the streaming economy from the perspective of a typical or average rightsholder, or from the perspective of a small independent label or music publisher, requires very challenging sampling techniques either in surveying or in empirically observing and aggregating data from royalty accounts. National and international music organizations are not equipped with the data processing and statistical capacity to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-effect-of-international-diversification-on-revenues---a-combination-of-international-price-differences-and-exchange-rate-fluctuations&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/reports/mce/Effect_International_Diversification_Revenues_Coplot.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Effect of International Diversification on Revenues - a combination of international price differences and exchange rate fluctuations.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The Effect of International Diversification on Revenues - a combination of international price differences and exchange rate fluctuations.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the problem that the Digital Music Observatory, a working demo of the European Music Observatory is solving. It grew out of the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Databases (CEEMID) initiative in 2014, in which righthsolders from three countries attempted to solve this problem. By 2019, CEEMID had collected information on 20 European markets, including the United Kingdom, and processed data on far more markets. The state51 music group, through its distribution arm, has been supporting the creation of the largest ever European market report, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Market Report&lt;/a&gt;, and supported the creation of the CEEMID-CI indexes, which, for the first time provided a stock-index type of view from an individual rightsholder’s perspective on volume and price movements in the UK and in other countries. The state51 music group drew attention to the observatory approach and this work in the Digital, Culture, Media and Sport Committee (DCMS) Select Committee of the British House of Commons. The MCE project first individually contacted the Digital Music Observatory (successor of CEEMID) and state51, and eventually with the permission of state51, the project commissioned this report, which re-uses the CEEMID-CI indexes. The MCE project also committed to share data in the Digital Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first chapter is divided into three subchapters: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/intro.html#theoretical-challenges&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;1.1&lt;/a&gt; the theoretical problems imposed by copyright law and intellectual property valuation methods; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/intro.html#policy-issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;1.2&lt;/a&gt; policy issues related to the copyright management problems that lead to large amounts of unpaid royalties and value transfer, as well as potential problems with AI distribution systems and royalty distribution rules; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/intro.html#empirical-challenges&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;1.3&lt;/a&gt; identifying and offering solutions for empirical problems in estimating the relevant earnings indicators for individual rightsholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second chapter presents the CEEMID-CI indexes, and gives an explanation to the seemingly paradoxical situation of total market growth, and the feeling of individual righthsolders that their earnings remain flat or decreasing. We show in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/empirical.html#streaming-value&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2.1&lt;/a&gt; that revenues that are flat or slightly growing are caused by growing volumes and falling prices (See &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/empirical.html#streaming-volume&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2.2 https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/empirical.html#streaming-volume&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/empirical.html#streaming-price&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2.3  CEEMID-CI Streaming Price Index&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third chapter, using computer simulations, gives a fuller picture. It shows that in the UK and many other markets, in the period of 2016-2019, the growth of streaming use hardly offset the diminishing price (value) of the streams. In many markets, rightsholders, expressed in British pounds, experienced flat earnings, which was by a large extent due to the benevolent USD/GBP, EUR/GBP, and CHF/GBP exchange rates. It is likely that the majority of individual rightsholders experienced flat or diminishing revenues, and later releases brought less and less revenue per a thousand streams. A less benevolent exchange rate environment could have brought very large losses of revenue (See &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/simulation-results.html#exchange-rate-effects&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;3.4&lt;/a&gt; for more details.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our computer simulations show that British rightsholders are experiencing a rather varied picture of music streaming. Because of the generally falling value of streams, short-lived hits are more impacted by value decline than perennial hits (See subchapters &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/simulation-results.html#difference-popularity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;3.1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/simulation-results.html#release-time&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;3.2&lt;/a&gt;.) Rightsholders with a diversified international audience are partly shielded by these effects (See &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/simulation-results.html#difference-international&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;3.3&lt;/a&gt;.) Younger stars and new genres generally experience a windfall from the pro-rata distribution system and older artists with more conventional genres such as rock or blues are experiencing headwinds. The publicly available market totals are hiding completely different market experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MCE project and its stakeholders did not provide us with any data. Our detailed data from other jurisdictions, however, shows that music streaming has been successfully competing with other sales/distribution formats of music partly because it was much cheaper, and generally devalued music-related rights. This is particularly the case with media platforms like YouTube. For the UK, which is not planning to adopt new EU regulations, closing the value gap is an important policy task. We also show on the example of other countries that current policy debate in the UK around the re-definition of equitable remuneration rigths, or on the pro-rata or user-centrique distribution schemes, are gaining excessive focus, and changes in these aspects of the streaming ecosystem will solve the problems of few, if any, rightsholders. We believe that the music industry must look beyond the current practices of streaming pricing and distribution, for example, to telecommunication services, and investigate the adoption of a more just system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our report highlights some important lessons. First, we show that in the era of global music sales platforms it is impossible to understand the economics of music streaming without international data harmonization and advanced surveying and sampling. Paradoxically, without careful adjustments for accruals, market shares in jurisdictions, and disaggregation of price and volume changes, the British industry cannot analyze its own economics because of its high level of integration to the global music economy. Furthermore, the replacement of former public performances, mechanical licensing, and private copying remunerations (which has been available for British rightsholders in their European markets for decades) with less valuable streaming licenses has left many rightsholders poorer. Making adjustments on the distribution system without modifying the definition of equitable remuneration rights or the pro-rata distribution scheme of streaming platforms opens up many conflicts while solving not enough fundamental problems.  Therefore, we suggest participation in international data harmonization and policy coordination to help regain the historical value of music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/listen_local_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Feasibility Study On Promoting Slovak Music In Slovakia &amp;amp; Abroad&lt;/a&gt;: Why are the total market shares of Slovak music relatively low both on the domestic and the foreign markets? How can we measure the market share of the Slovak music in the domestic and foreign markets? We offer some answers and solution based on empirical research and with the creation of a database and an AI application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/music_level_playing_field_2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?&lt;/a&gt;: Our paper argues that fair competition in music streaming is restricted by the nature of the remuneration arrangements between creators and the streaming platforms, the role of playlists, and the strong negotiating power of the major labels. It concludes that urgent consideration should be given to a user-centric payment system, as well as greater transparency of the factors underpinning playlist creation and of negotiated agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/european_visibilitiy_2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ensuring the Visibility and Accessibility of European Creative Content on the World Market: The Need for Copyright Data Improvement in the Light of New Technologies&lt;/a&gt;: While the US have already taken steps to provide an integrated data space for music as of 1 January 2021, the EU is facing major obstacles not only in the field of music but also in other creative industry sectors. Weighing costs and benefits, there can be little doubt that new data improvement initiatives and sufficient investment in a better copyright data infrastructure should play a central role in EU copyright policy. A trade-off between data harmonisation and interoperability on the one hand, and transparency and accountability of content recommender systems on the other, could pave the way for successful new initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt;: The results of the first Hungarian, Slovak, Croatian and Czech music industry reports are compared with Armenian, Austrian, Bulgarian, Lithuanian, Serbian and Slovenian data and findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;call-for-open-collaboration&#34;&gt;Call for Open Collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you need high-quality data for your music business or institution? Are you a music researcher? Join our open collaboration Digital Music Observatory team as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/curator&#34;&gt;data curator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/developer&#34;&gt;developer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/team&#34;&gt;business developer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-09-23-mce_reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-09-23-mce_reports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reprex was commissioned to prepare an analysis on the justified and not justified differences in music creators’ earnings.  We have posted our most important findings in an earlier blogpost (&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-18-mce/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era. United Kingdom Research Cooperation With the Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK Intellectual Property Office has published the entire report on the music creators’ earnings, and we have made our detailed analysis available in a side-publication. Reprex also signed an agreement with the researchers of the Music Creators’ Earnings project to deposit all data published in the report in the Digital Music Observatory, and to promote the building of the observatory further.
The research questions asked in this report are related to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/music-creators-earnings-in-the-digital-era&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creator Earnings&amp;rsquo; Project&lt;/a&gt; (MCE), exploring issues concerning equitable remuneration and earnings distributions. We were tasked with providing a longitudinal analysis of earnings development and relating our findings to equitable remuneration. The starting point of our work was centred around a very broadly defined problem: how much money music creators (rightsholders) earn from streaming, how these earnings are distributed, and how the earnings and their distribution have developed during the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highly globalized music industry generates two important international reports, as well as several national reports, but these are not suitable for the analysis of the typical or average rightsholder, nor for small labels and publishers who do not represent a large and internationally diversified portfolio of music works or recordings. Copyright and neighboring right revenues are collected in national jurisdictions. Because British artists are almost never constrained by their use of language, and the UK Music Industry is highly competitive in the global music markets, even relatively less known rightsholders earn revenues from dozens of national markets. The lack of market information on music sales volumes, prices for each jurisdiction, and the unaccounted for national, domestic, and foreign revenues makes the analysis of the rightholder’s earnings, or the economics of a certain distribution channel like music streaming or media platforms, impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While total earnings are reported by international and national organizations, they hide five important economic variables: changes in sales volumes, changes in prices, market share on various national jurisdictions (which have their own volume and price movements), the exchange rates applied, and the share of the repertoire exploited. Even worse, the global music industry has no comprehensive database of rightsholders, music works, and recordings – this is the data gap that we would like fill with the Digital Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://mce.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; highlights some important lessons. First, we show that in the era of global music sales platforms it is impossible to understand the economics of music streaming without international data harmonization and advanced surveying and sampling. Paradoxically, without careful adjustments for accruals, market shares in jurisdictions, and disaggregation of price and volume changes, the British industry cannot analyze its own economics because of its high level of integration to the global music economy. Furthermore, the replacement of former public performances, mechanical licensing, and private copying remunerations (which has been available for British rightsholders in their European markets for decades) with less valuable streaming licenses has left many rightsholders poorer. Making adjustments on the distribution system without modifying the definition of equitable remuneration rights or the pro-rata distribution scheme of streaming platforms opens up many conflicts while solving not enough fundamental problems.  Therefore, we suggest participation in international data harmonization and policy coordination to help regain the historical value of music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_20121/dcms_economics_music_streaming.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of our Digital Music Observatory was brought to the UK policy debate on music streaming by the &lt;em&gt;Written evidence submitted by The state51 Music Group&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;em&gt;Economics of music streaming review&lt;/em&gt; of the UK Parliaments&amp;rsquo; DCMS Committee&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry requires a permanent market monitoring facility to win fights in competition tribunals, because it is increasingly disputing revenues with the world’s biggest data owners. This was precisely the role of the former CEEMID&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; program, which was initiated by a group of collective management societies. Starting with three relatively data-poor countries, where data pooling allowed rightsholders to increase revenues, the CEEMID data collection program was extended in 2019 to 12 countries.The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;final regional report&lt;/a&gt;, after the release of the detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian reports&lt;/a&gt; of CEEMID was sponsored by Consolidated Independent (of the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was eventually to formed into the &lt;em&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/em&gt; in 2020&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, following the planned structure of the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-16-european-music-observatory-feasibility/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, and validated in the world&amp;rsquo;s 2nd ranked university-backed incubator, the Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Validation Lab. In 2021, under the final name &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, it became open for any rightsholder or stakeholder organization or music research institute, and it is being launched with the help of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JUMP European Music Market Accelerator Programme&lt;/a&gt; which is co-funded by the Creative Europe Programme of the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2020, we started investigating how the music observatory concept could be introduced in the UK, and how our data and analytical skills could be used in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://digit-research.org/research/related-projects/music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era&lt;/a&gt; (in short: MCE) project, which is taking place paralell to the heated political debates around the DCMS inquiry. After the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt; gave permission for the UK Intellectual Property Office to reuse the data that was originally published as the experimental &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#recmarket&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Volume and Revenue Indexes&lt;/a&gt;, we came to a cooperation agreement between the MCE Project and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;. We provided a detailed historical analysis and computer simulation for the MCE Project, and we will host all the data of the &lt;em&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings Report&lt;/em&gt; in our observatory, hopefully no later than early July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-contributes-to-the-music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era-project-with-understanding-the-level-of-justified-and-unjustified-differences-in-rightsholder-earnings-and-putting-them-into-a-broader-music-economy-context&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen.png&#34; alt=&#34;The [Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      The &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started our cooperation with the two  principal investigators of the project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/prof-david-hesmondhalgh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof David Hesmondhalgh&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/hyojung-sun/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Hyojugn Sun&lt;/a&gt; back in April and will start releasing the findings and the data in July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;join-us&#34;&gt;Join us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you need high-quality data for your music business or institution? Are you a music researcher? Join our open collaboration Digital Music Observatory team as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/curator&#34;&gt;data curator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/developer&#34;&gt;developer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/authors/team&#34;&gt;business developer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnote-references&#34;&gt;Footnote References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;state51 Music Group. 2020. “Written Evidence Submitted by The state51 Music Group. Economics of Music Streaming Review. Response to Call for Evidence.” UK Parliament website. &lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artisjus, HDS, SOZA, and Candole Partners. 2014. “Measuring and Reporting Regional Economic Value Added, National Income and Employment by the Music Industry in a Creative Industries Perspective. Memorandum of Understanding to Create a Regional Music Database to Support Professional National Reporting, Economic Valuation and a Regional Music Study.”&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel. 2021. “Launching Our Demo Music Observatory.” &lt;em&gt;Data &amp;amp; Lyrics&lt;/em&gt;. Reprex. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-18-mce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-18-mce/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_20121/dcms_economics_music_streaming.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; was brought to the UK policy debate on music streaming by the &lt;em&gt;Written evidence submitted by The state51 Music Group&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;em&gt;Economics of music streaming review&lt;/em&gt; of the UK Parliaments&amp;rsquo; DCMS Committee&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry requires a permanent market monitoring facility to win fights in competition tribunals, because it is increasingly disputing revenues with the world’s biggest data owners. This was precisely the role of the former CEEMID&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; program, which was initiated by a group of collective management societies. Starting with three relatively data-poor countries, where data pooling allowed rightsholders to increase revenues, the CEEMID data collection program was extended in 2019 to 12 countries.The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;final regional report&lt;/a&gt;, after the release of the detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian reports&lt;/a&gt; of CEEMID was sponsored by Consolidated Independent (of the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was eventually to formed into the &lt;em&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/em&gt; in 2020&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, following the planned structure of the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-16-european-music-observatory-feasibility/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, and validated in the world&amp;rsquo;s 2nd ranked university-backed incubator, the Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Validation Lab. In 2021, under the final name &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, it became open for any rightsholder or stakeholder organization or music research institute, and it is being launched with the help of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JUMP European Music Market Accelerator Programme&lt;/a&gt; which is co-funded by the Creative Europe Programme of the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2020, we started investigating how the music observatory concept could be introduced in the UK, and how our data and analytical skills could be used in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://digit-research.org/research/related-projects/music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era&lt;/a&gt; (in short: MCE) project, which is taking place paralell to the heated political debates around the DCMS inquiry. After the &lt;em&gt;state51 music group&lt;/em&gt; gave permission for the UK Intellectual Property Office to reuse the data that was originally published as the experimental &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#recmarket&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Volume and Revenue Indexes&lt;/a&gt;, we came to a cooperation agreement between the MCE Project and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;. We provided a detailed historical analysis and computer simulation for the MCE Project, and we will host all the data of the &lt;em&gt;Music Creators’ Earnings Report&lt;/em&gt; in our observatory, hopefully no later than early July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-contributes-to-the-music-creators-earnings-in-the-streaming-era-project-with-understanding-the-level-of-justified-and-unjustified-differences-in-rightsholder-earnings-and-putting-them-into-a-broader-music-economy-context&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen.png&#34; alt=&#34;The [Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      The &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; contributes to the Music Creators’ Earnings in the Streaming Era project with understanding the level of justified and unjustified differences in rightsholder earnings, and putting them into a broader music economy context.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started our cooperation with the two  principal investigators of the project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/prof-david-hesmondhalgh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof David Hesmondhalgh&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/hyojung-sun/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Hyojugn Sun&lt;/a&gt; back in April and will start releasing the findings and the data in July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;justified-and-unjustified-differences-in-earnings&#34;&gt;Justified and Unjustified Differences in Earnings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stating that the greatest difference among rightsholders’ earnings is related to the popularity of their works and recorded fixations can appear banal and trivial. Yet, because many payout problems appear in the hard-to-describe long tail, understanding the &lt;em&gt;justified&lt;/em&gt; differences of rightsholder earnings is an important step towards identifying the &lt;em&gt;unjustified&lt;/em&gt; differences. It would be a breach of copyright law if less popular, or never played artists, would receive significantly more payment at the expense of popular artists from streaming providers. The earnings must reflect the difference in use and the economic value in use among rightsholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our analysis we quantify differences using the actual data of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#ceemid-ci-volume-indexes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Indexes&lt;/a&gt;, created from hundreds of millions of data points, and computer simulations under realistic scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;justified-difference--changes-over-time&#34;&gt;Justified Difference &amp;amp; Changes Over Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the &lt;em&gt;justified&lt;/em&gt; differences we quantify four objective justifications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The variability of the domestic price of a stream over time&lt;/em&gt; shows a diminishing, but variable value of streams. Depending on the release date of a recording, and how quickly it builds up or loses the interest of the audience, the same number of streams can result in about 28% different earnings. In the period 2015-2019, later releases were facing diminishing revenues on streaming platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The variability of international market share&lt;/em&gt; and international streaming prices in &lt;em&gt;International Competitiveness&lt;/em&gt;. Compared to UK streaming prices, most international markets, particularly emerging markets, have a much greater variability of streaming prices. The variability of prices in advanced foreign markets such as Germany was similar to that of the British market, but in emerging markets and smaller advanced markets–such as the Netherlands–we measured a variability of around 50-80%. Artists who have a significant foreign presence, depending on their foreign market share, can experience 2-3 times greater differences in earnings than artists whose audience is predominantly British.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-in-our-simulated-results-the-depreciation-of-the-gbp-shielded-the-internationally-competitive-rightsholders-from-a-significant-part-of-the-otherwise-negative-price-change-in-streaming-markets&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/reports/mce/currency-environment-1.png&#34; alt=&#34; In our simulated results, the depreciation of the GBP shielded the internationally competitive rightsholders from a significant part of the otherwise negative price change in streaming markets.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      In our simulated results, the depreciation of the GBP shielded the internationally competitive rightsholders from a significant part of the otherwise negative price change in streaming markets.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The variability of the exchange rate&lt;/em&gt; that is applied when translating foreign currency revenues to the British pound in &lt;em&gt;Exchange Rate Effects&lt;/em&gt;. Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#ceemid-ci-volume-indexes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID-CI Streaming Indexes&lt;/a&gt; index covers the post-Brexit referendum period, when the British pound was generally depreciating against most currencies. This resulted in a GBP-denominated translation gain for artists with a foreign presence. We show that the variability of the GBP exchange rates can add &lt;em&gt;bigger justified differences&lt;/em&gt; among rightsholders’ earnings than the entire British price variation. The exchange rate movements are typically in the range of 30%, or at the level of the British domestic price variations in streaming prices. In our simulated results, this effect shielded the internationally competitive rightsholders from a significant part of the otherwise negative price change in foreign markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were also investigating the choice of &lt;em&gt;distribution model&lt;/em&gt;. , i.e., Both models, the currently used &lt;em&gt;pro-rata&lt;/em&gt; model and the &lt;em&gt;user-centric&lt;/em&gt; distribution, which has many proponents (and was introduced by SoundCloud in 2021), changes the earnings of artists. We think that both models represent a bad compromise, but they are legal, and a change of zero-sum distribution change could potentially increase the income of less popular and older artists at the expense of very popular and younger artists. More about this in our forthcoming report!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our understanding, there are some known and some hypothetical causes of &lt;em&gt;unjustified&lt;/em&gt; earning differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did not have systemic data on the &lt;em&gt;uncollected revenues&lt;/em&gt;–these are earnings that are legally made, but due to documentation, matching, processing, accounting, or other problems, the earnings are not paid. We could not even attempt to estimate this problem in the absence of relevant British empirical data. The problem is likely to be greater in the case of composers than in producer and performer revenues. In ideal cases, of course, the unclaimed royalty is near 0% of the earnings; it seems that on advanced markets the magnitude of this problem is in the single digits, and in emerging markets much greater, sometimes up to 50%. Royalty distribution is a costly business, and the smaller the revenue, the smaller the cost base to manage billions of transactions and related micropayments. We are working with a large group of eminent copyright researchers to understand this program better and provide regulatory solutions. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-05-16-recommendation-outcomes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recommendation Systems: What can Go Wrong with the Algorithm? - Effects on equitable remuneration, fair value, cultural and media policy goals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More analysis is required to understand how the algorithmic, highly autonomous recommendation systems of digital platforms such as Spotify, YouTube, Apple, and Deezer, among others, impact music rightsholders’ earnings. There are some empirical findings that suggest that such biases are present in various platforms, but due to the high complexity of recommendation systems, it is impossible to intuitively assign blame to pre-existing user biases, wrong training datasets, improper algorithm design, and other factors. We are working with our data curators, competition economist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/peter-ormosi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Peter Ormosi&lt;/a&gt;, antropologist and data scientist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/botond-vitos/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Botond Vitos&lt;/a&gt; and musicologist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-08-introducing-dominika-semanakova/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dominika Semaňáková - We Want Machine Learning Algorithms to Learn More About Slovak Music&lt;/a&gt; to understand what can go wrong here (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-08-teach-learning-machines/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Trustworthy AI: Check Where the Machine Learning Algorithm is Learning From&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is always a hypothetical possibility that organizations with monopolistic power try to corner the market or make the playing field uneven. The music industry requires a permanent market monitoring facility to win fights in competition tribunals, because it is increasingly disputing revenues with the world’s biggest data owners. We are working with our data curators, competition economist &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/peter-ormosi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Peter Ormosi&lt;/a&gt; and copyright lawyer &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-02-data-curator-eszter-kabai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dr Eszter Kabai - New Indicators for Royalty Pricing and Music Antitrust&lt;/a&gt; to find potential traces of an uneven playing field (see: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/music_level_playing_field_2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solidarity&#34;&gt;Solidarity &amp;amp; Equitable Remuneration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Equitable remuneration&lt;/em&gt; is a legal concept which has an economic aspect. In international law, it simply means that men and women should receive equal pay for equal work. Within the context of international copyright law, it was introduced by the Rome Convention, and it means that equitable remuneration means the same payment for the same use, regardless of genre, gender or other unrelated characteristics of the rightsholder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the word equitable in everyday usage often implies some level of equality and solidarity, in the context of royalty payments, these terms should not be mixed.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-uses-harmonized-anonimous-surveys-conducted-among-musicians-to-find-out-about-their-living-conditions-compared-to-their-peers-in-other-countries-and-people-in-other-professions&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/comparative/difficulty_bills_levels.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) uses harmonized, anonimous surveys conducted among musicians to find out about their living conditions compared to their peers in other countries, and people in other professions.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; uses harmonized, anonimous surveys conducted among musicians to find out about their living conditions compared to their peers in other countries, and people in other professions.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solidarity is present in many royalty payout schemes, but it is unrelated to the legal concept of equitable remuneration. Music earnings are very heavily skewed towards a small number of very successful composers, performers, and producers. The music streaming licensing model has little elements of solidarity, unlike some of the licensing models that it is replacing–particularly public performance licensing. However, in those cases, the solidarity element is decided by the rightsholders themselves, and not by external parties like radio broadcasters or streaming service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The so-called socio-cultural funds that provide assistance for artists in financial need must be managed by rightsholders, not others, and the current streaming model makes the organizations of such solidaristic action particularly difficult. Our data curator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/katie-long/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katie Long&lt;/a&gt; is working on us to find metrics and measurement possibilities on solidarity among rightsolders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-size-of-the-pie-and-the-distribution-of-the-pie&#34;&gt;The Size of the Pie and the Distribution of the Pie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current debate in the United Kingdom is often organized around the submission of the &lt;em&gt;#BrokenRecord&lt;/em&gt; campaign to the DCMS committee, which calls for a legal re-definition of equitable remuneration rights&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This idea is not unique to the United Kingdom, in various European jurisdictions, performers fought similar campaigns for legislation or went to court, sometimes successfully, for example, in Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hot redistribution topic is the choice between the so-called &lt;em&gt;pro-rata&lt;/em&gt; versus &lt;em&gt;user-centric&lt;/em&gt; distribution of streaming royalties. We think that both models represent a bad compromise, but they are legal, and a zero-sum distribution change could potentially increase the income of less popular and older artists at the expense of very popular and younger artists. We instead propose an alternative approach of &lt;em&gt;artist-centric distribution&lt;/em&gt; that could be potentially a win-win for all rightsholder groups; further elaboration of the concept lies outside the scope of this report.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-uses-monitors-volumes-prices-and-revenues-on-the-total-market-and-compares-them-to-calculated-fair-values-by-understand-the-entire-music-economy-we-can-highlight-when-music-is-devaluing-in-various-uses-or-countries&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/reports/mce/listen_hours_treemap_en.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) uses monitors volumes, prices and revenues on the total market, and compares them to calculated fair values. By understand the entire music economy, we can highlight when music is devaluing in various uses or countries.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; uses monitors volumes, prices and revenues on the total market, and compares them to calculated fair values. By understand the entire music economy, we can highlight when music is devaluing in various uses or countries.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is to help focus the policy debate with facts around the economics of music streaming. The legal concept &lt;em&gt;equitable remuneration&lt;/em&gt; is inseparable from the economic concept of &lt;em&gt;fair valuation&lt;/em&gt;, and music streaming earnings cannot be subject to a valid economic analysis without analyzing &lt;em&gt;the economics of music&lt;/em&gt;. Streaming services are competing with digital downloads, physical sales, and radio broadcasting; and the media streaming of YouTube and similar services is competing with music streaming, radio, and television broadcasting as well as retransmissions. It is a critically important to determine if in replacing earlier services and sales channels, the new streaming licensing model (a mix of the mechanical and public performance licensing) is also capable of replacing the revenues for all rightsholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current streaming licensing model in Europe is a mix of mechanical and public performance rights. Therefore, when we are talking about music streaming, we must compare the streaming sub-market with the digital downloads, physical sales and private copying markets (mechanical licensing), and with the radio, television, cable and satellite retransmission markets (public performance licensing.) Our experience outside the UK suggests that these replacement values are very low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;join-us&#34;&gt;Join us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join our open collaboration Music Data Observatory team as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/new-curators/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data curator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/new-developers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;developer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/observatory-business-associate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;business developer&lt;/a&gt;. More interested in antitrust, innovation policy or economic impact analysis? Try our &lt;a href=&#34;https://economy.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Economy Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; team! Or your interest lies more in climate change, mitigation or climate action? Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Green Deal Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; team!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnote-references&#34;&gt;Footnote References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;state51 Music Group. 2020. “Written Evidence Submitted by The state51 Music Group. Economics of Music Streaming Review. Response to Call for Evidence.” UK Parliament website. &lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15422/html/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artisjus, HDS, SOZA, and Candole Partners. 2014. “Measuring and Reporting Regional Economic Value Added, National Income and Employment by the Music Industry in a Creative Industries Perspective. Memorandum of Understanding to Create a Regional Music Database to Support Professional National Reporting, Economic Valuation and a Regional Music Study.”&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel. 2021. “Launching Our Demo Music Observatory.” &lt;em&gt;Data &amp;amp; Lyrics&lt;/em&gt;. Reprex. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gray, Tom. 2020. “#BrokenRecord Campaign Submission (Supplementary to Oral Evidence).” UK Parliament website. &lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15512/html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15512/html/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Welsh Music Industry In International Comparison</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 07:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next week we will introduce a music industry report from Wales. The country is a sub-national part of the United Kingdom from a statistical point view. Making evidence-based policy or market analysis is as challenging as in emerging markets where government statistical services are weak. And the parallels do not stop here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year we introduced a comparison of music audiences in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/audience.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;. Central European Music Industry Report. Using our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/publication/regions_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/publication/retorharmonize_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; software, we can re-run the code and compare part so the United Kingdom audience to various European audiences. Creating new, sub-national indicators allow a better market or policy analysis and comparison among small and larger countries. Going to sub-national levels is particularly important in live music, which is mainly a local business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While participation in concerts is similar to Western European nations in England (red) and Northern Ireland (grey), and in Scotland, maybe even to Northern Europe, in Wales we see very different participation rates.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-participation-in-music-concerts&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Participation in music: concerts&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_concerts_hu992e35f77e4832a96d2027b8b86ba362_286799_bfb7102dd6b7b79b6d1ffc7fe30e0dc8.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_concerts_hu992e35f77e4832a96d2027b8b86ba362_286799_1d713246da14c615122fb1adc84bad76.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_concerts_hu992e35f77e4832a96d2027b8b86ba362_286799_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_concerts_hu992e35f77e4832a96d2027b8b86ba362_286799_bfb7102dd6b7b79b6d1ffc7fe30e0dc8.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Participation in music: concerts
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Wales, concert attendance falls quickly from a promising start, which is similar to Central and Eastern Europe. While the granularity of our data is a bit too low for active participation like playing a music instrument or singing, we see striking differences for Wales, too.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-participation-in-music-playing-an-instrument&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Participation in music: playing an instrument&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_play_music_hu2e80ed59562796b9e4a189f8c557127d_286388_cf1626fca7f292fe684aa2d35d5166c0.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_play_music_hu2e80ed59562796b9e4a189f8c557127d_286388_4cb3a3fc809188696150e175965e7aa0.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_play_music_hu2e80ed59562796b9e4a189f8c557127d_286388_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_play_music_hu2e80ed59562796b9e4a189f8c557127d_286388_cf1626fca7f292fe684aa2d35d5166c0.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Participation in music: playing an instrument
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Wales is part of the UK British Industry, its role is similar to Slovak or the Croatian music industry in many sense.  It is part of a larger entity (Slovakia was part of Czechoslovakia, Croatia part of Yugoslavia, and now they are part of the borderless EU) but in an economically peripheral way. Wales offers less career opportunities for artists and audience, so the most valuable, highly-educated, high-earning audience (which can keep buying more and more expensive tickets) is missing, any many art talents leave to England or beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-participation-in-music-singing&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Participation in music: singing&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_sung_huc89aa99748f8439fc04b109d842c911d_246327_8ada76d8dd3515bea44902782bd5bfbf.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_sung_huc89aa99748f8439fc04b109d842c911d_246327_743cb035f5a5779cd3c65f7b1488c78a.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_sung_huc89aa99748f8439fc04b109d842c911d_246327_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_sung_huc89aa99748f8439fc04b109d842c911d_246327_8ada76d8dd3515bea44902782bd5bfbf.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Participation in music: singing
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leaves the &amp;ldquo;supply&amp;rdquo; of music drying, and the sustainability of the live music audience at peril.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July 2020, Professor Paul Carr of University of South Wales was commissioned by Senedd Cymru – the Welsh Parliament to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-06-welsh-covid-response/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;create a report&lt;/a&gt; examining the &lt;em&gt;state of play&lt;/em&gt; in the post Covid-19 music industries in Wales. &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/welsh_muisc_industries_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Welsh Music Industries in a Post-Covid World&lt;/a&gt;, featured on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; website, will be presented to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://senedd.wales/en/bus-home/committees/Pages/Committee-Profile.aspx?cid=445&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Culture, Welsh Language and Communications Committee&lt;/a&gt;. We hope that this is the beginning of an exciting cooperation when we can share knowledge between Western and Eastern Europe, and support new, evidence-based policies on a devolved, sub-national level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inquiry Into The Live Music Industry In Wales</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-06-welsh-covid-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-06-welsh-covid-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In July 2020, Professor Paul Carr of &lt;a href=&#34;http://staff.southwales.ac.uk/users/381-pcarr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;University of South Wales&lt;/a&gt; was commissioned by &lt;a href=&#34;https://senedd.wales/en/Pages/Home.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Senedd Cymru – the Welsh Parliament&lt;/a&gt; to create a report examining the ‘&lt;em&gt;state of play&lt;/em&gt;’ in the post Covid-19 music industries in Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;WATCH: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pcarr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@pcarr&lt;/a&gt; came to give evidence to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SeneddCWLC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@SeneddCWLC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; for our inquiry into Live Music Industry in Wales 🎵 &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/GtrYPOg8iW&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/GtrYPOg8iW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Senedd CWLC (@SeneddCWLC) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SeneddCWLC/status/1185216516201111555?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;October 18, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SeneddCWLC/status/1185216516201111555?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click through&lt;/a&gt; to see a short interview with Prof. Paul Carr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industries in Wales consist of both part-time and full-time stakeholders and  although dominated by live and recording sectors, also comprise of other sub-sectors, and like in other countries that we surveyed in Central and Eastern Europe, many stakeholders in the music industries are freelancers, following &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/supply.html#creators-of-music&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;multi-track careers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prof. Carr&amp;rsquo;s report is particularly interesting for our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; project because the Welsh nation is a part of a larger entity, the United Kingdom, and many important statistical products may need to be recreated for this sub-national level &amp;mdash; something we have been doing with &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;our survey retroharmonization&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://regions.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regional statistical tools&lt;/a&gt; for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Welsh Music Industries in a Post-Covid World&lt;/em&gt; will be presented to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://senedd.wales/en/bus-home/committees/Pages/Committee-Profile.aspx?cid=445&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Culture, Welsh Language and Communications Committee&lt;/a&gt; later this month, and we will publish the entire report in English and start a discussion around it, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
