<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Antal | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/author/daniel-antal/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/author/daniel-antal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Daniel Antal</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 07:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Daniel Antal</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/author/daniel-antal/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Welsh Music Industry In International Comparison</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 07:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next week we will introduce a music industry report from Wales. The country is a sub-national part of the United Kingdom from a statistical point view. Making evidence-based policy or market analysis is as challenging as in emerging markets where government statistical services are weak. And the parallels do not stop here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year we introduced a comparison of music audiences in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/audience.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;. Central European Music Industry Report. Using our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/publication/regions_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/publication/retorharmonize_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; software, we can re-run the code and compare part so the United Kingdom audience to various European audiences. Creating new, sub-national indicators allow a better market or policy analysis and comparison among small and larger countries. Going to sub-national levels is particularly important in live music, which is mainly a local business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While participation in concerts is similar to Western European nations in England (red) and Northern Ireland (grey), and in Scotland, maybe even to Northern Europe, in Wales we see very different participation rates.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-participation-in-music-concerts&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_concerts_hu992e35f77e4832a96d2027b8b86ba362_286799_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Participation in music: concerts&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_concerts_hu992e35f77e4832a96d2027b8b86ba362_286799_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;2204&#34; height=&#34;1240&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Participation in music: concerts
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Wales, concert attendance falls quickly from a promising start, which is similar to Central and Eastern Europe. While the granularity of our data is a bit too low for active participation like playing a music instrument or singing, we see striking differences for Wales, too.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-participation-in-music-playing-an-instrument&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_play_music_hu2e80ed59562796b9e4a189f8c557127d_286388_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Participation in music: playing an instrument&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_play_music_hu2e80ed59562796b9e4a189f8c557127d_286388_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;2204&#34; height=&#34;1240&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Participation in music: playing an instrument
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Wales is part of the UK British Industry, its role is similar to Slovak or the Croatian music industry in many sense.  It is part of a larger entity (Slovakia was part of Czechoslovakia, Croatia part of Yugoslavia, and now they are part of the borderless EU) but in an economically peripheral way. Wales offers less career opportunities for artists and audience, so the most valuable, highly-educated, high-earning audience (which can keep buying more and more expensive tickets) is missing, any many art talents leave to England or beyond.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-participation-in-music-singing&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_sung_huc89aa99748f8439fc04b109d842c911d_246327_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Participation in music: singing&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-13-wales-comparison/CAP_with_Wales_sung_huc89aa99748f8439fc04b109d842c911d_246327_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;2204&#34; height=&#34;1240&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Participation in music: singing
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves the &amp;ldquo;supply&amp;rdquo; of music drying, and the sustainability of the live music audience at peril.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July 2020, Professor Paul Carr of University of South Wales was commissioned by Senedd Cymru – the Welsh Parliament to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-06-welsh-covid-response/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;create a report&lt;/a&gt; examining the &lt;em&gt;state of play&lt;/em&gt; in the post Covid-19 music industries in Wales. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/welsh_muisc_industries_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Welsh Music Industries in a Post-Covid World&lt;/a&gt;, featured on our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; website, will be presented to the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://senedd.wales/en/bus-home/committees/Pages/Committee-Profile.aspx?cid=445&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Culture, Welsh Language and Communications Committee&lt;/a&gt;. We hope that this is the beginning of an exciting cooperation when we can share knowledge between Western and Eastern Europe, and support new, evidence-based policies on a devolved, sub-national level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching Our Demo Music Observatory</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 08:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, on 15 September 2020, we officially launched our &lt;code&gt;minimal viable product&lt;/code&gt; as we promised to partners back in February. This was a particularly difficult period for everybody. We aspired to deliver by September in a very different environment, our hopes for commissioned work went up in flames with the pandemic, and our targeted users, musicians and music entrepreneurs, talent managers, music venues lost most of their income. The organizations helping them, granting authorities, export offices and collective management societies are overwhelmed with the problem. During these troublesome times, our team expanded, attracted great new talent, and kept working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first product is the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, a collaborative, automated research-based 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/faq/observatories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;observatory&lt;/a&gt; for the music industry, one that is particularly hard hit by the COVID19 crisis. Not only great artists, composers, technicians, managers fell victim to the virus, but musicians lost about 50–90% of their income from live music. This translates to a 100% loss for the live music technicians and managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fQJHflWPS34&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

See our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;earlier blogpost&lt;/a&gt; on what you see on the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry was never a place for great job security. For putting up a show, you usually need a network of 10–200 artists, technicians and managers to work together as freelancers without all those social benefits that many people enjoy in other walks of life. We have been trying to figure out how to help this microenterprise and freelancer-network based industry with research for five years. Our aim is to make them competitive when they are talking with their buyers: Google, Apple, Spotify, who are really heavy-weight data and AI pros. Our better plan their tours, when they will be back on the road, to understand what sort of audiences and purchasing power waits for them in different European cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are launching at a time when the music industry is crying for help.Therefore, we have decided to make our demo observatory open and unfinished. Over the last 7 years, we have built up about 2000 music and creative sector indicators to be used for business KPIs, forecasting targets, grant evaluations, royalty valuations, concert demography target group analysis and other professional uses. We would like to open up, based on your needs, about 50 well-designed indicators, and pledge to keep it daily refreshed, corrected, documented, citaable, downloadable. Also, feel free to use our most valuable source code—use it for your own purposes, even modify it, as long as you keep it open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our smaller partners, we follow what musicians do these days on Bandcamp: name your price. We make a pledge to our small partners: if you need reliable data to plan your next grant calls, calculate royalties, compensations, predict hit candidates, give us the job—and name your price. Post-corona, you can take for a dollar the best music from Bandcamp. You can take our research products, for a limited period, for any amount you name, as long as  it is for a good cause and serves the industry, musicians, technicians or managers. In return, we ask for your feedback. Help us validate whether we are on the right track, tell us how we can cooperate after the pandemic, in better times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our larger and better funded partners? We ask you to pay the price we name, because we believe that it is a well-justified, fair and competitive price, set by pricing experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appreciate it if you take a look at our offering, or if you pass this blogpost on to your colleagues in the industry.  Our main target audience initially are music professional in broader Europe, but we are planning to cover all major global markets very soon, too. Feedback from the U.S., Australia, Canada, Colombia, Brazil &amp;amp; Argentina is particularly welcome as we have great plans over there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-we-are&#34;&gt;Who we are?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; our operations on 1 September 2020 on the basis of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://documentation.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt;, a pan-European data observatory that created about 2000 music and creative industry indicators for its users. In the coming days, we are gradually opening up about 50 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music industry&lt;/a&gt; and 50 broader creative industry indicators in a fully reproducible workflow, with daily re-freshed, re-processed, well-formatted and documented indicators for business and policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate this approach in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious university-backed incubator programs, in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/yes-programs/ai-blockchain-validation-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI/Blockchain Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re finalist on their selection, and all help before 23 September from our friends in the music industry is more than appreciated. If we get there, we can rely on probably the best pros in Europe to make our offering better tailored and financially sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-in-touch&#34;&gt;Get in touch!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the very simple and extremely secure &lt;strong&gt;keybase.io&lt;/strong&gt;, a kind of mix of Whatsapp, Skype, Google Drive, One Drive and zoom. You can get in touch on that platform with us in anytime 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/team/reprexcommunity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily contact on LinkedIn 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/k%C3%A1tya-nagy-a9447730/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kátya&lt;/a&gt; and of course, we have a usually working 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;email contact form&lt;/a&gt;, too. Our email is name.surname at our main domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-credits&#34;&gt;Video credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data acquisition and processing: Daniel Antal, CFA and Marta Kołczyńska, PhD (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/economy.html#demand&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;survey data&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation automation: Sandor Budai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video art: Line Matson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/moonmoonmoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating An Automated Data Observatory</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 16:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are building data ecosystems, so called observatories, where scientific, business, policy and civic users can find factual information, data, evidence for their domain.  Our open source, open data, open collaboration approach allows to connect various open and proprietary data sources, and our reproducible research workflows allow us to automate data collection, processing, publication, documentation and presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our scripts are checking data sources, such as Eurostat&amp;rsquo;s Eurobase, Spotify&amp;rsquo;s API and other music industry sources every day for new information, and process any data corrections or new disclosure, interpolate, backcast or forecast missing values, make currency translations and unit conversions. This is shown illustrated with an 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-07-25-reproducible_ingestion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;earlier post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fQJHflWPS34&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For direct access to the file visit 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/video/making-of-dmo.mp4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the video we show automated the creation of an observatory website with well-formatted, statistical data dissemination, a technical document in PDF and an ebook can be automated.  In our view, our technology is particularly useful technology in business and scientific researech projects, where it is important that always the most timely and correct data is being analyzed, and remains automatically documented and cited. We are ready deploy public, collaborative, or private data observatories in short time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data processing costs can be as high as 80% for any in-house AI deployment project. We work mainly with organization that do not have in house data science team, and acquire their data anyway from outside the organization. In their case, this rate can be as high as 95%, meaning that getting and processing the data for deploying AI can be 20x more expensive than the AI solution itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI solutions require a large amount of standardized, well processed data to learn from.  We want to radically decrease the cost of data acquisition and processing for our users so that exploiting AI becomes in their reach. This is particularly important in one of our target industries, the music industries, where most of the global sales is algorithmic and AI-driven. Artists, bands, small labels, publishers, even small country national associations cannot remain competitive if they cannot participate in this technological revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; our operations on 1 September 2020 on the basis of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://documentation.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt;, a pan-European data observatory that created about 2000 music and creative industry indicators for its users. In the coming days, we are gradually opening up about 50 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music industry&lt;/a&gt; and 50 broader creative industry indicators in a fully reproducible workflow, with daily re-freshed, re-processed, well-formatted and documented indicators for business and policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate this approach in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious university-backed incubator programs, in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/yes-programs/ai-blockchain-validation-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI/Blockchain Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-credits&#34;&gt;Video credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data acquisition and processing: Daniel Antal, CFA and Marta Kołczyńska, PhD (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/economy.html#demand&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;survey data&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation automation: Sandor Budai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video art: Line Matson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/moonmoonmoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/ceereport_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/ceereport_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The predecessor of Reprex&amp;rsquo;s Demo Music Observatory, CEEMID together with the independent music distributor Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativeflip.creativehubs.net/2019/12/03/flipping-the-odds/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference&lt;/a&gt; – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEE Report builds on the results of the first 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://czdev.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Czech&lt;/a&gt; music industry reports are compared with Armenian, Austrian, Bulgarian, Lithuanian, Serbian and Slovenian data and findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research findings were earlier presented and discussed in Vienna, Prague, Budapest and Bratislava with stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the earlier presentations in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; section of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Central European Music Industry Report is the result of a co-operation that started among stakeholders in three EU countries five years ago to measure the economic value added of music – the basis of a modern royalty pricing system. This gave birth to CEEMID, originally the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Databases, a data integration programme that now in 2020, covers all of Europe. CEEMID fulfils similar roles to the planned European Music Observatory and supports all pillars of the future pan-European system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comparison of Western and Eastern music audiences reveals key demographic differences that make the unchanged adoption of business practices from mature markets in the region questionable. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/audience.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt; of this report will show these differences and their consequences on music markets, in terms of visiting and acquisition likelihood, frequency, seasonality and purchasing capacity. This is an example of how CEEMID fulfils the role of Pillar 3 (music, society and citizenship) in the planned European Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/supply.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt; contrasts market demand with the supply strategies of musicians. CEEMID has been surveying music professionals, including artists, technicians and managers about their working conditions, market conditions and plans for five years across a growing number of countries. In 2019 we invited 100 national and regional stakeholders to distribute our surveys. In some countries, our surveys already have several years of historic data, making the resulting musician database probably the largest ever source of data about how music is produced and how musicians live. We are constantly looking for partners to roll out this survey to new countries in new languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEE region has comparative advantages in big music events like festivals, and it has become one of the most important hubs for cultural tourism in the world. We explain this phenomenon in Chapter 4 by showing the differences in demand composition, demography and supply of venues in the second chapter. The lack of a modern and dense network of permanent music venues gave rise to magnificent music festivals in the CEE. Open’er, Sziget and Exit are among the biggest and best festivals in the world, closely followed by several smaller festivals in all countries. The share of festivals in the live music market is many times higher than in Western Europe and they provide vital export revenues to the local music economies. However, they play a limited role in finding new audiences for local artists, as they are increasingly programming for Western audiences by providing shows of international hits. They can only very partially fill in the gaps left by the small venue problem that hit the emerging markets harder than the UK or Australia, where policy action had been already taken to reverse the decline of the availability of smaller live music venues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the recording side, our analysis shows that modern digital services are growing at a faster rate than in mature markets. Because of lower repertoire competition, streaming quantities are similar for a typical Austrian, Czech, Hungarian, Polish or Slovak track than in the mature markets. However, revenue growth is limited because of the interplay of several analysed factors. Our analysis of the live and recorded music markets shows that CEEMID fulfils the roles of the Pillar 1 (music economy) of the planned European Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recorded music sales revenue in the region comes from streaming platforms, just like in the mature markets. Successful sales strategies require a solid knowledge of the global marketplace and the ability to understand and train sales algorithms. Micro-enterprises, such as independent labels, have very limited ability to cope with these functions, given that they do not have market research or R&amp;amp;D functions. CEEMID and Consolidated Independent have started initiating open, national R&amp;amp;D consortia to create the necessary concentration in data assets, analytical capacity and budgets to close this gap. As a first step, CEEMID and Consolidated Independent have created a large, independent music dataset based on hundreds of millions of royalty statement entries to create our market indexes, styled after stock market and bond market indexes. Streaming opportunities are fast changing as roll-out of streaming services is happening at a different rate in various territories; subscription charges and the exchange rate to the producer’s currency vary and repertoire competition emerges in the market. Our volume and revenue indexes in 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/export.html#recexport&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 5.3&lt;/a&gt; are aimed at creating sales algorithms that optimize sales volumes and expected revenues. We believe that this analysis also reveals that CEEMID partially fulfils the roles of Pillar 2 (music diversity and circulation) and feeds important data into Pillar 4 (innovation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The region has far bigger untapped potential than most music business executives believe. Households in the region spend a significantly lower share of their recreational budget on music than their Western, Southern or Nordic peers. The region has a lot of untapped cultural purchasing power because servicing is particularly challenging in both the live and recorded sides of the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This upside potential cannot be tapped without better pricing. Royalty levels are often very low in the region. Due to many combined effects analysed in this short report, the gap between royalties earned in the CEE and Western Europe is several times bigger than the difference in GDP or national average wage. These gaps are partly caused by special interests preventing collective management from charging appropriate tariffs for restaurants, media companies or electronic appliance importers and manufacturers, and partly by unfavourable taxation of cultural products and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was designed to create economic evidence on royalty pricing, private copying compensation and the creation of economic value added in the industry. In the first Hungarian Music Industry Report of ProArt and in the first Slovak Music Industry Report we have shown that economic and taxation policies of the CEE countries aimed to support car and electronics manufacturing create a distorted, unfavourable economic regime for creative industries. We want to help local stakeholders with economic evidence to correct these discriminatory policies during the overhaul of the EU VAT system. We have been helping various national organizations with economic evidence, presented in the light of latest EU jurisprudence, to improve their pricing activities. Our thousands of indicators were also used in ex ante evaluations of granting schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, all EU member states will change their copyright administration legislation because of the national implementations of the 2019/790 Digital Single Market directive. CEEMID provides evidence in several countries about the size and impact mechanism of the value transfer, and generally the widespread use of the copyright exemption for private copying. We believe that the thousands of pan-European music industry indicators that we have aggregated over the five years will play a vital role in these regulatory processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID fulfils its roles with a very thorough exploitation of the EU’s 17-years-old Open Data regime with the re-use of public sector information, and a very careful mapping of the music industry. These maps help us conduct annual surveys among musicians and the audience, and they help us connect (always with pre-approval and with a user mandate) to industry databases. We do not only cover the EU countries, but increasingly (potential) candidate countries and neighbourhood countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our vision, this data collection and integration, i.e. Pillars 1-3 should be available for all music stakeholders, should remain public and publicly funded. The last Pillar of the observatory, innovation, is where private entities should compete. The founders of CEEMID and Consolidated Independent believe that this report demonstrates the business and policy benefits of such a system with the analysis of the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European music markets. We believe that this way CEEMID is in a position to serve most of the planned functions of the envisioned European Music Observatory, and we are looking for ways to make either our thousands of indicators, or our data collection and integration software open source and available for all stakeholders in the EU and its neighbours. CEEMID was born out of necessity to level out the different levels of public research and statistical coverage of the EU member states. In our view, private entities in the future should focus their investments in Pillar 4 of the planned observatory, i.e. competing in innovation with creating new models, algorithms and services based on data that is available throughout the European Union without giving further advantage to the already mature markets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After much delay, the first measurement of licensed use of music, audiovisual content, home copying and value transfer to media platforms in Croatia for a practical update of the private copying remuneration in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the whole study in English, a Croatian language summary and a press release in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The models presented are simplified models of the Hungarian and Slovak models, with less detailed data. However, they show clearly that in less developed markets, compensation for unlicensed use remains a key issue. Only a very small fraction of households pay for music and film, and creators, performers, film writers are massively undercompensated in the Croatia, Bulgaria, Romania, Poland or the Baltic states of the EU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My study, Private Copying in Croatia, argues that the cultural and welfare benefits of this private copying regime are enormous and important to create a good quality of life in Croatia for all age groups, but especially for young people, and it must be maintained. Furthermore, it is very advantageous for the tech sector, because their products are mainly used with unlicensed music and film copies, given that only a very small portion of the population pays for downloads, or subscribes to services like Spotify, Deezer or Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even for those who are not interested in royalties, the first 3 chapters offer a very interesting introduction on how people listen to music, how musicians make music and how people copy it in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was a continuation of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2016-04-20_makk15/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;mapping of the Croatian music sector&lt;/a&gt;. I have created more detailed valuation and use studies of private copying and YouTube in Hungary (2015, 2017, 2018, 2019) and currently preparing similar studies in other countries, including Slovakia, as a continuation of the work started with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; and generally my home copying work started in 2012 with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/cisac_goodg_13/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Market Growth on European Markets</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-24_streaming-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-24_streaming-market/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have never been a great fan of the headline figures reported by the recording industry about streaming growth.  I always felt that however dynamic are those charts, artists keep complaining that they do not feel these developments.  So I started to decompose those growth figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Global Music Report quotes national streaming revenues on a dollar basis, which contains a lot of currency exchange noise.  And behind the national total there are too many factors: subscriber base growth and repertoire growth and the subscription fee.  The interplay of these forces is unpredictable. Whenever a local artist or producers sees a 10% reported national growth, they can never be sure if this will likely cause their sale to grow or shrink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the changes in the subscriber base and the available competing repertoire, it is important to see if the artist’s segment is growing, and if the competition is growing. The sales platforms will never reveal such data, and anyway, there is a competition among many sales platforms.
I was looking for an analogy for a similar problem. Securities are a bit similar to songs, they will produce later cash flows, and they are competing for an always changing number of investors and with a constantly changing competition in the investible universe.  Songs and their royalty flows exhibit similarities with both equity and bonds, and I believe that a good solution is the creation of song indexes, similarly to stock and bond indexes that represent the performance of various security classes.
After many hours of work with the state51 data science team, and at least as much processing work for the servers, we came up with a dataset that contained data from about 700 million royalty statements. I designed a sampling method that is far from perfect, but I think it gives a first birds-eye view on the European markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/dataanimation/animated_median_quantity_plot.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Growth of the &amp;lsquo;typical&amp;rsquo; songs streams on various markets&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every country and every month, we selected those exploited songs that were in the middle of the exploitation range: as many songs were less listened to as many were more listened too.  For simplicity, I call those selected songs the ‘typical songs’ for each streaming platform and royalty territory.  I added together the streaming quantities on the three major platforms. For every territory and month, this could have been the sales of a ‘typical’ song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like stock and bond indexes, we can create even more relevant indexes for certain rightsholders.  In the Central European Music Industry Report, we will present for each territory a ‘domestic’ and a ‘foreign’ index, because the sales potential of a Slovak song in Slovakia or in Austria is very different from a British song in Slovakia or Austria.  In Slovakia, a Slovak song is on a home territory and in Austria in a near territory, while the British song is on one of the almost 200 territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These findings will be open to discussion on&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/waves_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Waves Music Showcase Festival and Conference&lt;/a&gt; [click for details] &lt;em&gt;on 27 September 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If we take a look at the streaming charts of the region, we usually find that the vast majority of the streamed songs are foreign songs - except for Austria, U.S. songs.  For comparison, we added a similar, middle-income emerging market (Argentina) and a rich, small-population English-speaking country, Australia to the chart. These countries seem to be in a similar position to the CEE countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/dataanimation/domestic_market_share_animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Market shares August-September 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably, the strongest countries of songwriting are the United States and Brazil - these are the countries that have ran out of the ISRC recording identifier range. Their charts are full with their domestic songs, but they are not alone.  Japan, France, and the bigger EU countries, France, Germany and Poland have very strong domestic performance, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are many factor at play here. Large countries with large artist populations generate a lot more recordings, so they local fans always have thousands of new songs to select from.  In small countries, the total annual creations, from pop to jazz, from authentic folk to classical amounts to a few thousand tracks. But it is not only size that matters.  Sweden&amp;rsquo;s population is similar to that of Austria, Hungary and Czechia, yet the Swedish repertoire performs better in Sweden, and as we will see in the next chart, abroad, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created a second data animation to visualize how hits were travelling across the borders in the summer of 2ö19. To make the chart easier to read, we omitted the United States, Brazil and Japan as countries of origin, and concentrated only on intra-European hit flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/dataanimation/cross_border_plot-animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Cross-border hits August-September 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second week of September 2019 was not an exceptional week. Most EU countries&#39; producers did not score any hits in any other EU countries&#39; Spotify Top 50 hits.  The UK exported many great hits to all over Europe, as usual, but there were other important hit flows. These hits mainly follow cultural proximity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France exported hits to the two Francophone countries of Europe, Belgium and Romania, and furthermore to Greece, a Southern country with particularly unique chart composition. Germany exported many hits to Austria, another German-speaking country, and some hits to other Germanic countries. Dutch producers placed a few hits in the Germanic countries and in Belgium, where the Dutch-speaking Flemish community has its own radios, TVs, press and hitlists. The Netherlands is a powerhouse of electronic popmusic that are not bound by language which finds audience in several countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strength and competitive position of the national market where an artists is most known and has a fan base is usually a determining factor of track performance and revenue.  The overall revenue prospects and competition situation of a Hungarian or Croatian song is very different from a British or even a Polish song.  But overall, most European recordings are not bound to a domestic country. Because of cultural proximity, the presence of native minorities or new immigrant diasporas, even small-language songs are being listened to on a much wider territory than the artists&#39; original country. Some relatively small EU countries, such as Sweden and the Netherlands successfully export their music on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, as the streaming services slowly overtake all other forms of use, the charts above depict a very fundamental market change.  Whereas in the traditional channels of physical sales, digital downloads and broadcasting, the CEE countries, like other small- and medium-sized EU countries, enjoyed 30-50% market share, among the streaming hits their producer&amp;rsquo;s share is below 10%. It is not unusual to find only domestic recordings in physical sales hitlists, while domestic songs rarely enter the streaming charts in the region, with the exception of Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional sales channels protected CEE markets in several ways.  After EU accession most import duties are gone, but physical products have very significant logistics costs, which gives local producers a competitive edge.  Because physical products are increasingly sold on concerts and festivals, where the market share of domestic performers is usually very high, the traditional, mechanically licensed sales had a protected market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The broadcasting channel, which used the be the most important promotion channel, too, was protected in many European countries by national content quotas, or supported with generously funded national, regional, local public broadcasters who gave a preference to national composers, producers and performers. These market barriers are not present in the streaming markets, which poses many questions. Our research is aiming to answer these questions, but it took several years to build a data infrastructure that can help producing an accurate market overview.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/eu_cross_border_hits_20190915.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;European hits on an other European country&amp;amp;rsquo;s Spotify hitlist, 15 September 2019.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/eu_cross_border_hits_20190915_hu87f5dcff746518fbceefbd4abed84ec5_40449_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;266&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;National repertoire market shares on national Spotify hitlists, 15 September 2019.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915_hu781d82e369311575b56de92db7530f5f_19890_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;266&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These findings will be open to discussion on&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/waves_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Waves Music Showcase Festival and Conference&lt;/a&gt; [click for details] &lt;em&gt;on 27 September 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musicians’ Living Standards And Life Satisfaction In The CEE Region</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-07-21_life_satisfaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-07-21_life_satisfaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to get a high-level comparison among the living standards of musicians, we use the standard survey question used in Eurobarometer surveys for decades: how often have had the respondent difficulties with paying bills in the past year?   This is a very good starting point because it makes comparable the rough material standards of musicians and other professional groups in the EU, irrespective of local earnings and living costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musicians everywhere, including rich countries like Germany, Austria and Slovenia have more problems with paying their bills than the general population in their countries.  The only seemingly different country is Bulgaria, but in this case, the self-reported difference is small, and generally Bulgarian musicians and other Bulgarian people have similarly frequent difficulties with paying their bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in an emerging economy is more stressful than in a mature economy – making ends is more difficult, risks are greater and usually rules change faster. No wonder that people generally report higher level of life satisfaction in countries where the living standards are also higher: average life satisfaction in a country is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/happiness-and-life-satisfaction&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;greatly influenced&lt;/a&gt; by national income and general health level, measured by life expectancy.  However, it is also recorded since the 1970s that after reaching a certain level of living standards, life satisfaction does not increase further with economic conditions. Other factors, such as vocation, work-life balance and political factors play a role, too. Working in an emerging economy is more stressful than in a mature economy – making ends is more difficult, risks are greater and usually rules change faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the emerging music business countries, it is very important to see that the musicians not only earn little money, but as freelancers their income is mainly based on live performances, peaking in the festival season and in December. This income is usually taxed at far higher rates in the CEE region than in Western Europe or in non-creative industries.  Royalties, which should balance variable live performance earnings are far lower both as a percentage of total musician income and in euro terms than in advanced markets. This is often coupled with higher taxation, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid the bias of higher satisfaction levels in richer environments, we measure musician’s self-reported life satisfaction levels against the national averages from the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dbk.gesis.org/dbksearch/sdesc2.asp?no=7489&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2018/11 Eurobarometer sample&lt;/a&gt;, scaled between the numerical values of -2 (not at all satisfied) to 2 (very satisfied).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-comparing-the-life-satisfaction-levels-of-musicians-with-the-general-public-2018-2019&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/musician_charts/life_satisfaction_levels.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Comparing the life satisfaction levels of musicians with the general public, 2018-2019.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/musician_charts/life_satisfaction_levels.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Comparing the life satisfaction levels of musicians with the general public, 2018-2019.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our comparison shows that in most of our surveyed countries, musicians are more satisfied with their lives than the average person, despite having more material difficulties.  Of course, age, and other factors can contribute to this, but a vocational calling is certainly an important aspect, too.  The exceptions are, interestingly, Austria and Slovenia, where the general population has a very high level of life satisfaction, and where both musicians and the general public are generally more satisfied with their lives than in the other countries. In these cases, compared to the general population, music professional are less satisfied with their lives. In Serbia our sample is too small to draw real conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-comparing-the-difficulties-of-paying-bills-among-musicians-and-the-general-public-2018-2019&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/musician_charts/difficulty_bills_levels.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Comparing the difficulties of paying bills among musicians and the general public, 2018-2019.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/musician_charts/difficulty_bills_levels.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Comparing the difficulties of paying bills among musicians and the general public, 2018-2019.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Career in music can lead to higher life satisfaction than other similarly paid jobs in Europe.  However, music market stakeholders should focus on increasing the level of music professional earnings and reducing its variance within the year and over the years, because the material living conditions of musicians is significantly worse than the conditions of the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can read a lot more about this research 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://survey2019.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurpoean Comparison: How Many People Ever Pay For Music, Film or Software</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-06-08_how_many_ever_pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-06-08_how_many_ever_pay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our recent private copying reports we compiled European survey data relevant to analysis.  In Europe, there is a big difference between the use of electronic entertainment devices in richer and poorer countries. Nevertheless, the real difference is between the number of people who sometimes and who never pay for downloaded music, films and software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some countries of Europe, less then 10 percent of the population ever pays for the content that is loaded to their computers, smartphones and tablets.  These survey data, accompanied by other objective data, can help explaining 96% of the variance among digital music sales levels within the EU countries, and it is highly relevant in calculating the economic benefit of home copying for users, and the harm for rightsholders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can review the slides here.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide1.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Slovak Music Industry Report&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide1_huaadc006dabad6f931881373b7458ff05_88558_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide2.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Music industry has a great potential to create jobs…&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide2_hu8fb30eb298294ef97d61dc144e7c2b4c_182313_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide3.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Mapping the Slovak Music Industry&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide3_hu5e60fd5e970b2c7bbcc362473ec09bc8_99011_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide4.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Mapping the Slovak Music industry&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide4_hu66be944f36e1d56a5b372a09ce09fd93_159996_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide5.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;The importance of the changing VAT regulation&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide5_huf441aca3285f3f8d19a741ecc5d66464_97903_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide6.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;The need of stronger copyright protection and higher royalty values&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide6_hudb27c489db7df2ca4a2fd0d2d125d94e_117307_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide7.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Critical size in the global market requires strong national players&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide7_hu8225d1627899f21a00b525433d99e2f9_78204_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide8.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Part of an animation, not animated here.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide8_hucff3831e7fc362d0de36638c3e4c5f36_89596_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide9.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Short-term growth with foreign revenues&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slide9_hu5c68701034a87e6f9ad825617271edc0_234931_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slidez10.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Get involved&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2018-04-18_sharpe_bratislava/gallery/Slidez10_hu32c80ac327c29a20d60060ed92a80c5b_49531_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel/spva-o-hudobnom-priemysle-na-slovensku-sharpe-2018&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slideshare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industy Report&lt;/a&gt; can be downloaded from 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soza.sk/aktuality/235/soza-zverej%C5%88uje-historicky-prvu-spravu-o-slovenskom-hudobnom-priemysle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I presented my market view and experience with distinguished colleagues from the Baltic states, Central Europe and the Balkan, representatives of WIN and IFPI and the international indie distributor State 51. We had a lively discussion on why emerging markets are emerging so slowly in the new digital music business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a decade of decline due to piracy and change in business model, the global music business is steadily growing.  However, defying some economic expectation, to growth is stronger in mature markets than in most emerging markets, and most of the global growth came from the United States. The dollar-based IFPI Global Music Report hides the fact that mature and emerging Europe is truly lagging behind the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European music scene is very fragmented, has many languages and the lack of critical market size often leads to neglect by innovative global players. In a world where most music is soled by big data driven algorithms in subscription streams, the lack of large repertoires, data analytics capabilities and critical audience masses puts the smaller European repertoires into a competitive disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/gallery/digital_gap.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Digital gap: share in household recreational spending and digital music revenues.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/gallery/digital_gap_hu791651d5ca2404d74016b85aa8de3dcd_59241_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;380&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/gallery/featured.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;The source of growth has been mainly the United States so far.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-11-01_cee_mini/gallery/featured_hu0603511b481da77ae47104f64292b1ac_44645_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a very interesting discussion that will lead to hopefully many new initiatives on a number of problems, including low market prices in collectively managed and private channels, distribution problems, the difficulties and opportunities in regional cooperation and a number of other topics. 
The presentation and the working paper is not public, but the similar workshops in the future may help growing a more mature network of CEE industry players and the adoption of new business models, pricing and promotion methods and more coordinated planning and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMP Session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion on Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-09-29_ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-09-29_ceempc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID had the honor to participate in the third panel of CEEMP in Warsaw together with Ben McEwen from ICE; Jules Parker from Spotify and Dominic Houston from Netflix, and Chris Butler from Music Sales, who is also the chairperson of ICMP. Our panel was moderated by Nigel Elderton from peermusic, who is also the new chairperson of PRS in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jules from Spotify spoke about their new initiative, Spotify for Publishers.  Spotify pays out about 20% of its royalties to publishers.  Because the labels are the bigger stakeholders, they often do not provide the necessary information for work identification in the case of publishers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominic from Netflix is already one of the biggest buyers of music, and I believe that his company’s footprint will just continue growing.  His time buys licenses only 10% of their music from publishers. They mainly use original film music, and to a significant degree, catalogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben made a presentation about their innovation efforts at ICE digital rights management. Working with some of the largest repertoires represented by PRS, GEMA and STIM, they really offer world class services. Next year they promise to scale services to smaller repertoires, who can immediately benefit from low-cost identification from the cleaned data of these large societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital gap between household cultural spending and CE / S European music industry revenues in the digital world
Comparing household cultural spending with digital music revenues in Europe’s main regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel’s short presentation highlighted the fact that the CEE region’s is much richer in terms of household cultural and recreational spending that it is thought by the music industry, because the music industry is really lagging its Western and Nordic peers in tapping into this pool of money.  There are many reasons for this, all a bit touched upon the other speaker’s issues, and their implementation difficulties n the CEE region, especially different revenue stream breakup, strong collective management and relatively underdeveloped publishing.  The region is about 200% or more below its benchmark in the sales we were talking about in this session.  The conversation will continue in Brussels, Prague, Budapest, Bratislava and Warsaw in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Musician Career Paths</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-02-03-music_career_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-02-03-music_career_path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the 20th century the first career step was to get on stage and create a credible live performance. After several years on the stage musician’s got a recording contract, and usually even later they registered their first composition. The recording stream was the most important revenue source. The making of a record was expensive and offered considerable royalties or advances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century the live music stream is far more important than the recordings. Creating recordings is much cheaper and stage performances are expensive. Musicians usually create their music, also register it as a music work and offer it to the public on an online portfolio of mp3 downloads, YouTube and music streams.  Often they are booked for their first live performance after publishing a recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean for the musician and the manager?  First and foremost that traditional career development strategies do not work anymore. A convincing stage performance is mandatory with a good touring strategy.  Recordings are often not profitable, but equally important in building the audience. Making the recording stream a revenue stream instead of the cost stream requires a very good understanding of the costs and benefits of the different digital channels. CEEMID also contains market information on these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Career information in CEEMID&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Milestones of the musician’s career&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Level of professionalization, secondary career paths&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Income level and basic live standards information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production and concert volumes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revenue breakup in all the three major income streams, i.e. publishing, recording and live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is available for Croatia, Hungary and Slovakia. Breakup by genre, gender, birth year, age cohort, capital  / countryside is also possible.  Similar surveys are being conducted in the film production industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Croatian Music Industry</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2016-04-20_makk15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2016-04-20_makk15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel Antal presented the preliminary findings of the Croatian music industry research in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makk.hr/web/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;International Authors’ and Creators’ Conference (Međunarodna autorska kreativna konferencija, #MAKK2015)&lt;/a&gt; in Zagreb on 24 November 2015. The presentation was largely based on analysis of various CEEMID databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Central European music industry, as shown by processing the data of more than 2000 musicians in the region is even more reliant on live performances than the British music industry.  Even though Croatia appears to be more similar to the UK than the region, a deeper analysis of the data reveals that this is not the case. The most important difference between mature markets and emerging markets is the lack of good distribution and monetization strategy for recorded music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collecting and analyzing industry data is very important for small, national music industries that do not have a large enough repertoire that can be easily promoted on global platforms such as Spotify, Deezer or YouTube.  New digital platforms produce relatively low income for Central and Southeastern European artists and labels, but they are growing at a rate similar to mature markets with a short, 1-5 years lag. Understanding the different strategies of global service providers, forthcoming liberalization and data-driven analytics are very important to maintain the share of domestic music in the radio and television channels and further expand it in the new channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More insights will be published on our blog and the forthcoming Regional music industry report. To be involved in the data collection and sharing of the Croatian national industry report please contact HDS-ZAMP, ZAPRAF, HGU or Unison in Croatian or CEEMID in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the presentation slides below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/peCdp6CFF02xZX&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel/preliminary-results-of-mapping-the-croatian-music-industry&#34; title=&#34;Preliminary results of mapping the Croatian music industry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Preliminary results of mapping the Croatian music industry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dániel Antal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granting And Policy Evaluation For Musicians In Hungary</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The data and intelligence of CEEMID was used in Hungary to create an ex ante evaluation of the new Cseh Tamás Program to support popular music development in Hungary.  Our mandate was to create concrete granting proposals that have a high chance of making a change in terms of the later royalty earning capabilities of artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first phase of the project, we made two workshops with the eight fields development method to understand the challenges and existing working practices that result in a low level of royalties paid out in Hungary. This methodology requires a groupwork of all stakeholders and professionals of the industry. In this case, we worked in groups of 30-40, covering various artists, stage, light, sound technicians, producers, managers and even band transporters.  One group predominantly was Budapest-based and one in Eastern Hungary, to have a different view on working and market conditions in the metropolitan city and in the countryside. While royalties are not applicable for live music, it was well understood by the granting authority and the music industry that royalties cannot grow without a healthy live music sector in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the workshop, the consultant with several aides facilitates a very structured conversation that starts with a desired state of the industry which is not described by slogans but by actual characterizations of a desired working environment.   Instead of envisioning that “everybody gets a grant”, we describe the ideal project planning and management cycle of a new tour or record to see how a granting can fit into this workflow and what type of grants add effective assistance to realize goals.  For each goal and change we envision how that effects the work of the performing artists, her manager, the technician crew, even the schedule of the tour bus driver.  We discuss if the change makes any material change in the way we can prepare for a new album release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the latter stages what sort of changes we envision in day practices, programmers, institutions and what concrete steps are needed to be made to get there.  As a controlling step, we assign indicators that can be objectively judged, and which can show the degree of change if recommended actions are taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage of the eight-fields methodology, which was originally developed to support EU and global aid program design is that it allows conflicting viewpoints, finding consensus, and display very highly detailed policy and program scenarios already in a day. It is generally a very enjoyable experience for artists and professionals.  If the workshop takes place over 2 days, a first draft program is already presented on the second morning and by the end of the day participants usually have a detailed program.  In this case, we came up with dozens of concrete proposals, many of which could be addressed to the stakeholders themselves without any action taken from the granting authority.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/01-featured.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Workshop in the Design Terminal, Budapest&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/01-featured_hu48dff82355c51cb9da72e1905faaf94d_108737_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.JPG&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/02-mindmap.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Creating the mindmap&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/02-mindmap_hu54f47b9031cb6332641cf1916acdc576_98341_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/03-mindmap.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Excerpt of mindmap&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/03-mindmap_hu83e8e21014b7b14b6bb8e4256a9d2c34_145989_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/04-professions.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Participating professions&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/gallery/04-professions_hud961f54fec5297723fa4ca07fa483799_954022_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next stage we carried out the annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey with additional questions where artists, managers and technicians could rate the proposals.  They could also optionally give their next year development priorities in the fields of live performances, recordings and composition, in the context of their current work, pre-existing financing and professional assistance of financial assistance needs.  In Hungary, more than 1000 music professionals filled out the survey in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the workshop and the survey, we could present a very comprehensive policy and granting program, with preliminary estimates on granting needs, ideal and minimum grant sizes, and grant contractual conditions to avoid grant calls that cannot be contracted out to winners due to unrealistic prerequisites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results, with suggested cultural policy indicators, program indicators and budgetary outlines were presented to the granting authority of the Cseh Tamás Program (currently named: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hangfoglalo.hu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hangfoglaló Popular Music Support Program&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hungarian Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/fQuYJEbQXoPgP3&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel/a-proart-zeneipari-jelentse&#34; title=&#34;A ProArt zeneipari jelentése&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A ProArt zeneipari jelentése&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dániel Antal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2013-11-18-cisac_good_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2013-11-18-cisac_good_governance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can review the slides below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/MPGDNcEefEU04I&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel/sgeur13-1037-dantal&#34; title=&#34;Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications in tariff setting&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications in tariff setting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dániel Antal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contents&lt;/strong&gt;:
2. Private copying: blank carriers, technology-driven challenges&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological changes coupled with arbitrage opportunities on the Single Market undermine revenue collection in some jurisdictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benchmarking breaks down if race starts to the bottom. You can adjust your tariffs to the neighbor without in-depth analysis as long your neighbor charges the right amount. ght) owners. Instead of simple benchmarking of fees, basic market variables such as quantities (number of tracks copied in homes), price variables, artist incomes should be compared in an economically meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimating quantities, methodology, survey design Consumer surplus estimate requires reliable quantity estimates that can be best collected on an international basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private copying: various challenges make economic assessment unavoidable. Value of intellectual property changes: technological and cultural changes modify the use of private copies. Economics deals with subjective value that is not indifferent of use. Compensation estimates must be updated when you blank carriers or copying technology enters the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CVM, choice modeling and hedonic pricing results Well designed economic estimates not only justify tariffs, but can create better value proposition for royalty payers. CVM surveys result in well-behaved demand curves for music in public places. Tariffs can be directly validated. Choice modeling reveals that consumers demand music and are rather insensitive to its price. Tariff levels are generally approved. Hedonic pricing reveals the different value added by different restaurants, bars, etc. – crucial for good value proposition and risk sharing with differentiated tariffs. Source: Various surveys designed by Visegrad Investments, conducted by Gfk Hungary, Universitas and Artisjus territorial representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Econometric analysis differentiates high- and low-willing-to-pay customers Improving existing tariff differentiation can lead to a win-win situation. The same amount of royalty can be collected with less pain and less risk of loosing royalty payers, or even increase the number of customers who can experience high-quality 9 Economic analysis helps to create better tariff differentiation that is more accepted by payers without changing the average level of royalties, leading to less loss to royalty-free or cheap repertoire alternatives. Willingness-to-pay survey based on new hypothetical offerings reveal that better differentiated tariffs can significantly improve value proposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public performance: changes in the restaurant, entertainment, retail outlet industry makes periodical tariff review necessary. The structure of restaurant, leisure and retailing changed significantly over two decades, creating chains of restaurants or retail outlets that have significant bargaining power and professional purchasing management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot more information on the slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;./usecase/&#34;&gt;Use cases&lt;/a&gt; of this website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
