<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>value-gap | Creative Data Observatories</title>
    <link>/tag/value-gap/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/value-gap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>value-gap</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>value-gap</title>
      <link>/tag/value-gap/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Czech Music Development Program &amp; Comparative Market Research</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was presenting some highlights from the work we started with in the organization of SoundCzech with 25 music professionals representing more than 20 stakeholders in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/2019_10_09_praha/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; evaluation workshop in the context of the comparative 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the full presentation, including slides not shown in the workshop 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/presentation/nouvelle-prague&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The presentation is a self-contained big file of 20Mb, takes time to load.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work is done in a collaborative manner with the open Research Consortium started by SoundCzech, CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent.  We would like to invite any Czech stakeholders, or even individuals to join our efforts.  Because in the music sector, all organization are microenterprise or small enterprise sized, they usually have no significant market research, innovation and strategic HR management capacities. We hope to give them in each country useful tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very interesting part of the discussion in the morning was around transparency and potential conflict between stronger and weaker markets. Thank you for all colleagues who came on a Saturday morning after great showcase concerts the night before, and let&amp;rsquo;s stay in touch!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After much delay, the first measurement of licensed use of music, audiovisual content, home copying and value transfer to media platforms in Croatia for a practical update of the private copying remuneration in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the whole study in English, a Croatian language summary and a press release in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The models presented are simplified models of the Hungarian and Slovak models, with less detailed data. However, they show clearly that in less developed markets, compensation for unlicensed use remains a key issue. Only a very small fraction of households pay for music and film, and creators, performers, film writers are massively undercompensated in the Croatia, Bulgaria, Romania, Poland or the Baltic states of the EU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My study, Private Copying in Croatia, argues that the cultural and welfare benefits of this private copying regime are enormous and important to create a good quality of life in Croatia for all age groups, but especially for young people, and it must be maintained. Furthermore, it is very advantageous for the tech sector, because their products are mainly used with unlicensed music and film copies, given that only a very small portion of the population pays for downloads, or subscribes to services like Spotify, Deezer or Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even for those who are not interested in royalties, the first 3 chapters offer a very interesting introduction on how people listen to music, how musicians make music and how people copy it in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was a continuation of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2016-04-20_makk15/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;mapping of the Croatian music sector&lt;/a&gt;. I have created more detailed valuation and use studies of private copying and YouTube in Hungary (2015, 2017, 2018, 2019) and currently preparing similar studies in other countries, including Slovakia, as a continuation of the work started with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; and generally my home copying work started in 2012 with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/cisac_goodg_13/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Press release: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zamp.hr/clanak/pregled/2197/studija-naknade-za-privatno-kopiranje-btl-u-hrvatskoj-drasticno-ispod-prosjeka-eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Studija: Naknade za privatno kopiranje (BTL) u Hrvatskoj drastično ispod prosjeka EU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short summary in Croatian: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zamp.hr/uploads/documents/Saetak_studije_na_hrvatskom_jeziku.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Privatno kopiranje u Hrvatskoj&lt;/a&gt;
Full text in English: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zamp.hr/uploads/documents/Studija_privatno_kopiranje_u_Hrvatskoj_DA_CEEMID.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Private Copying in Croatia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMP Session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion on Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/post/2017-09-29_ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2017-09-29_ceempc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID had the honor to participate in the third panel of CEEMP in Warsaw together with Ben McEwen from ICE; Jules Parker from Spotify and Dominic Houston from Netflix, and Chris Butler from Music Sales, who is also the chairperson of ICMP. Our panel was moderated by Nigel Elderton from peermusic, who is also the new chairperson of PRS in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jules from Spotify spoke about their new initiative, Spotify for Publishers.  Spotify pays out about 20% of its royalties to publishers.  Because the labels are the bigger stakeholders, they often do not provide the necessary information for work identification in the case of publishers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominic from Netflix is already one of the biggest buyers of music, and I believe that his company’s footprint will just continue growing.  His time buys licenses only 10% of their music from publishers. They mainly use original film music, and to a significant degree, catalogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben made a presentation about their innovation efforts at ICE digital rights management. Working with some of the largest repertoires represented by PRS, GEMA and STIM, they really offer world class services. Next year they promise to scale services to smaller repertoires, who can immediately benefit from low-cost identification from the cleaned data of these large societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital gap between household cultural spending and CE / S European music industry revenues in the digital world
Comparing household cultural spending with digital music revenues in Europe’s main regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel’s short presentation highlighted the fact that the CEE region’s is much richer in terms of household cultural and recreational spending that it is thought by the music industry, because the music industry is really lagging its Western and Nordic peers in tapping into this pool of money.  There are many reasons for this, all a bit touched upon the other speaker’s issues, and their implementation difficulties n the CEE region, especially different revenue stream breakup, strong collective management and relatively underdeveloped publishing.  The region is about 200% or more below its benchmark in the sales we were talking about in this session.  The conversation will continue in Brussels, Prague, Budapest, Bratislava and Warsaw in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
