<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music-export | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>/tag/music-export/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/music-export/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>music-export</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 08:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>music-export</title>
      <link>/tag/music-export/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: The Youniverse from East to Southwest</title>
      <link>/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/</guid>
      <description>




  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-guitarist-jerguš-oravec-and-singer-tammy-nižňanska&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/Youniverse_bw_hu058abfd6177ddd8e71df0e608d9f6cd1_975961_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Guitarist Jerguš Oravec and singer Tammy Nižňanska&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/Youniverse_bw_hu058abfd6177ddd8e71df0e608d9f6cd1_975961_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1440&#34; height=&#34;810&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Guitarist Jerguš Oravec and singer Tammy Nižňanska
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Youniverse as a band and creator collective was formed in 2015 around guitarist Jerguš Oravec and singer Tammy Nižňanska. Changing genres and forms, creating musical and visual worlds spiced up with BDSM attire they have been playing shows in Slovakia and releasing a full-length album in 2018.  Tammy is a bilingual Slovak, who is more comfortable in the English language due to her upbringing than in the country’s language, and against what she feels to be the expectation of the local audience, she sings in English.  No wonder that she is also looking for ways to expand their universe beyond the country borders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bYsOnmUeLHE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tammy believes that The Youniverse it at a crossroads.  To be more successful at home, they would have to switch to their native Slovak language, and to be more successful in English they would have to connect better to foreign audiences.  She believes that the local audiences often seek a different quality than what she offers – the purity of her voice instead of auto-tune, or the native language instead of the language of rock and roll. Therefore, their main targets are the Southwestern part of the United States, particularly Los Angeles in California and Austin in Texas, and they believe that their eccentric show would probably create interest in Japan, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do they know or think of big data algorithms? The Youniverse hired a Google Analytics manager and they try to figure out how they could reach out to fans in far away places, or to understand how their songs occasionally find their ways to people in different countries.  Tammy knows that Spotify employs playlist curators who are helped with computer-based algorithms to find new music, but she is not familiar with the process – that is why she volunteered to participate in our Listen Local project and our Feasibility Study for the creation of a Slovakian music promotion service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/artist/1TIOHaY7eRJ6jZVA1NLYrk&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; is developing transparent algorithms and open source solutions to find new audiences for independent music. We want to correct the injustice and inherent bias of market leading big data algorithms. If you want&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;your music and audience&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;to be analysed in Listen Local, fill&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in. We will include you in our demo application for local music recommendations and our analysis to be revealed in December.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Audience: Size Of Music Discovery Age Populations In Europe</title>
      <link>/post/2020-11-20-music-discovery-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 15:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-11-20-music-discovery-population/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is various global and national research available on the music discovery demography.  People usually discover new music in their young age as they are forming their own personal identity with their peer group.  This process mainly happens in the school, where similarly aged, educated young people spend much of their day together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music discovery phase is strongly related to the time when most people get their music education: their skills to listen to music, play music or sing, and to compose new music. Investment into music education pays of in later age: people with more diverse music education, for example, with the ability to play music, tend to visit concerts more or discover more music in later life stages.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-annual-growth-top-chart-and-total-growth-lower-chart-of-the-15-24-years-old-population-in-select-european-countries&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/comparative/music_discovery_population.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;The annual growth (top chart) and total growth (lower chart) of the 15-24 years-old population in select European countries.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/comparative/music_discovery_population.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The annual growth (top chart) and total growth (lower chart) of the 15-24 years-old population in select European countries.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For practical reasons and supported by academic research, we chose the age group 15-24 as the key age group for music discovery.  We placed the national population of the music discovery age group in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://data.music.dataobservatory.eu/music-society.html#audiences&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music &amp;amp; Society&lt;/a&gt; pillar of the Demo Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changes across Europe are dramatic: in Latvia and the Baltic states, the music discovery age population decreased by 60% since the countries (re-)gained independence in 1991. Musicians and their organizations must work hard in these countries on developing export strategies if they want to maintain the market and audience of their music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some European countries, for example, the Netherlands and Turkey have significantly increased their future audiences. In Turkey this is mainly related to population growth, in the Netherlands to immigration. Countries with a growing young population have a strong position for their music business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all lost in the Baltics and other countries where the &lt;code&gt;music discovery age population &lt;/code&gt; is shrinking.  Much of the lost young population migrated to the United Kingdom and other parts of Europe. If artists and their association in these countries find a way to connect with these new diaspora, their market loss will be far less dramatic. Connecting to the diaspora is the most natural way to start exporting new music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the data from the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://data.music.dataobservatory.eu/music-society.html#audiences&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earlier this year we introduced some in-depth comparison of music audiences in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/audience.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;. Central European Music Industry Report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo credit 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:TeenStar_2013_Winner.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LauraMayM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Exports &amp; Imports</title>
      <link>/project/music-export/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/music-export/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Europe, like most regions of the world, is a net importer of music, but has very signficant export potential. Intra-European export is also very significant, especially from Germany, France, Sweden and the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Central and Eastern European region is relatively weak in exporting recorded and live performances, but it is among global leaders in creating export revenues from festivals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I am involved in creating predicitve models that help finding the best potential foreign market for music, and I make economic impact assessments of cultural tourism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If we take a look at the streaming charts of the region, we usually find that the vast majority of the streamed songs are foreign songs - except for Austria, U.S. songs.  For comparison, we added a similar, middle-income emerging market (Argentina) and a rich, small-population English-speaking country, Australia to the chart. These countries seem to be in a similar position to the CEE countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dataanimation/domestic_market_share_animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Market shares August-September 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably, the strongest countries of songwriting are the United States and Brazil - these are the countries that have ran out of the ISRC recording identifier range. Their charts are full with their domestic songs, but they are not alone.  Japan, France, and the bigger EU countries, France, Germany and Poland have very strong domestic performance, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are many factor at play here. Large countries with large artist populations generate a lot more recordings, so they local fans always have thousands of new songs to select from.  In small countries, the total annual creations, from pop to jazz, from authentic folk to classical amounts to a few thousand tracks. But it is not only size that matters.  Sweden&amp;rsquo;s population is similar to that of Austria, Hungary and Czechia, yet the Swedish repertoire performs better in Sweden, and as we will see in the next chart, abroad, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created a second data animation to visualize how hits were travelling across the borders in the summer of 2ö19. To make the chart easier to read, we omitted the United States, Brazil and Japan as countries of origin, and concentrated only on intra-European hit flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dataanimation/cross_border_plot-animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Cross-border hits August-September 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second week of September 2019 was not an exceptional week. Most EU countries&#39; producers did not score any hits in any other EU countries&#39; Spotify Top 50 hits.  The UK exported many great hits to all over Europe, as usual, but there were other important hit flows. These hits mainly follow cultural proximity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France exported hits to the two Francophone countries of Europe, Belgium and Romania, and furthermore to Greece, a Southern country with particularly unique chart composition. Germany exported many hits to Austria, another German-speaking country, and some hits to other Germanic countries. Dutch producers placed a few hits in the Germanic countries and in Belgium, where the Dutch-speaking Flemish community has its own radios, TVs, press and hitlists. The Netherlands is a powerhouse of electronic popmusic that are not bound by language which finds audience in several countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strength and competitive position of the national market where an artists is most known and has a fan base is usually a determining factor of track performance and revenue.  The overall revenue prospects and competition situation of a Hungarian or Croatian song is very different from a British or even a Polish song.  But overall, most European recordings are not bound to a domestic country. Because of cultural proximity, the presence of native minorities or new immigrant diasporas, even small-language songs are being listened to on a much wider territory than the artists&#39; original country. Some relatively small EU countries, such as Sweden and the Netherlands successfully export their music on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, as the streaming services slowly overtake all other forms of use, the charts above depict a very fundamental market change.  Whereas in the traditional channels of physical sales, digital downloads and broadcasting, the CEE countries, like other small- and medium-sized EU countries, enjoyed 30-50% market share, among the streaming hits their producer&amp;rsquo;s share is below 10%. It is not unusual to find only domestic recordings in physical sales hitlists, while domestic songs rarely enter the streaming charts in the region, with the exception of Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional sales channels protected CEE markets in several ways.  After EU accession most import duties are gone, but physical products have very significant logistics costs, which gives local producers a competitive edge.  Because physical products are increasingly sold on concerts and festivals, where the market share of domestic performers is usually very high, the traditional, mechanically licensed sales had a protected market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The broadcasting channel, which used the be the most important promotion channel, too, was protected in many European countries by national content quotas, or supported with generously funded national, regional, local public broadcasters who gave a preference to national composers, producers and performers. These market barriers are not present in the streaming markets, which poses many questions. Our research is aiming to answer these questions, but it took several years to build a data infrastructure that can help producing an accurate market overview.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/eu_cross_border_hits_20190915.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;European hits on an other European country&amp;amp;rsquo;s Spotify hitlist, 15 September 2019.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/eu_cross_border_hits_20190915_hu87f5dcff746518fbceefbd4abed84ec5_40449_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;266&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;National repertoire market shares on national Spotify hitlists, 15 September 2019.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915_hu781d82e369311575b56de92db7530f5f_19890_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;266&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These findings will be open to discussion on&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/waves_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Waves Music Showcase Festival and Conference&lt;/a&gt; [click for details] &lt;em&gt;on 27 September 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
