<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creative Data Observatories</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Creative Data Observatories</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 15:31:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Creative Data Observatories</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product/Market Fit Validation in Yes!Delft</title>
      <link>/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 15:31:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate our product market/fit in two segments, business/policy research and scientific research, with a supporting role given to data journalism. Because we want to follow a bootstrapping strategy, we must focus on those clients where we find the highest value proposition, which is of course easier said than done.  We see much interest in our offering from other continents, therefore we truly welcome the opportunity that we can do this on a truly global business canvas in one of the worlds’ 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/news/yesdelft-among-the-top-5-business-incubators-in-the-world/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;top five incubators&lt;/a&gt;, the number 2 university-backed incubator in the world, second to none in Europe, in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/focus-areas/artificial-intelligence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain&lt;/a&gt; Validation Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Europe hundreds of thousands of microenterprises, such as record labels, video producers or book publishers are facing data and AI giants like Google’s YouTube, Apple Music, Spotify, Netflix or Amazon. If the recommendation engines of these giants do not recommend their songs, films or books, then their investments are doomed to fail, because about half of the global sales are driven by AI algorithms. When they make a claim for the missing money, they will immediately find themselves in a dispute with gigabytes of data that they can only handle with a data scientist, even though they do not even have an IT professional or an HR professional to make the hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An awful lot of money, creativity and real values are at stake, and we want to be on the creator’s side, their technician’s side, their manager’s side when they want to get a fair share from the pie and they want to help these industry leader to make the pie grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unesco.org/new/en/culture/themes/creativity/arts-education/research-cooperation/observatories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UNESCO&lt;/a&gt; and the EU have been promoting as an organizational solution the fragmentation problem with the so-called data observatories that are pooling the business, policy, and scientific research needs of various domains, like music. This is an idea that we really like, and we believe that our research automation solutions can help these observatories to grow faster as ecosystems, create better quality and more timely data and research products and a far lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define ourselves as a reproducible research company inspired by the philosophy of open collaboration, based on open-source software and open data. We want to explore various revenue models around these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not committed to open source licensing if more permissive licensing policies provide us with better opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to explore various data-as-service models, because we do not want to be locked into the position of cheap open data vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to deploy AI applications that really help earning money in these sectors with playlisting, recommendation engines, forecasting applications, or royalty valuations, because our open collaboration approach brings up enough data sooner to than its alternatives, because it manages inherent conflicts of interests, fragmentation, and decentralization better than hierarchical solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January CEEMID reached its peak: we introduced a 12-country 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproducible research project&lt;/a&gt; made with only freelancers in Brussels, presented as best use case of evidence-based policy design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February Daniel visited the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/yes-delft-co-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft Co-Lab&lt;/a&gt; to find out who would be the best co-founder to re-launch CEEMID as an enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April we started to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;release our data&lt;/a&gt; as open data for validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month ago we 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started-up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we launched the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few other 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/annex.html#other-observatories&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data observatories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.palato.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Palato&lt;/a&gt; in the Hague, where we took our selfie and had an absolutely amazing dinner after the pitch. Check them out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible Survey Harmonization: retroharmonize Is Released</title>
      <link>/post/2020-09-21-retroharmonize_release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 11:31:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-09-21-retroharmonize_release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our original intention was to make surveying more accessible for music and creative industry partners, by relying more on already existing survey data, and better designing complementary, smaller surveys, becasue surveying, opinion polling is becoming increasingly expensive in the develop world.  People are less and less likely to sit down for an interview in their houses.  We have tried to harmonize our custom surveys, particuarly with Kantar in Hungary and Focus in Slovakia with exisiting EU projects.  But we ended up making a part of international survey harmonization across countries and throughout years easier to automate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/packages/ab_plot1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Harmonized results from Afrobarometer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surveys are like sensors for natural sciences and industrial production. They are essential for almost any social and economic statistical indicator, for calculating the inflation, parts of the GDP, participation in education programs.  Making surveys easier to harmonize and exploit more already existing survey data can bring down research cost, and can increase research value at the same time. (See our earlier blog post 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-07-10-retroharmonize/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Increase The Value Of Market Research With Open Data And Survey Harmonization&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you are an R user, you can use &lt;code&gt;install.packages(“retroharmonize”)&lt;/code&gt; to get the released 0.1.13 version and make tutorials with real Eurobarometer or Afrobarometer microdata.  With &lt;code&gt;devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;antaldaniel/retroharmonize&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt; you can already install the current development version 0.1.14, which handles perl-like regex, which will be necessary for our next tutorial in the making for 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arabbarometer.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Arab Barometer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize package website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/antaldaniel/retroharmonize/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize on github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching Our Demo Music Observatory</title>
      <link>/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 08:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, on 15 September 2020, we officially launched our &lt;code&gt;minimal viable product&lt;/code&gt; as we promised to partners back in February. This was a particularly difficult period for everybody. We aspired to deliver by September in a very different environment, our hopes for commissioned work went up in flames with the pandemic, and our targeted users, musicians and music entrepreneurs, talent managers, music venues lost most of their income. The organizations helping them, granting authorities, export offices and collective management societies are overwhelmed with the problem. During these troublesome times, our team expanded, attracted great new talent, and kept working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first product is the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, a collaborative, automated research-based 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/faq/observatories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;observatory&lt;/a&gt; for the music industry, one that is particularly hard hit by the COVID19 crisis. Not only great artists, composers, technicians, managers fell victim to the virus, but musicians lost about 50–90% of their income from live music. This translates to a 100% loss for the live music technicians and managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fQJHflWPS34&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

See our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;earlier blogpost&lt;/a&gt; on what you see on the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry was never a place for great job security. For putting up a show, you usually need a network of 10–200 artists, technicians and managers to work together as freelancers without all those social benefits that many people enjoy in other walks of life. We have been trying to figure out how to help this microenterprise and freelancer-network based industry with research for five years. Our aim is to make them competitive when they are talking with their buyers: Google, Apple, Spotify, who are really heavy-weight data and AI pros. Our better plan their tours, when they will be back on the road, to understand what sort of audiences and purchasing power waits for them in different European cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are launching at a time when the music industry is crying for help.Therefore, we have decided to make our demo observatory open and unfinished. Over the last 7 years, we have built up about 2000 music and creative sector indicators to be used for business KPIs, forecasting targets, grant evaluations, royalty valuations, concert demography target group analysis and other professional uses. We would like to open up, based on your needs, about 50 well-designed indicators, and pledge to keep it daily refreshed, corrected, documented, citaable, downloadable. Also, feel free to use our most valuable source code—use it for your own purposes, even modify it, as long as you keep it open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our smaller partners, we follow what musicians do these days on Bandcamp: name your price. We make a pledge to our small partners: if you need reliable data to plan your next grant calls, calculate royalties, compensations, predict hit candidates, give us the job—and name your price. Post-corona, you can take for a dollar the best music from Bandcamp. You can take our research products, for a limited period, for any amount you name, as long as  it is for a good cause and serves the industry, musicians, technicians or managers. In return, we ask for your feedback. Help us validate whether we are on the right track, tell us how we can cooperate after the pandemic, in better times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our larger and better funded partners? We ask you to pay the price we name, because we believe that it is a well-justified, fair and competitive price, set by pricing experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appreciate it if you take a look at our offering, or if you pass this blogpost on to your colleagues in the industry.  Our main target audience initially are music professional in broader Europe, but we are planning to cover all major global markets very soon, too. Feedback from the U.S., Australia, Canada, Colombia, Brazil &amp;amp; Argentina is particularly welcome as we have great plans over there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-we-are&#34;&gt;Who we are?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; our operations on 1 September 2020 on the basis of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://documentation.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt;, a pan-European data observatory that created about 2000 music and creative industry indicators for its users. In the coming days, we are gradually opening up about 50 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music industry&lt;/a&gt; and 50 broader creative industry indicators in a fully reproducible workflow, with daily re-freshed, re-processed, well-formatted and documented indicators for business and policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate this approach in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious university-backed incubator programs, in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/yes-programs/ai-blockchain-validation-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI/Blockchain Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re finalist on their selection, and all help before 23 September from our friends in the music industry is more than appreciated. If we get there, we can rely on probably the best pros in Europe to make our offering better tailored and financially sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-in-touch&#34;&gt;Get in touch!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the very simple and extremely secure &lt;strong&gt;keybase.io&lt;/strong&gt;, a kind of mix of Whatsapp, Skype, Google Drive, One Drive and zoom. You can get in touch on that platform with us in anytime 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/team/reprexcommunity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily contact on LinkedIn 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/k%C3%A1tya-nagy-a9447730/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kátya&lt;/a&gt; and of course, we have a usually working 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;email contact form&lt;/a&gt;, too. Our email is name.surname at our main domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-credits&#34;&gt;Video credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data acquisition and processing: Daniel Antal, CFA and Marta Kołczyńska, PhD (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/economy.html#demand&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;survey data&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation automation: Sandor Budai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video art: Line Matson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/moonmoonmoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating An Automated Data Observatory</title>
      <link>/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 16:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are building data ecosystems, so called observatories, where scientific, business, policy and civic users can find factual information, data, evidence for their domain.  Our open source, open data, open collaboration approach allows to connect various open and proprietary data sources, and our reproducible research workflows allow us to automate data collection, processing, publication, documentation and presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our scripts are checking data sources, such as Eurostat&amp;rsquo;s Eurobase, Spotify&amp;rsquo;s API and other music industry sources every day for new information, and process any data corrections or new disclosure, interpolate, backcast or forecast missing values, make currency translations and unit conversions. This is shown illustrated with an 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-07-25-reproducible_ingestion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;earlier post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fQJHflWPS34&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For direct access to the file visit 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/video/making-of-dmo.mp4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the video we show automated the creation of an observatory website with well-formatted, statistical data dissemination, a technical document in PDF and an ebook can be automated.  In our view, our technology is particularly useful technology in business and scientific researech projects, where it is important that always the most timely and correct data is being analyzed, and remains automatically documented and cited. We are ready deploy public, collaborative, or private data observatories in short time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data processing costs can be as high as 80% for any in-house AI deployment project. We work mainly with organization that do not have in house data science team, and acquire their data anyway from outside the organization. In their case, this rate can be as high as 95%, meaning that getting and processing the data for deploying AI can be 20x more expensive than the AI solution itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI solutions require a large amount of standardized, well processed data to learn from.  We want to radically decrease the cost of data acquisition and processing for our users so that exploiting AI becomes in their reach. This is particularly important in one of our target industries, the music industries, where most of the global sales is algorithmic and AI-driven. Artists, bands, small labels, publishers, even small country national associations cannot remain competitive if they cannot participate in this technological revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; our operations on 1 September 2020 on the basis of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://documentation.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt;, a pan-European data observatory that created about 2000 music and creative industry indicators for its users. In the coming days, we are gradually opening up about 50 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music industry&lt;/a&gt; and 50 broader creative industry indicators in a fully reproducible workflow, with daily re-freshed, re-processed, well-formatted and documented indicators for business and policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate this approach in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious university-backed incubator programs, in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/yes-programs/ai-blockchain-validation-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI/Blockchain Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-credits&#34;&gt;Video credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data acquisition and processing: Daniel Antal, CFA and Marta Kołczyńska, PhD (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/economy.html#demand&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;survey data&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation automation: Sandor Budai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video art: Line Matson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/moonmoonmoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>retroharmonize R package for survey harmonization</title>
      <link>/publication/retorharmonize_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/retorharmonize_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of &lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; is to provide tools for reproducible
retrospective (ex-post) harmonization of datasets that contain variables
measuring the same concepts but coded in different ways. Ex-post data
harmonization enables better use of existing data and creates new
research opportunities. For example, harmonizing data from different
countries enables cross-national comparisons, while merging data from
different time points makes it possible to track changes over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retrospective data harmonization is associated with challenges including
conceptual issues with establishing equivalence and comparability,
practical complications of having to standardize the naming and coding
of variables, technical difficulties with merging data stored in
different formats, and the need to document a large number of data
transformations. The &lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; package assists with the latter
three components, freeing up the capacity of researchers to focus on the
first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the &lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; package proposes a reproducible
workflow, including a new class for storing data together with the
harmonized and original metadata, as well as functions for importing
data from different formats, harmonizing data and metadata, documenting
the harmonization process, and converting between data types. See

&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/reference/retrohamonize.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
for an overview of the functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;code&gt;labelled_spss_survey()&lt;/code&gt; class is an extension of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://haven.tidyverse.org/reference/labelled_spss.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;haven’s
labelled_spss
class&lt;/a&gt;. It not
only preserves variable and value labels and the user-defined missing
range, but also gives an identifier, for example, the filename or the
wave number, to the vector. Additionally, it enables the preservation –
as metadata attributes – of the original variable names, labels, and
value codes and labels, from the source data, in addition to the
harmonized variable names, labels, and value codes and labels. This way,
the harmonized data also contain the pre-harmonization record. The
stored original metadata can be used for validation and documentation
purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vignette 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/articles/labelled_spss_survey.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Working With The labelled_spss_survey
Class&lt;/a&gt;
provides more information about the &lt;code&gt;labelled_spss_survey()&lt;/code&gt; class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/articles/harmonize_labels.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonize Value
Labels&lt;/a&gt;
we discuss the characteristics of the &lt;code&gt;labelled_spss_survey()&lt;/code&gt; class and
demonstrates the problems that using this class solves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also provide two extensive case studies illustrating how the
&lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; package can be used for ex-post harmonization of data
from cross-national surveys on the example of the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/articles/afrobarometer.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Afrobarometer&lt;/a&gt;
and the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/articles/eurobarometer.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt;.
The creators of &lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; are not affiliated with either
Afrobarometer, Eurobarometer, or the organizations that designs,
produces or archives their surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the &lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; project is released with a

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/version/2/0/code_of_conduct/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Contributor Code of
Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.
By contributing to this project, you agree to abide by its terms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting-up</title>
      <link>/post/2020-08-24-start-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-08-24-start-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big day has come: the co-founders singed off the documents at the public notary and started the registration of a reproducible research start-up in Leiden.  We got a lot of support from our friends! Your encouragement gives us a lot of energy to accomplish our first milestones, and to get Reprex B.V. going!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex means &amp;lsquo;reproducible example&amp;rsquo; in data science.  When you are stuck with a problem, creating a reproducible example allows other computer scientists, statisticians, programmers or data users to solve it. In 80% of the cases, you usually find the solution while creating a generalized example.  In the 20% other cases, you can reach out for help easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming days, we are launching demo versions of our headline products, data observatories. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; will be a fully automated online service that every day collects, processes, cleans, and publishes scientifically valid data about European music.  Very soon after we will launch two other observatories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative and cultural sector, NGOs, most research institutions, data journalism teams are usually very small, and they do not have internal IT or data science capacities.  We would like to provide them a transparent, high quality, and fully open source solution to acquire data, process it without errors, document it and make sense of it. We would like to embrace the idea of open collaboration among creative enterprises, scientific researchers, NGOs, data journalists and policymakers with our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work will comply with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/opa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Policy Analysis&lt;/a&gt; standards developed by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkeley Initiative for Transparency in the Social Sciences&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cega.berkeley.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Effective Global Action&lt;/a&gt; and the four principles of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/reproducible/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproducible research&lt;/a&gt;: reviewability, replicability, confirmability and auditability.  We believe that these standards apply in reproducible finance, empirical evidence presentation in courts, or advocating sound policies and producing high-quality journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;help&#34;&gt;Do you want to help our start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to enter into the Validation Lab of one of the best artificial intelligence incubators in early September. Talented team members, letters of intents and assignments from organizations will give a lot of credibility to our start 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/team/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Meet our team »&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put as in contact with people who love to write code in R and interested in automating business and social science research and primary data collection such as surveying. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/#featured&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out what sort of code we create »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduce us to people who need data and information to make better informed decision and analysis in music, film, book publishing, photography services or socially responsible finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share contacts of data journalists who would like to develop stories from big survey programs like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/commfrontoffice/publicopinion/index.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.afrobarometer.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Afrobarometer&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latinobarometro.org/lat.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lationbarometro&lt;/a&gt;, or base their storytelling on data and its visualizations. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://retroharmonize.satellitereport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;See our survey harmonization examples »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know such people?  Send over this post or connect us in an email or social media message!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks again for your good wishes and encouragements, and hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Music Professionals Survey Wave</title>
      <link>/post/2020-music-professional-survey-wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-music-professional-survey-wave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID is conducing its 8th survey programme this among musicians, music professionals, and music managers. This is the largest empirical research program in the world about how people work and earn their living in the music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are teaming up with some music organizations and research universities to form a Music Observatory, which will support all participant countries musicians with free data for royalty calculation, advocacy at government, tour scheduling and tour planning.  This year we particularly focus on effective COVID19 relief measures, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the results of last years&amp;rsquo; results:

&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; - free download in PDF, epub, or browse the html version.

&lt;a href=&#34;post/2020-01-30-ceereport/&#34;&gt;CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp;amp; The Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are asking music organizations to send out our questionnaires to their members, and we ask musicians to forward our questionnaires to music technicians and managers, too. After the fieldwork is done, we are sending back statistically analysed data, reports to the participating countries, and assist local music organizations to make the best use of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;which-countries-are-covered-this-year&#34;&gt;Which countries are covered this year?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous year we covered emerging Europe Austria, Czechia, Croatia, Hungary, Lithuania, Serbia, Slovakia, Slovenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we are aiming to cover some of our regularly surveyed countries, and a number of new, mainly developed markets. The countries will be announced shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible data ingestion in practice</title>
      <link>/post/2020-07-25-reproducible_ingestion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-07-25-reproducible_ingestion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-a-reproducible-data-ingestion-look-like-in-practice&#34;&gt;How does a reproducible data ingestion look like in practice?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your analytical work has used a certain type of data at least two times in the past, it is likely that the data will be needed again.  This is a good time to make the data ingestion automatic and reproducible.  We demonstrate a simple data ingestion from Eurostat.  Daniel is part of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ropengov.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rOpenGov&lt;/a&gt; collective that maintains the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ropengov/eurostat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurostat&lt;/a&gt; package for reproducible access to the European statistical agencies data warehouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;library(eurostat)
nuts3_population_raw &amp;lt;- get_eurostat (&amp;quot;demo_r_pjangrp3&amp;quot;) 
nuts3_population_metadata &amp;lt;- get_eurostat_toc() %&amp;gt;%
  filter ( code == &amp;quot;demo_r_pjangrp3&amp;quot; ) %&amp;gt;%
  distinct_all () 

last_update &amp;lt;- nuts3_population_metadata$`last update of data`
first_data &amp;lt;- nuts3_population_metadata$`data start`
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metadata entries to this statistics suggest that the latest data is from Thursday 14 May, 2020, so it is high time to refresh your data tables and update your charts. Sadly, the metadata suggest that on this occasion the table went through structural changes, so you may get a different spreadsheet table when you downloaded compared to the last occasion.  You may think that this is another reason to automate the ingestion into a well-defined, tidy table format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped table-hover table-condensed table-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
 &lt;thead&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; title &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; code &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; last update of data &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; last table structure change &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; data start &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; data end &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; Population on 1 January by age group, sex and NUTS 3 region &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; demo_r_pjangrp3 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 14.05.2020 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 14.05.2020 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2014 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2019 &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the head of this raw data, you realize that this is not table, but a little database! It contains population divisions by sex and age groups.  However, your indicator is the total population of each &lt;code&gt;NUTS3&lt;/code&gt; regions, so let’s filter out only the total population for both sexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped table-hover table-condensed table-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
 &lt;thead&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; sex &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; unit &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; age &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; geo &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; time &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; values &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; T &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; NR &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; Y_LT5 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; NO07 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2018-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 25108 &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; M &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; NR &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; Y10-14 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; DED44 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2014-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 4620 &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; F &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; NR &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; Y45-49 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; FRB &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2014-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 88590 &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the head of this raw data, you realize that this is not table, but a little database! It contains population divisions by sex and age groups.  However, your indicator is the total population of each &lt;code&gt;NUTS3&lt;/code&gt; regions, so let’s filter out only the total population for both sexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;nuts3_population &amp;lt;- nuts3_population_raw %&amp;gt;%
  filter ( sex == &amp;quot;T&amp;quot;,             # for both sexes
           age == &amp;quot;TOTAL&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%     # for all age groups
  mutate ( year = as.integer(substr(as.character(time), 1,4)), 
           indicator = paste0(&amp;quot;population_sex-&amp;quot;, sex, &amp;quot;_unit-&amp;quot;, unit, 
                               &amp;quot;_age-&amp;quot;, age)) %&amp;gt;%
  select ( -all_of(c(&amp;quot;sex&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;unit&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;age&amp;quot;))) 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following table is already tidy &amp;mdash; each observation corresponds with a small region of Europe.  The filtering information as metadata is included in the indicator&amp;rsquo;s name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped table-hover table-condensed table-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
 &lt;thead&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; geo &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; time &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; values &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; year &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; indicator &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; HU222 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2015-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 253997 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2015 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; NO &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2014-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 5107970 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2014 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; ES704 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2016-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 112087 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2016 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; FRK12 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2015-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 146219 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2015 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; DE3 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2018-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 3613495 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2018 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; NL225 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2019-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 400685 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2019 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;data_ingest_files/figure-html/choropleth-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The population size is rather homogeneous &amp;mdash; no wonder, the small regions of Europe are exactly defined to be roughly of equal size and easily comparable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are wondering how you could match this data with your own records, or data acquired from Google about number of restaurants or searchers for concerts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped table-hover table-condensed table-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
 &lt;thead&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; geo &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; time &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; values &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; year &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; indicator &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; IE042 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2017-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 451293 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2017 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; SI044 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2014-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 112848 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2014 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; DE225 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2015-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 77927 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2015 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; PL621 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2016-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 523096 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2016 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; TRB13 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2018-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 273354 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2018 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; FRK24 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; 2018-01-01 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 1261373 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2018 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; population_sex-T_unit-NR_age-TOTAL &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no easy solution for this problem.  Within the EU in the last 20 years there were several thousand internal boundary changes &amp;mdash; states, provinces, regions are rather free to change their internal administration boundaries. Regions are constantly changing their names or their spelling, too. Sometimes they use a standard English translation of their region, sometimes only the national language variants.  In Greece or Bulgaria they do not even use the Latin alphabet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/author/daniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/author/istvan-zsoldos/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Istvan&lt;/a&gt; created and released an open-source code library, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://regions.danielantal.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; to deal with similar issues. It allows the changes between boundary definition between 1999-2021, or the connection of the globally used geographical typology adopted by Google with Eurostat&amp;rsquo;s EU-only definitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you can already foresee that there are future changes (to be implemented from the year 2021) that will affect two of these regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;set.seed(21)
validate_for_2021 &amp;lt;- nuts3_population  %&amp;gt;%
  select ( -all_of(c(&amp;quot;time&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;indicator&amp;quot;)) ) %&amp;gt;%
  sample_n(8) %&amp;gt;%
  regions::validate_nuts_regions(., nuts_year = 2021 ) 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped table-hover table-condensed table-responsive&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
 &lt;thead&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; geo &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; values &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; year &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; typology &lt;/th&gt;
   &lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; valid_2021 &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; DE248 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 115681 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2018 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; nuts_level_3 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; TRUE &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; BG422 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 228141 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2019 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; nuts_level_3 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; TRUE &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; UKN13 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 139774 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2014 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; NA &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; FALSE &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; FRH0 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 3276543 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2014 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; nuts_level_2 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; TRUE &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; DEB3 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2031780 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2016 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; nuts_level_2 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; TRUE &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; ITG25 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 335097 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2014 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; NA &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; FALSE &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; DE71A &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 232848 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2016 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; nuts_level_3 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; TRUE &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; FI1D5 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 68677 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt; 2014 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; nuts_level_3 &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt; TRUE &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is trouble ahead, but we have a table that is tidy and works for the time being.  Let&amp;rsquo;s save it and document it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;eurostat::get_bibentry(&amp;quot;demo_r_pjangrp3&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## @Misc{demo_r_pjangrp3_14-05-2020,
##   title = {Population on 1 January by age group, sex and NUTS 3 region [demo_r_pjangrp3]},
##   url = {https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/web/products-datasets/-/demo_r_pjangrp3},
##   language = {en},
##   year = {14.05.2020},
##   publisher = {Eurostat},
##   author = {{Eurostat}},
##   urldate = {2020-07-25},
## }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-reproducibility-in-this-case&#34;&gt;What is reproducibility in this case?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Replicability&lt;/strong&gt; means that somebody else in your team can get exactly the same data as in this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording exactly what have your analysts downloaded, including source, date, filtering settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducibility&lt;/strong&gt; means that not only your team, but an external auditor or a peer reviewer can easily validate that your data is sound. All our solutions are opens source, and use the most popular statistical programming language, R. Anybody with a basic knowledge of R, or probably even SQL (we use an extension of R that uses SQL-like syntax) can read if everything goes allright. Your team can even modify the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a documentation that you updates your reports data citations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmability&lt;/strong&gt; means that somebody who is not using . All our solutions are opens source, and use the most popular statistical programming language, R.  R is supported by Microsofts BI products, SPSS and other statistical software, too. We are not a software company, there is no vendor lock-in, and our work can be confirmed with other statistical software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data acquired via our data gathering apps is automatically documented, follows tidy formats and valid abbreviations, and can be confirmed in a wide range of statistical and spreadsheet applications, including SPSS, Excel, OpenOffice, Google Spreadsheets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bringing the data to a tidy format which is easy to join with other data in a spreadsheet application, or stored in a relational database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validating the data structure, in this case, with special attention to regional boundaries and regional names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auditability&lt;/strong&gt; means that external auditors can validate that the data your team uses from our app is correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are following methodological guidelines and definitions set by international bodies such as Eurostat&amp;rsquo;s ESSNet statistical network or IFRS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our critical software code is not only open source, but goes through various levels of statistical peer-review. We are sending for scientific validation and peer-review our methodology, too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being open source allows us to make any corrections, updates, should any problem or standard change affect the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;references&#34; class=&#34;section level2 unnumbered&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-R-regions&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel. 2020. &lt;em&gt;Regions: Processing Regional Statistics&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://regions.danielantal.eu/&#34;&gt;https://regions.danielantal.eu/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-demo_r_pjangrp3_14-05-2020&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eurostat. n.d. Eurostat. Accessed July 25, 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/web/products-datasets/-/demo_r_pjangrp3&#34;&gt;https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/web/products-datasets/-/demo_r_pjangrp3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-R-eurostat&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lahti, Leo, Janne Huovari, Markus Kainu, and Przemyslaw Biecek. 2020. &lt;em&gt;Eurostat: Tools for Eurostat Open Data&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=eurostat&#34;&gt;https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=eurostat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-R-eurostat&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hadley Wickham. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Tidy Data&lt;/em&gt;.Journal of Statistical Software vol 59, no 10.&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstatsoft.org/v059/i10&#34;&gt;https://www.jstatsoft.org/v059/i10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible Research</title>
      <link>/faq/reproducible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/reproducible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reproducible-research&#34;&gt;Reproducible Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We apply data science, and intersection of quantitative social sciences &amp;amp; management science, statistics and computer science, to make data collection, processing and analysis fully reproducible.  Our observatory systems allow users to save thousands of working hours in data collection, in senior supervision, documentation and compliance functions. We want to help business researchers, policymakers, scientists and journalist to focus on what they do best, and use the latest, most complete, and perfectly processed information to support their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our methodology can be used in business consultancy, evidence-based policy making, social and management science and data journalism. We thrive to support all these communities, because by incorporating their different review, confirmation and auditing processing, and provide an even more reliable, robust data services to all of our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviewability&lt;/strong&gt; means that our application’s results are can be assessed and judged by our user’s experts, or experts they trust. We not only automate data collection and cleaning, but we also automate documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewability for &lt;em&gt;professional consultants&lt;/em&gt; means that the data is always avaible with the freshest forms and with up-to-date documentation, instead of ad hoc spreadsheets collected, modified and overwritten by junior staff. The usual error-prone work that junior staff does is done by our observatory system automatically, and all the latest spreadsheets are available for all staff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewability in a &lt;em&gt;scientific context&lt;/em&gt; means that our observatory systems produce the research data in a well-documented format that adheres to the expectation of social scientific and management science peer-review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewability in &lt;em&gt;data journalism&lt;/em&gt; means that all the data is automatically refreshed and present for journalistic and editorial source-checking and analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducibility&lt;/strong&gt; means that we are providing data products and tools that allow the exact duplication of our results during assessments. The most important aspect of our reproducibility is that we make the entire statistical program code either fully open source, or make the entire algorithm available for our clients. From the raw data that they give us, or we collect for them, they can arrive step-by-step to the same indicator or KPI values. Reproducibility ensures that there is no lock-in to our applications. You can always chose a different data and software vendor, or compare our results with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reproducibility in &lt;em&gt;a consulting context&lt;/em&gt; means that our data is well-processed and described, and a senior analyst can re-create it, or even modify it to the organizations needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;em&gt;a scientific context&lt;/em&gt; it means that other researchers can reproduce the scientific findings which are supported by our data, because it is of high quality, well formatted and documented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;em&gt;data journalism&lt;/em&gt; this means that journalist can reliably follow leads and sources over a longer period of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are creating applications that are confirmable and auditable. These are usually required by the ethical guidelines and professional standards of our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmability&lt;/strong&gt; means that using our applications findings leads to the same professional results as other available software and information. Our data products use the open-source statistical programming language R. We provide details about our algorithms and methodology to confirm our results in SPSS or Stata or sometimes even in Excel or OpenOffice. Confirmability is often a requirement of various ethical guideleins and professional standards that our clients must adhere to in the legal, economic or policy-making professions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reproducibility in a &lt;em&gt;consulting context&lt;/em&gt; means that our data is well-processed and described, and a senior analyst can re-create it, or even modify it to the organizations needs.  They can confront the data with their qualitative results or parallel information bases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a &lt;em&gt;scientific context&lt;/em&gt; it means that other researchers can reproduce the scientific findings which are supported by our data, because it is of high quality, well formatted and documented. If any issues are raised with scientific confirmation, we assist our scientific partner to amend, replace or correct the problematic data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;em&gt;data journalism&lt;/em&gt; this means that journalist can reliably follow leads and sources over a longer period of time. We review the entire data pipeline if our journalistic partners find contrary evidence or red flags with our data sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auditability&lt;/strong&gt; means that our data and software is archived in a way that external auditors can later review, reproduce and confirm our findings.  This is a &lt;em&gt;stricter form of data retention&lt;/em&gt; that most organizations apply, because we do not only archive results step-by-step but all computational steps – as if your colleagues would not only save every step in Excel but also their keystrokes. While auditability is a requirement in accounting, but we are extending this approach to all the quantitative work of a professional organization in an advisory or consulting capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auditability means that we are following &lt;em&gt;professional guidelines and standards&lt;/em&gt; of various statistical, accounting, national accounting and other professional bodies to develop our indicators and data products, and we allow auditors to review not only our data, but the entire history of the data processing, including key elements of our software code, and our general methodology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auditability means for us that we make our critical methods and software code available for &lt;em&gt;peer-review&lt;/em&gt; both as a software on CRAN and as a statistical method in an appropriate, peer-reviewed journal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a data journalism context our data products can be subject to &lt;em&gt;full editorial and journalistic&lt;/em&gt; review, from source to publication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/team/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps</title>
      <link>/faq/modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;analytics-applications&#34;&gt;Analytics applications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the increasing availability of connected and big data, automated regressions, forecasting, predictive machine learning &amp;amp; AI helps modern organizations to reach their business, policy and scientific goals, or help data journalists to reveal hidden patterns. Our applications can run tens of thousands of model variants and help to focus data analysis human intuition and knowledge on the most promising leads. The use of these analytics methods relies on often hundreds of standardized and independent variables (&amp;ldquo;features&amp;rdquo;), which cannot be consistently maintained by error-prone human analyst work.  Our data integration applications makes sure that the data is available in a statistically tidy, easy to use format. Our analytics applications adhere to the tidy modelling standards, which allow the proper documentation and comparison of hundreds of model families from the simpler linear and multiple regressions to advanced non-linear models, supervised and unsupervised models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organization investing into reproducible research can rely on tens of thousands of analytical model candidates for their work &amp;mdash; putting traditional analysts into an impossible competition.  We believe that our applications should produce thosandds of model candidates and comparisons, and leave human wisdom and intuition to refining the most promising leads.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consulting</title>
      <link>/faq/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/consulting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;analyitcs-consultation&#34;&gt;Analyitcs consultation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We support our reproducible data collection, analysis and reporting with management and policy consulting and training.  We not only make far more, better documented and higher quality data available for your consulting, policy or editorial teams, but we show them how to find answers with advanced analytics tools for strategic or detailed questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Access and Participation surveys</title>
      <link>/faq/cap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/cap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cultural Access and Participation Surveys are standardized surveys designed to measure various market-based and non-market based (amateur, liturgical, etc.) cultural activities, including concerts, streaming subscriptions, singing, etc.  They are based on various quantative sociological models and had been standardized by the Eurostat working group 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/assets/eac/culture/library/reports/ess-net-report_en.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ESSNet-Culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEEMID CAP surveys are usually live interviews that allow cross-country comparison, and they are used both for market forecasting, market analytics, royalty and compensation value setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-europe-2013&#34;&gt;CAP Europe 2013&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the data of the CAP 2013 survey for cross-country comparisons and for model calibration, because it includes all EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cee_concert_demography_16x9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Comparative Demography with CAP EU 2013&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-europe-2007&#34;&gt;CAP Europe 2007&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the data of the CAP 2007 survey for understanding cross-country dynamics and long-term changes, because it includes all EU countries. For example, we can determine in which countries visit &lt;code&gt;Generation Z&lt;/code&gt; 20-years-old people more concerts or cinemas than their &lt;code&gt;Generation X&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Generation Y&lt;/code&gt; peers when they were 20-years-old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2019&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2019 survey fieldwork is under way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2018&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2018 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying, the value transfer to YouTube and other media platforms, and the development of the audidence for Hungarian films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2017&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2017 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying. A separate mini-CAP survey was designed to capture the value transfer to YouTube, which was later incorporated into the CAP Hungary 2018-2019 surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-croatia-2017&#34;&gt;CAP Croatia 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Croatia 2017 survey was designed for the creation of the Private Copying in Croatia report, which is prepared for the forthcoming Croatian Copyright legislation changes on private copying and the value gap.  The survey was conducted by Hendall on a sample of 800 respondents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-slovakaia-2015&#34;&gt;CAP Slovakaia 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Slovakia 2015 survey was designed as a part of a larger survey that also incorporated attitudes towards Slovak culture and non-standard survey questions designed by Focus.  The CAP Survey was used to create the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; and to make various legislative impact assessment presentations during the modification of the Slovak Copyright Law on private copying and radio quotas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2015&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2015 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors. It was used in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gvh.hu/sajtoszoba/sajtokozlemenyek/2016_os_sajtokozlemenyek/az_ures_hordozoi_dij_fogasztoi_visszaigenylesenek_.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;competition authority case&lt;/a&gt; related to the Hungarian private copying regime and in a consulting project related to better finding the audience of Hungarian cinemas in their domestic theatrical market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey was conducted by TNS Hoffmann (currently named Kantar Hoffmann.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2014&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2014 was a non-representative, large-sample online survey to pilot the later surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps</title>
      <link>/faq/dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/dashboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reproducible-dashboards&#34;&gt;Reproducible dashboards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our apps can integrate your internal financial or transactional data with thousands of external indicators from official statistics to satellite sensory data.  We make sure that your organization always has valid KPIs that are aware of the changes of your working environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Curation</title>
      <link>/faq/curation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/curation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-curation&#34;&gt;Data curation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are reviewing and processing thousands of business and policy indicators from the most various open and confidential data sources, and constantly evaluate their availability, reliability, timeliness, consistency and other properties. During the production of our indicators, we are going back to primary sources, such as standardized survey microdata, accounting or API microdata. We believe that our greatest asset is our detailed map of public and confidential data. We can help designing your own private observatory that find the best value for money indicators for your professional business, policymaking, scientific or journalistic needs. We can usually find better, cheaper or more timely data, and process it for use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Maps</title>
      <link>/faq/data_maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/data_maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The copyright and neighboring right royalty is the wage-like earning of the music performer, the composer and producer. In popular music performers usually play their own composition and sing their own lyrics. If the musician is self-published, all the three royalties directly pay the artist’s work. If a professional publisher is helping the artist as a composer, or a record producer as a recorded performer, they usually share the respective royalty revenues. In emerging markets fewer, in mature markets more composers are represented by publishers and performers by record labels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification-of-industries&#34;&gt;Classification of Industries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of the creative jobs is that they contain a wide range of activities. Economists and government policymakers classify industries with the &lt;em&gt;Nomenclature statistique des activités économiques dans la Communauté européenne&lt;/em&gt;, in short, with the NACE classification in Europe. This classification is largely harmonized on UN level and can be used to compare almost all economies in the world. The NACE classification has its origins in the economic structure of the middle 20th century, and it is more appropriate for the classification of manufacturing and trading activities, such as car manufacturing, or retail sale of cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry is not even recognized by the NACE classification. For example, musicians often perform music (NACE group 90), compose music (NACE group 90), and at the same time do sound recordings (NACE group 58) and teach music (NACE group 85). Many EU member states do not even create government economic statistics for the NACE 90 classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the main reason why music is not well represented in governmental statistics, which is mainly based on tax returns data from ‘clear’ activity groups, such as sound recordings only. Most creative enterprises, and music businesses are no excemptions, do not have a clear economic activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;microenterprises--freelancers&#34;&gt;Microenterprises &amp;amp; Freelancers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry, for various reasons, is not part of the NACE industry, and music industry data must be mapped from different data sources.  A further difficulty is that music industry, similarly to the other creative and cultural industries, mainly works in freelancer networks and microenterprises.  All over Europe, microenterprises are exempted from many statistical reporting, and they are filing simplified tax and financial reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government statistics are largely based on tax returns and other filings of corporate entities with at least 5 employees.  While most manufacturing or trading activities, or licensed service activities such as insurance or banking, are easy to classify, the creative industries are different.  &lt;strong&gt;Because most creative enterprises are smaller than 5 people, they do not file many data for the government or the tax authorities, and they often carry out heterogeneous activities&lt;/strong&gt;.  For example, the music industry is not even recognized by the NACE classification – the live music and compositions can be found in the NACE 90 class, and the sound recordings in the NACE 58 class, and many countries do not even create government economic statistics for the NACE 90 classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;standardized-mapping&#34;&gt;Standardized mapping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID has been mapping data sources for composer, producer and performer royalties, and other data sources since 2014, based on the standard mapping technique developed originally in the United States and later adopted to the EU ^[Hull, Geoffrey P., Thomas W. Hutchison, Richard Strasser, and Geoffrey P. Hull. 2011. &lt;em&gt;The Music Business and Recording Industry Delivering Music in the 21st Century.&lt;/em&gt; New York: Routledge; Leurdijk, Adnra, and Nieuwenhuis Ottilie. 2012. &lt;em&gt;Statistical, Ecosystems and Competitiveness Analysis of the Media and Content Industries. The Music Industry.&lt;/em&gt; 25277 EN. Edited by Jean Paul Simon. Luxembourg: Publications Office of the European Union, 2012: Joint Research Centre Institute for Prospective Technological Studies (IPTS).].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID designed and administered the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest data collection on how musicians work and earn their living.  Over the course of 6 years we collected anonymous data among musicians related to their touring habits, income, costs, recording expenses and income in various channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 100 stakeholders, among them many collective management organizations helped our work.  Some collective management organizations provided us with anonymous payout lists, which was essential to validate the representativeness of our samples.  We reconstructed the density function of actual payouts, and collected data until our anonymous responses showed a very accurately similar shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the music industry all over Europe is mainly made of microenterprise and freelancers, getting an overal picture of the music industry is very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observatories</title>
      <link>/faq/observatories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/observatories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;private observatory&lt;/em&gt; is a data integration system, which automatically collects external information, processes it and professionally joins it with internal data resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;collaborative observatory&lt;/em&gt; is a data integration system that has a map to collaborating institutions’s data resources, and is able to exploit their synergies by automatically combining their data, triggered by an authorization of all involved parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;public observatory&lt;/em&gt; is a collaborative observatory that intends to make at least some of its data assets available as open data. 
ode chunk to prevent printing of the R code that generated the plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our observatories fulfil important functions in data collection, processing, integration, and automated modelling. We provide these services as custom software as service products in the form of 
&lt;a href=&#34;reproducible/apps/&#34;&gt;data applications&lt;/a&gt;.  To design a good observatory that fulfils your business, policy, scientific or journalistic needs, we provide data curating as a consulting service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps</title>
      <link>/faq/apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reproducible-data-retrieval&#34;&gt;Reproducible Data Retrieval&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many consulting companies and think tanks, junior staff is downloading statistical data, reports, and other external information for later use. We believe that this approach is wasteful, error-prone, and creates huge unnecessary workload during the analysis and the supervision of the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysts usually spend at least 80% of their work with data processing steps: pulling information out from spreadsheets and resources, and try to match them. Data arriving even from respectable institutions such as the Eurostat or industry organizations need a lot of adjustment for unit of measure, regional boundary changes, decimal places, and various identifier abbreviations. These steps cannot be reproduced in a file-based, spreadsheet workflow, and they create a major bottleneck in senior staff supervision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our applications put the data from various sources into tidy formats (a statistical definition of well-formatted data that can easily be joined with other data tables), making sure that suitable unit and currency translations took place, the missing values are professionally interpolated, forecasted or backcasted, and the latest data revisions are available.  We provide a one-point entry of well-formatted data for further use in your team&amp;rsquo;s favorite spreadsheet or statistical applications like Excel, OpenOffice, SPSS or Stata.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental &amp; Big Data Sources</title>
      <link>/faq/experimental/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/experimental/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was made out of necessity in EU member states when official statistics are missing key elements of the music or other creative industries.  We had been experimenting with big data sources since 2017, especially to find ways to break down statistics to regional or city level, and to find leading indictors or estimators where government statistics are not available, or available only with a very long time delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://webgate.ec.europa.eu/fpfis/mwikis/essnetbigdata/index.php/Main_Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ESSnet Big Data&lt;/a&gt; is a project within the European statistical system (ESS) jointly undertaken by 28 partners. Its objective is the integration of big data in the regular production of official statistics, through pilots exploring the potential of selected big data sources, and through building and implementing concrete applications. We are closely monitoring such developments, and aim to integrate ESSNet Big Data recommendations into the CEEMID workflow 
&lt;a href=&#34;/publication/creating_better_2015/&#34;&gt;similarly to&lt;/a&gt; earlier ESSnet Culture recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-trends&#34;&gt;Google Trends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Trends creates a fully anonymous sample of Google search traffic. Because of the way Google allows the use of Google Trends and scales results, it is very complicated to use Google Trends across regions and countries.  However, our experience shows that Google Trends is an excellent short-term forecasting tool for ticket sales.  It also means that it can serve as a good estimator for ticket sales for regions and territories where few reliable data sources exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/seasonality_plot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CEE concert seasonality analysis&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geolocational-data&#34;&gt;Geolocational data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3lW8bhQ2fbY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Existing Observatories</title>
      <link>/faq/otherobservatories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/otherobservatories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;existing-observatories---independent-from-us&#34;&gt;Existing observatories - independent from us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observatories are created to permanently collect data, information, and createa  knowledge-base for research and development, science, evidence-based policymaking, usually by Consortia of business, NGO, scientific and public bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aiming to create similar observatories, but we are in no way affiliated or connected to the following, existing observatories that we see as role models. Our mission is to serve similar observatories with research automation, making the observatory&amp;rsquo;s services less costly, more timely with higher level of quality control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-single-market/en/european-digital-media-observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Digital Media Observatory&lt;/a&gt; was launched on 1 June 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eafo.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Alternative Fuels Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is an European Commission funded initiative which provides open and free information, amongst others to support Member States with the implementation of EU Directive 2014/94 on the deployment of alternative fuels infrastructure. The EAFO is maintained by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eafo.eu/knowledge-center/consortium&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EAFO Consortium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.energypoverty.eu/about/about-observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EU Energy Poverty Observatory&lt;/a&gt; (EPOV) is an initiative by the European Commission to help Member States in their efforts to combat energy poverty. It exists to improve the measuring, monitoring and sharing of knowledge and best practice on energy poverty. The EU Energy Poverty Observatory (EPOV) has been developed by a consortium of 13 organisations, including universities, think tanks, and the business sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clustercollaboration.eu/eu-initiatives/european-cluster-observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Observatory for Clusters and Industrial Change&lt;/a&gt; to help Europe&amp;rsquo;s regions and countries in designing better and more evidence-based cluster policies and initiatives. This platform is funded by the EU programme for the Competitiveness of Enterprises and SMEs (COSME).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.euro.who.int/en/about-us/partners/observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Observatory on Health Systems and Policies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.feantsaresearch.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Observatory on Homelessness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://euipo.europa.eu/ohimportal/en/web/observatory/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Observatory on Infringements of Intellectual Property&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clusterobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cluster Observatory&lt;/a&gt; of the Center for Strategy and Competitiveness at the Stockholm School of Economics, which started out originally as the European Cluster Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.obs.coe.int/en/web/observatoire/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Audiovisual Observatory&lt;/a&gt; of the Council of Europe works in a more complicated environment, as it is created by EU member states and non-member states before the EU was born with the Maastricht Treaty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://observatory.culturepartnership.eu/en/page/observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eastern Partnership Cultural Observatory&lt;/a&gt; has an out of EU reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harmonized Surveys</title>
      <link>/faq/surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/surveys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are designing survey questionnaires and create data integration code for harmonized surveys. Harmonized surveys are asking the very same questions, and they can be integrated. Our surveys planned for 2020 in Slovakia for example have comparative data from earlier years in Slovakia, but also from its neighbouring countries and Germany or France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of our survey harmonization software is open source and is under peer-review, it can be found on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eurobarometer.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer.dataobservatory.eu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very technical terms of &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; or retrospective harmonization hide opportunities that can significantly increase the value for money in empirical market research, potentially increasing the value of a high-cost, high-value survey to multiple times of its euro value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can usually compare the basic values, such as concert visiting likelihood in the past – for example, I surveyed Hungary and Slovakia first in 2015, but immediately could compare with 2013 and 2007 data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/gif/concert_hu_animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Harmonized concert visiting questions over time&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We get international benchmarks for free, for example, German, Czech, French data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cee_concert_demography_15x10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Harmonized concert visiting questions accross countries&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the hierarchical nature of our surveys, we can make reasonable estimates of details that we only in one or few countries for the whole EU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value added to our surveys are building on our investment into a reproducible research infrastructure that is able to connect to millions of interview transcriptions programatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are making critical elements of our software open source (for non-commercial use), because we believe that the key elements of reproducibility, particularly replicability and confirmability rely on a full openness about our data processing and data transformations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the  
&lt;a href=&#34;http://retroharmonize.satellitereport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://eurobarometer.danielantal.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://regions.danielantal.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cultural-access-and-participation-surveys&#34;&gt;Cultural Access and Participation surveys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultural Access and Participation Surveys are standardized surveys designed to measure various market-based and non-market based (amateur, liturgical, etc.) cultural activities, including concerts, streaming subscriptions, singing, etc.  They are based on various quantative sociological models and had been standardized by the Eurostat working group 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/assets/eac/culture/library/reports/ess-net-report_en.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ESSNet-Culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEEMID CAP surveys are usually live interviews that allow cross-country comparison, and they are used both for market forecasting, market analytics, royalty and compensation value setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-europe-2013&#34;&gt;CAP Europe 2013&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the data of the CAP 2013 survey for cross-country comparisons and for model calibration, because it includes all EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cee_concert_demography_16x9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Comparative Demography with CAP EU 2013&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-europe-2007&#34;&gt;CAP Europe 2007&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the data of the CAP 2007 survey for understanding cross-country dynamics and long-term changes, because it includes all EU countries. For example, we can determine in which countries visit &lt;code&gt;Generation Z&lt;/code&gt; 20-years-old people more concerts or cinemas than their &lt;code&gt;Generation X&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Generation Y&lt;/code&gt; peers when they were 20-years-old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2019&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2019 survey fieldwork is under way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2018&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2018 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying, the value transfer to YouTube and other media platforms, and the development of the audidence for Hungarian films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2017&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2017 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying. A separate mini-CAP survey was designed to capture the value transfer to YouTube, which was later incorporated into the CAP Hungary 2018-2019 surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-croatia-2017&#34;&gt;CAP Croatia 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Croatia 2017 survey was designed for the creation of the Private Copying in Croatia report, which is prepared for the forthcoming Croatian Copyright legislation changes on private copying and the value gap.  The survey was conducted by Hendall on a sample of 800 respondents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-slovakaia-2015&#34;&gt;CAP Slovakaia 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Slovakia 2015 survey was designed as a part of a larger survey that also incorporated attitudes towards Slovak culture and non-standard survey questions designed by Focus.  The CAP Survey was used to create the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; and to make various legislative impact assessment presentations during the modification of the Slovak Copyright Law on private copying and radio quotas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2015&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2015 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors. It was used in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gvh.hu/sajtoszoba/sajtokozlemenyek/2016_os_sajtokozlemenyek/az_ures_hordozoi_dij_fogasztoi_visszaigenylesenek_.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;competition authority case&lt;/a&gt; related to the Hungarian private copying regime and in a consulting project related to better finding the audience of Hungarian cinemas in their domestic theatrical market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey was conducted by TNS Hoffmann (currently named Kantar Hoffmann.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2014&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2014 was a non-representative, large-sample online survey to pilot the later surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps</title>
      <link>/faq/integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-integration-applications&#34;&gt;Data integration applications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data integration applications automatically collect data from open data, various APIs, industry partners, and our clients internal system. They process them using valid interpolation, forecasting, backcasting, currency translation, unit conversion, imputation, avoiding error-prone, difficult statistical work to put the data in its best form. We make them available in the forms of charts, maps, and simple, easy-to use spreadsheets that adhere to the statistical definition of tidy data, i.e. data that is easy to join in spreadsheet models or in relational databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in ongoing data collection. If you have needed a certain data at least twice in your organization, we believe the best to start recording the information permanently. Instead of acquiring, downloading, buying data when you need it, we offer a better value for automatic collection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Journalism</title>
      <link>/faq/journalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/journalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For data journalism, two cornerstones of reproducible research, namely reviewability by editors and confirmability by other sources are essential requirements.  Our data integration system can produce thousands of reviewable and confirmable facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open data means that there is too much data and information available as business, scientific or journalistic, and we believe that our data sources should have scientific and journalistic corroboration for business uses, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started a discussion with a premier data journalism team to review how our automated data products could fit into their journalistic production workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localization</title>
      <link>/faq/localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/localization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-localization&#34;&gt;Live Localization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/reproducible/reports/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;live reporting technology&lt;/a&gt; is particularly suitable for international localization projects. We make sure that all non-textual elements, such as graphs, charts, bibliographies, footnotes are always updated in all language variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often the presence of high labour-input tables and charts are the barriers to otherwise valuable language localizations. Our technology integrates the text with the data ingestion pipeline, the analysis and visualization and provides a good platform to automate this process, making newsletters, dashboards, interactive visualization open for multi-language use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reports</title>
      <link>/faq/reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/reports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-reports&#34;&gt;Live Reports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our live reports are self-refreshing business or policy reports, regulatory filings, reports to repeating management board committees and other similar uses. They are also very well placed as technical annexes of lengthy, complex policy or consulting documents.  They automatically update all charts, tables, data reference sentences, bibliographical and data citation annexes, making sure that your team always works with the best available data, and that all the documentation and presentation work is under reviewable, reproducible, confirmable and even auditable control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any newsletter, committee review document, regulatory filing that is periodical and is based on many data sources is a good candidate for our live reports. Complex consulting and research documents should be put on a reproducible footing even if they are not repeating, because the process makes documentation and validation fully automatic, saving countless senior oversight hours. Such live documents are very good candidates for re-use in later projects, too. Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;, or the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; are fully automated and can be refreshed any time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data &amp; Re-use Of Public Sector Information</title>
      <link>/faq/psi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/psi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The European governments, and the EU itself, collects information that is worth billions of euros for the commercial and non-governmental sector. While PSI is generally free, or very cheap in the EU, the re-use of these information sources usually requires deep knowledge and further investment, given that these public information sources were never designed for the secondary public or commercial need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satellite Report founder Daniel Antal has been involved in the re-use of public sector information since 2003, when the EU first opened government sources to the business sector on a European level. Satellite Report builds on 17 years of experience with accessing various information sources originally collected by the public sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The re-use of public sector information directive which had been replaced in 2019 with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=1561563110433&amp;amp;uri=CELEX:32019L1024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EU Open Data Directive&lt;/a&gt;, and it allows a very wide access to data with a market value of tens of billions of euros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no free lunch. Using these data sources makes avoids the data collection cost, but processing datasets originally created for governmental or scientific use requires a very significant investment. Our statistica software that helps in this process has been developed over years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are creating thousans of music and audiovisual industry related indicators from raw data collected for other purposes, such as inflation measurement or public policy assessment in the EU using our proprietary software and some open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our economic impact assessment tool is, for example, builds heavily on our 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iotables software&lt;/a&gt; that we released as an open source software within the framework of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ropengov.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rOpenGov&lt;/a&gt; collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Demo Observatories</title>
      <link>/faq/demoobservatories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/demoobservatories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-demo-observatories&#34;&gt;Our demo observatories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our apps can integrate your internal financial or transactional data with thousands of external indicators from official statistics to satellite sensory data.  We make sure that your organization always has valid KPIs that are aware of the changes of your working environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work is historically based on CEEMID, that integrated the data of about 100 music organizations with various other data sources, and created about 2000 statistical indicators for better pricing, advocating for better economic and tax policies, better granting or better marketing of music. CEEMID was constructed from the ad-hoc contributions of users, and was never meant to be public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we are currently bringing out to the ligth in full transparency, with open code and open data several demo observatories for a permanent observation of social and economic data in an automated collection, processing, validation, documentation and publishing workflow. Most of this know-how was developed in CEEMID, but it is not specific to the music industry. We present them as a proof of concept for the best practices of our  research automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A demonstration and proof of concept that a modern, European data observatory can be in large part automated, and adhere to the highest standards of statistical disclosure, reproducible research and open policy analysis (see \ref(opa) 
&lt;a href=&#34;#opa&#34;&gt;Evidence-based, Open Policy Analysis&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;musicdemoobservatoryeu&#34;&gt;music.demoobservatory.eu&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently the website is updated about every day. Each time a refreshment is made, the entire website in  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;html&lt;/a&gt;, the downloadable data catalogue in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/music_observatory.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/music_observatory.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;epub ebook&lt;/a&gt; is re-created with new data tables, latest citation information and visualizations.  Unfortunately, during these daily updates the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; goes blank for a few minutes &amp;mdash; we are working on a solution to avoid this inconvenience and schedule updates for late night hours (in Europe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that a modern data observatory must improve how evidence is created and used in policy reports, and pass on the efficiency gains from increasing reproducibility and automation, therefore we pledge that the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; will comply with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/opa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Policy Analysis&lt;/a&gt; standards developed by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkeley Initiative for Transparency in the Social Sciences&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cega.berkeley.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Effective Global Action&lt;/a&gt;. These standards are applied by the World Bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-development&#34;&gt;In development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our partners we are developing a similar demonstration for the broader cultural, creative and copyright-based industries, which will be revealed until 10 September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are exploring the ideas of future data needs of several industries and policy areas with our partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have an idea? Let us know!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase The Value Of Market Research With Open Data And Survey Harmonization</title>
      <link>/post/2020-07-10-retroharmonize/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-07-10-retroharmonize/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last weeks I have been releasing the early source code of two R packages, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/publication/retorharmonize_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; harmonization infrastructure of surveys, and  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/publication/eurobarometer_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt; for Eurobarometer-specific work, complemented by my earlier release of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/publication/regions_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt;, which tracks about 20,000 regional boundary changes of French departments, Polish voivodeships and Hungarian counties, and other sub-national divisions of about 32 European countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very technical terms of &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; or retrospective harmonization hide opportunities that can significantly increase the value for money in empirical market research, potentially increasing the value of a high-cost, high-value survey to multiple times of its euro value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my work, I have used &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; harmonized questionnaires with EU survey programs, for example, the harmonized CAP surveys to determine the characteristics of concert audiences in a country, or people who download music to their computers.  The EU has been opening up its own survey programs in a piecemeal fashion, and surveys used by the European Commission, the Parliament, or even the national statistical offices are becoming more and more available.  After harmonizing the questions, I can apply &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; harmonization of the results, too, resulting in a far more valuable research document:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can usually compare the basic values, such as concert visiting likelihood in the past – for example, I surveyed Hungary and Slovakia first in 2015, but immediately could compare with 2013 and 2007 data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dataanimation/concert_hu_animation_smooth.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Harmonized concert visiting questions over time&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I get international benchmarks for free, for example, German, Czech, French data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/music/cee_concert_demography_16x9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Harmonized concert visiting questions accross countries&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the hierarchical nature of CAP surveys, I can make reasonable estimates of details that I survey only in one or few countries, such as visiting jazz concerts, and not concert only; or copying non-licensed music to devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is no free lunch here.  I can access millions of euros values of survey data, but nobody will make prepare it for my use. These surveys were processed for different users and different uses and joining them with my data is a very difficult task that I had been doing better and better in the past 5 years. To make this work as error-free as possible, I will publish the critical elements of the code as open source software on CRAN soon - the github release is an early version of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the current momentum is due to a new contributor to these packages, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://martakolczynska.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marta Kołczyńska&lt;/a&gt;, who is an excellent R programmer and a bright academic in international survey harmonization and reproducible research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related&#34;&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eurobarometer.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://regions.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eurobarometer R package</title>
      <link>/publication/eurobarometer_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/eurobarometer_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please review the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eurobarometer.dataobservatory.eu/articles/workflow.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>regions R package</title>
      <link>/publication/regions_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/regions_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install the development version from

&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;rOpenGov/regions&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or the released version from CRAN:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;install.packages(&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://regions.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; currently takes care of 20,000 sub-divisional boundary changes in Europe since 1999. Comparing departments of France in 2013, with 2007 vojvodinas of Poland and 2018 megyék in Hungary? This extremely errorprone work is automated, as a result, you can compare 110-260 regions for far better analysis. regions was downloaded about 600 researchers in the first month after release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can review the complete package documentation on

&lt;a href=&#34;https://regions.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt;. If you find
any problems with the code, please raise an issue on

&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/antaldaniel/regions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. Pull requests are
welcome if you agree with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://contributor-covenant.org/version/2/0/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Contributor Code of
Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use &lt;code&gt;regions&lt;/code&gt; in your work, please 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3825696&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cite the
package&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with sub-national statistics has many benefits. In policymaking or in social sciences, it is a common practice to compare national statistics, which can be hugely misleading. The United States of America, the Federal Republic of Germany, Slovakia and Luxembourg are all countries, but they differ vastly in size and social homogeneity. Comparing Slovakia and Luxembourg to the federal states or even regions within Germany, or the states of Germany and the United States can provide more adequate insights. Statistically, the similarity of the aggregation level and high number of observations can allow more precise control of model parameters and errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages of switching from a national level of the analysis to a
sub-national level comes with a huge price in data processing,
validation and imputation. The package Regions aims to help this
process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This package is an offspring of the

&lt;a href=&#34;http://ropengov.github.io/eurostat/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurostat&lt;/a&gt; package on

&lt;a href=&#34;http://ropengov.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rOpenGov&lt;/a&gt;. It started as a tool to validate and re-code regional Eurostat statistics, but it aims to be a general solution for all sub-national statistics. It will be developed parallel with other rOpenGov packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sub-national-statistics-have-many-challenges&#34;&gt;Sub-national Statistics Have Many Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequent boundary changes&lt;/strong&gt;: as opposed to national boundaries,
the territorial units, typologies are often change, and this makes
the validation and recoding of observation necessary across time.
For example, in the European Union, sub-national typologies change
about every three years and you have to make sure that you compare
the right French region in time, or, if you can make the time-wise
comparison at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hierarchical aggregation and special imputation&lt;/strong&gt;: missingness is
very frequent in sub-national statistics, because they are created
with a serious time-lag compared to national ones, and because they
are often not back-casted after boundary changes. You cannot use
standard imputation algorithms because the observations are not
similarly aggregated or averaged. Often, the information is
seemingly missing, and it is present with an obsolete typology code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;package-functionality&#34;&gt;Package functionality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generic vocabulary translation and joining functions for
geographically coded data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping track of the boundary changes within the European Union
between 1999-2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vocabulary translation and joining functions for standardized
European Union statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vocabulary translation for the &lt;code&gt;ISO-3166-2&lt;/code&gt; based Google data and
the European Union&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imputation functions from higher aggregation hierarchy levels to
lower ones, for example from &lt;code&gt;NUTS1&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;NUTS2&lt;/code&gt; or from &lt;code&gt;ISO-3166-1&lt;/code&gt;
to &lt;code&gt;ISO-3166-2&lt;/code&gt; (impute down)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imputation functions from lower hierarchy levels to higher ones
(impute up)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aggregation function from lower hierarchy levels to higher ones, for
example from NUTS3 to &lt;code&gt;NUTS1&lt;/code&gt; or from &lt;code&gt;ISO-3166-2&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;ISO-3166-1&lt;/code&gt;
(aggregate; under development)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disaggregation functions from higher hierarchy levels to lower ones,
again, for example from &lt;code&gt;NUTS1&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;NUTS2&lt;/code&gt; or from &lt;code&gt;ISO-3166-1&lt;/code&gt; to
&lt;code&gt;ISO-3166-2&lt;/code&gt; (disaggregate; under development)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vignettes--articles&#34;&gt;Vignettes / Articles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://regions.danielantal.eu/articles/Regional_stats.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Working With Regional, Sub-National Statistical
Products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://regions.danielantal.eu/articles/validation.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Validating Your
Typology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://regions.danielantal.eu/articles/recode.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recoding And
Relabelling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://regions.danielantal.eu/articles/google_mobility_report.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Typology Of The Google Mobility Reports
(COVID-19)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback&#34;&gt;Feedback?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raise and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/antaldaniel/eurobarometer/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; on Github or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;. Downloaders from CRAN: 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/package=regions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cranlogs.r-pkg.org/badges/regions&#34; alt=&#34;metacrandownloads&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regionalized Cultural Access and Participation (Books And Libraries) And Science Attitudes Variables</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-22-regional-eurobarometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-04-22-regional-eurobarometer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My new R package, Eurobarometer, helps the creation of data panels and regionalized statistics from the Pan-European survey’s microdata. This allows the creation of many new statistical indicators for the CEEMID Music Observatory and for many market and policy research tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example dataset (Antal 2020) was created from the microdata of the
Eurobarometer 79.2 survey using the development version of the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/antaldaniel/eurobarometer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer R package&lt;/a&gt;.
The dataset can be downloaded from

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3759811&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;. It will be used in a forthcoming academic publication about book piracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-access--participation-variables&#34;&gt;Cultural Access &amp;amp; Participation Variables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The read a book variable is a weighted sum of the responses that chose
from &lt;code&gt;QB1 How many times in the last twelve months have you read a book?&lt;/code&gt; any answer apart from “not in the last 12 months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/book-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Individuals Who Read A Book&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;library-access&#34;&gt;Library Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The library access variable is a weighted sum of the responses that
chose from &lt;code&gt;QB1 How many times in the last twelve months have you visited a public library?&lt;/code&gt; any answer apart from “not in the last 12 months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/library-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Individuals Who Visited A Library&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;limited-library-access&#34;&gt;Limited Library Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limited library access is a weighted sum of the responses that chose from the question block
&lt;code&gt;QB2 And for each of the following activities, please tell me why you haven’t done it or haven’t done it more often in the last 12 months? ... Visited a public library&lt;/code&gt; the answer option &lt;code&gt;Limited or poor quality of this activity in the place where you live.&lt;/code&gt; In this case, the number of respondents is rather low and this is not a very reliable statistic on regional level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Individuals Who Have Poor Local  Library&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;science--technology-attitudes&#34;&gt;Science &amp;amp; Technology Attitudes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supports open access variable is a weighted sum of yes answer
options to the &lt;code&gt;QD 17 Do you think that the results of publicly funded research should be made available online free of charge?&lt;/code&gt;
question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/openaccess-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Individuals Who Have Poor Local  Library&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demography&#34;&gt;Demography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet access question is a weighted sum of responses to the
answer option for &lt;code&gt;D46 Which of the following do you have? - An Internet connection at home&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/internetaccess-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Individuals Who Have Internet Access At Home&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet access question is a weighted sum of responses to the
answer option for &lt;code&gt;D15 What is your current occupation? - student&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/students-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Regional Student Population&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-source--data-processing&#34;&gt;Data Source &amp;amp; Data Processing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source of the data is the microdata file stored in GESIS for the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://dbk.gesis.org/dbksearch/sdesc2.asp?db=e&amp;amp;no=5688&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurobarometer 79.2
survey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data file contains the microdata for the Eurobarometer 79.2 survey (TNS Opinion &amp;amp; Social 2013), which includes a Cultural Access and Participation Survey (see (Haan and Broek 2012; Bína, Vladimir et al.2012)) and a Science &amp;amp; Technology Attitude survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey samples are designed to represent the national population,
with the exceptions of Northern Ireland, the former East- and
West-Germany, and the Turkish community on Cyprus. These samples are
designed to be representative for these populations, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For weighting we used the w1 weights, which allow for
post-stratification based on gender, education level and community size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of the Republic of Cyprus, Estonia, Latvia, Luxembourg and
Malta regionalization is not necessary because the entire countries are equivalent to a single NUTS2 region in terms of size and homogeneity. In these countries the weighting produces representative statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, due to a problem with the original data file, no regional information is available for the Republic of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Germany, Great Britain and Italy, data can be summarized on the level of NUTS1 territories, and we are imputing these values into the constituent (smaller sub-)regions on NUTS2 levels. In the case of the remaining countries it can be summarized on NUTS2 levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the survey samples are designed to be nationally representative, the regional sub-samples are not necessarily representative, and often they are very small. For post stratification purposes, we created a “dirty weighting”, Using the national w1 post-stratification weights, but centered to an average value of 1 for each region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that this causes problems on more detailed answer options (on the level levels of the questionnaire’s question hierarchy.) Except for the science attitudes and the library quality questions, we used relatively simple questions that are less affected by the small,
potentially biased sample size&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A better option would be the creation of new, regional
post-stratification weights. We believe that this would be a very
interesting, but very big research task that would potentially need the cooperation of the survey’s producer, Kantar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: &lt;em&gt;This was originally posted on Daniel&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2020-04-22-regional-eurobarometer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://eurobarometer.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt; became a much more useful and ex post survey harmonization tool after Marta joined the development efforts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel, Antal. 2020. “Regionalized Cultural Access and Participation
(Books And Libraries) And Science Attitudes Variables 2013.” Zenodo.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3759811&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3759811&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bína, Vladimir, Chantepie, Philippe, Deboin, Valérie, Kommel, Kutt,
Kotynek, Josef, and Robin, Philippe. 2012. “ESSnet-CULTURE, European
Statistical System Network on Culture. Final Report.” Edited by Frank,
Guy.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&#34;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haan, Jos de, and Andries van den Broek. 2012. “Nowadays Cultural
Participation - an Update of What to Look for and Where to Look for It.”
In &lt;em&gt;ESSnet-CULTURE, European Statistical System Network on Culture.
Final Report.&lt;/em&gt;, 397–417. Luxembourg.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&#34;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TNS Opinion &amp;amp; Social. 2013. “Cultural Access and Participation. Special Eurobarometer 399 Report.” European Commission.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/public_opinion/archives/ebs/ebs_399_en.pdf&#34;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/public_opinion/archives/ebs/ebs_399_en.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First CEEMID Regional Open Data Release</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internet use: participating in social networks (creating user profile, posting messages or other contributions to facebook, twitter, etc.) [percentage of individuals]&lt;/em&gt; shows the development of social media use in the past 10 years in very high detail.  Social media is one of the most important ways to communicate with fans and find audiences for gigs, performances and to share new releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dataanimation/internet_use_social_networks.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Social media use 2011-2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chosen dataset is highlighting several new priorities of CEEMID.  This indicator, which is based on a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://appsso.eurostat.ec.europa.eu/nui/show.do?dataset=isoc_r_iuse_i&amp;amp;lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurostat statistical product&lt;/a&gt;, has a much higher data quality than the Eurostat release, it is easier to use, and goes beyond the detail of national statistics.  It contains data on 411 territories in Europe, including countries, provinces and smaller regions, even some metropolitan areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset is available on the European open research data repository, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/record/3754574#.XpimX8gzbIU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;. It will be updated annually. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3754574&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/DOI/10.5281/zenodo.3754574.svg&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The processing information is available in the dataset.  First, we have used our open source software to correct the regional boundary changes during the decade (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/2020-02-13-regional_eurostat/&#34;&gt;Programatic Approach To Work With European Regional Data Panels&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When data was missing in the end of the dataset, we used the last observation carry forward, when in the beginning, the next observation carry backwards data.  Gaps in the data were interpolated using linear interpolation. Whenever data was available on a larger (provincial level), we imputed it to the smaller regional units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data contains standard national / regional references according the European NUTS2013 standard for backwards compatibility. Further documentation will be available on our methodology on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;documentation.ceemid.eu&lt;/a&gt; wiki website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last, the data was put into a table that complies with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstatsoft.org/article/view/v059i10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidy data&lt;/a&gt; principles for easier processing on computers and immediate use in spreadsheet applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use this in your article? Further research? Collaboration? Let&amp;rsquo;s get in touch on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or via 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;danielantal.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2011)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_238711_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2015)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_246037_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2019)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_250355_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2011)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_247818_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2015)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_247520_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2019)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_243997_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Social Distancing in Europe</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People around the world are facing newer and newer exponential charts everyday. We’re all hoping for new information about the progress against the coronavirus. Unfortunately, the vast majority of these charts is meaningless. In fact, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/coronavirus-case-counts-are-meaningless/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;coronavirus case counts are meaningless&lt;/a&gt;, unless they are done with very heavy statistical knowledge, and even then they are very messy. Countries have different testing and hospitalization protocols, death certificating standards, and there are less and more trustworthy governments. We do not really know the severity of the local epidemics and the relative success of public health policies.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/countryclusters.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Clustering countries on current lockdown strictness and change&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/countryclusters_huc63f6ee1cc1b69a8e28d2c9e7295fd18_347025_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;338&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/difference_summary_en.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Changes in community space use, end of March and early April&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/difference_summary_en_huc7370673eb468102ac3ad5af70997f54_262570_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/work_home_change_EN.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Growth in time spend at home and in the workplace since January&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/work_home_change_EN_huf1bc5f0534491039237e4dc526b79bf4_336010_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, we have some timely information on how people and the economy react to the epidemic, because there are ongoing, frequent, and comparable data sources on various consequences of the epidemic.  A particularly interesting big data source is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blog.google/technology/health/covid-19-community-mobility-reports/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google’s geolocational reporting&lt;/a&gt; on how people’s time spent in homes, workplaces, parks, shopping areas and recreational areas change. Google gets plenty of realtime data from hundreds of millions of people and compares them by days in the week and local time with the ‘baseline’ scenario before the outbreak of the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the locational data of various smartphones and application data, we know that people spend 10-15% more time at home since January, and 40-50% less in their workplaces.  Similar data is available for other locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/post/2020-04-15-covid/work_home_en_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stay at home or go to the workplace?&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While people are spending less time in the workplace and more at home in every European country, there are significant differences.  Countries in the top left corner, most notable Sweden, switched less from workplaces to homes.  On the bottom right corner, Spain and Italy, which were most hit by the epidemic, are in the most severe form of lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some outliers, like Romania, where people stay a lot more at home, but not so much less in the workplaces – probably they cannot afford to stay clear of the job, but they are reducing other activities.  Or, in the case of Germany, people spend a lot more time in parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/post/2020-04-15-covid/difference_summary_en_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Differences in space use in Europe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grouped the countries according to their dynamics.  Looking at Belgium and Luxembourg, we see that they are more locked down than the typical European country, but they are moving up in the first week of April compared to the last week of March. This is very much in line with their improving strain on the health system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/post/2020-04-15-covid/countryclusters_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Clusters of countries&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is worrying is that there appears to be a significant asynchronicity in the Schengen zone, where people and goods should move around freely.  The peripheric countries, which are less densely populated, often less integrated into the global transport and travel routes, are getting into the local epidemics later, and are acting later.  This is logical from a national point of view, but given that the European economy is very much integrated, it will prolong the pain.  The Netherlands, France and Germany need plenty of seasonal agricultural workers from the Southeast, where the lockdown is just getting really strict.  While some of their regions see improving national epidemic situations, the easing will increase the intensity of the local epidemic if a large number of workers will arrive from countries that are just going into the epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efficient solution, as many public health officials keep saying, would be a synchronized effort to contain the virus.  The different pace and strictness of social distancing measures will mean that the local epidemics will not be in synchronization, and the countries will re-infect each other, this way prolonging the economic and social cost of this devastating pandemic.  While health policy is a national competence in the European Union, in fact, the European economic and social life is so much integrated, not only within the Schengen Zone, but even with future, prospective and candidate members states in the Balkans, that a far more coordinated public health policy would be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use this in your article? Further research? Collaboration? The data &amp;amp; code is available in a private github repo. Let&amp;rsquo;s get in touch on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or via 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;danielantal.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please quote this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel (2020): Comparing Social Distancing in Europe (March, April 2020). figshare. Preprint. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.12124194.v1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.12124194.v1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Social Distancing in Europe</title>
      <link>/post/yes-delft-co-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/yes-delft-co-lab/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;People around the world are facing newer and newer exponential charts everyday. We’re all hoping for new information about the progress against the coronavirus. Unfortunately, the vast majority of these charts is meaningless. In fact, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/coronavirus-case-counts-are-meaningless/&#34;&gt;coronavirus case counts are meaningless&lt;/a&gt;, unless they are done with very heavy statistical knowledge, and even then they are very messy. Countries have different testing and hospitalization protocols, death certificating standards, and there are less and more trustworthy governments. We do not really know the severity of the local epidemics and the relative success of public health policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, we have some timely information on how people and the economy react to the epidemic, because there are ongoing, frequent, and comparable data sources on various consequences of the epidemic. A particularly interesting big data source is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blog.google/technology/health/covid-19-community-mobility-reports/&#34;&gt;Google’s geolocational reporting&lt;/a&gt; on how people’s time spent in homes, workplaces, parks, shopping areas and recreational areas change. Google gets plenty of realtime data from hundreds of millions of people and compares them by days in the week and local time with the ‘baseline’ scenario before the outbreak of the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the locational data of various smartphones and application data, we know that people spend 10-15% more time at home since January, and 40-50% less in their workplaces. Similar data is available for other locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-covid19-europe-geolocations_files/figure-html/workhome-1.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While people are spending less time in the workplace and more at home in every European country, there are significant differences. Countries in the top left corner, most notable Sweden, switched less from workplaces to homes. On the bottom right corner, Spain and Italy, which were most hit by the epidemic, are in the most severe form of lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some outliers, like Romania, where people stay a lot more at home, but not so much less in the workplaces – probably they cannot afford to stay clear of the job, but they are reducing other activities. Or, in the case of Germany, people spend a lot more time in parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;page-break-after: always;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;C:/Users/Daniel%20Antal/OneDrive%20-%20Visegrad%20Investments/2020%20Projektek/covid19/plots/difference_summary_en.jpg&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grouped the countries according to their dynamics. Looking at Belgium and Luxembourg, we see that they are more locked down than the typical European country, but they are moving up in the first week of April compared to the last week of March. This is very much in line with their improving strain on the health system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;C:/Users/Daniel%20Antal/OneDrive%20-%20Visegrad%20Investments/2020%20Projektek/covid19/plots/countryclusters.jpg&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is worrying is that there appears to be a significant asynchronicity in the Schengen zone, where people and goods should move around freely. The peripheric countries, which are less densely populated, often less integrated into the global transport and travel routes, are getting into the local epidemics later, and are acting later. This is logical from a national point of view, but given that the European economy is very much integrated, it will prolong the pain. The Netherlands, France and Germany need plenty of seasonal agricultural workers from the Southeast, where the lockdown is just getting really strict. While some of their regions see improving national epidemic situations, the easing will increase the intensity of the local epidemic if a large number of workers will arrive from countries that are just going into the epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efficient solution, as many public health officials keep saying, would be a synchronized effort to contain the virus. The different pace and strictness of social distancing measures will mean that the local epidemics will not be in synchronization, and the countries will re-infect each other, this way prolonging the economic and social cost of this devastating pandemic. While health policy is a national competence in the European Union, in fact, the European economic and social life is so much integrated, not only within the Schengen Zone, but even with future, prospective and candidate members states in the Balkans, that a far more coordinated public health policy would be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use this in your article? Further research? Collaboration? The data &amp;amp; code is available in a private github repo. Let’s get in touch on LinkedIn, Twitter, or via danielantal.eu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please quote this:
&amp;gt; Antal, Daniel (2020): Comparing Social Distancing in Europe (March, April 2020). figshare. Preprint. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.12124194.v1&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.12124194.v1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible Consulting</title>
      <link>/project/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/consulting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reproducible-consulting&#34;&gt;Reproducible consulting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professionals in advisory positions, such as management consultants, policy consultants and evaluators, grant designers and evaluators, investment advisors or competition law practitioners must adhere to strict ethical guidelines, professional standards and audit by external organizations, regulators and courts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provide professional organizations with reproducible data applications.  These applications make sure that users of our applications can produce their advice and evaluations in a way that is reviewable and reproducible – which is critical to make internal senior oversight efficient &amp;ndash;, and remain confirmable and auditable externally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data analytics applications are reviewable and reproducible, which allows independent assessment and duplication of our results. This is a guarantee of high quality and security:  our apps create data products that remain error-free after validation, and during validation any errors can be safely and quickly corrected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewability means that our application’s results are can be assessed and judged by our user’s experts, or experts they trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reproducibility means that we are providing data products and tools that allow the exact duplication of our results during assessments.  This makes sure that all logical steps can be verified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are creating applications that are confirmable and auditable. These are usually required by the ethical guidelines and professional standards of our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmability&lt;/strong&gt; means that using our applications findings leads to the same professional results as other available software and information. Our data products use the open-source statistical programming language R. We provide details about our algorithms and methodology to confirm our results in SPSS or Stata or sometimes even in Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auditability&lt;/strong&gt; means that our data and software is archived in a way that external auditors can later review, reproduce and confirm our findings.  This is a stricter form of data retention that most organizations apply, because we do not only archive results step-by-step but all computational steps – as if your colleagues would not only save every step in Excel but also their keystrokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documenting CEEMID For Open Data Use</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-24-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 13:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-03-24-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID is a data integration system that could provide to be a model and starting point of building a European Music Observatory based on open data, open-source software using best statistics, data science and AI practices. CEEMID has created thousands of high-value, hard music industry indicators using open data sources, industry data sources, surveys and various APIs to relevant other data sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID is aiming to transfer thousands of indicators and a verifiable, open-source software that creates them to the European Music Observatory to give Europe-wide access timely, reliable, actionable statistics and indicators for the music industry, policymakers and music professionals. (Read more about our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Data_CoverageMain_Page#Data_Coverage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data coverage&lt;/a&gt; and our pan-European 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Main_Page#Geographic_Coverage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;geographical coverage&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of Consolidated Independent, CEEMID created the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/appendix.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report - online, pdf and epub versions 2020&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a rich illustration on European cross-country research to provide the music industry businesses and music policymakers with rich data and  high-quality indicators for analysis and AI for the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Innovation_pillar&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;innovation pillar&lt;/a&gt; of the European Music Observatory by creating input data on the  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Music_Economy_of_Europe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Economy of Europe&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Music_Diversity_and_Circulation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Diversity and Circulation&lt;/a&gt; and on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Music,_Society_and_Citizenship&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music, Society &amp;amp; Citizenship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID is a private initiative. We developed data products for the needs of the industry: to calculate adequate royalty price (tariff) levels, to calculate adequate compensation for damages, to design 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/project/grants/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;better grants&lt;/a&gt;, to advocate 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/tags/cci/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;better CCI policies&lt;/a&gt;, to pinpoint discriminative taxation of the industry, to monitor public performance licenses, to calculate the size of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/tags/value-gap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;value gap&lt;/a&gt;,  to train algorithms that find new audience for small nation repertoires 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/project/music-export/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;abroad&lt;/a&gt;, and so on. Because the industry is made of microenterprises all over Europe and the world, and even larger organizations, such as collective management societies are at most SMEs, the industry has very limited market research or research &amp;amp; development capacities. This puts the music industry in a particularly vulnerable position because the biggest distributors of music, such as Alphabet’s Google and YouTube, or Apple’s iTunes and streaming services, or Spotify are data-driven companies that apply AI in all their workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-open-data&#34;&gt;Why open data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The music industry cannot get more favourable position in disputes if it is not able to ramp up its data analytics capacities. This is only possible in a collaborative way, because the combined research capacity of the European industry is smaller than its main partner’s capacities individually.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that CEEMID could fulfil the functions of the European Music Industry if it would find a sustainable financing that makes access to all our data open. We need to be able to avoid the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tragedy_of_the_commons&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tragedy of the commons&lt;/a&gt;, where only a few industry users contribute to the financing of thousands of indicators that could potentially benefits tens of thousands of stakeholders in the EU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that a very large segment of CEEMID&amp;rsquo;s and the European Music Observatory&amp;rsquo;s data coverage is based on public-interest data that is collected by public authorities.  We have also realized that the music industry stakeholders and policymakers, particularly in cultural ministries and similar functions in cities and regions underestimate the availability of open data.  The EU open data regime gives access to almost all information stored in government data systems. Because this is in fact re-use of the information, the data for this purpose is usually not documented. While the data is available for free or almost free, only high level of metadata and data processing know-how is required to access it. This know-how is usually missing from cultural policy institutions and music industry bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, CEEMID was based on the regulatory framework provided by the Directive on open data and the re-use of public sector information provides a common legal framework for a European market for government-held data (public sector information). It a regulatory framework that is built around two key pillars of the internal market: transparency and fair competition.  In our view, &lt;em&gt;these principles should apply to European Music Observatory, too&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the EU, open data is governed by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=1561563110433&amp;amp;uri=CELEX:32019L1024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Directive on open data and the re-use of public sector information - in short: Open Data Directive (EU) 2019/1024&lt;/a&gt;. It entered into force on 16 July 2019. It replaces the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/ALL/?uri=CELEX:32003L0098&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Public Sector Information Directive&lt;/a&gt;, also known as the ‘PSI Directive’ which dated from 2003 and was subsequently amended in 2013^[@eu_directive_2019_1024; @eu_directive_2013_37; @eu_directive_2003_98]. The founder of CEEMID, Daniel Antal has been involved in Open Data and PSI since 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-open-collaboration-in-data-integration&#34;&gt;Why open collaboration in data integration?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We believe that the European Music Observatory must rely on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Open-source_software&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;open-source statistical software&lt;/a&gt; written in the R statistical language like CEEMID, and it must be funded on the principle of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Open_collaboration&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;open collaboration&lt;/a&gt; with the industry, public authorities and academia&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open-source software (OSS) is a type of computer software in which source code is released under a license in which the copyright holder grants users the rights to study, change, and distribute the software to anyone and for any purpose. Open-source software is often developed in a collaborative public manner, and which is a prominent example of &lt;strong&gt;open collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, the use of open source software, including the open source R language and its software packages or libraries in the national statistical offices are encouraged by four important considerations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lower cost, 2. security, 3. no vendor &amp;lsquo;lock in&amp;rsquo; and 4. &lt;strong&gt;better quality&lt;/strong&gt;.  We believe that the number of data scientists in the music domain is so few that only an open collaboration can guarantee adequate data quality. (In our CEEMID documentation you find more information about the [R language](&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=R_(programming_language)&#34;&gt;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=R_(programming_language)&lt;/a&gt; and the concept of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Open-source_software&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;open-source software&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the European Music Observatory must rely on open-source statistical software written in the R statistical language like CEEMID, and it must be funded on the principle of open collaboration with the industry, public authorities and academia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID uses the open source statistical programming language R, and various open source R programs.  CEEMID also releases some of its customary program code developed to create its indicators. This allows an open collaboration with statisticians working in national statistics authorities and in independent research institutions in the EU and globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of open source software and the open source R statistical language allows a continuous peer-review of data ingestion, processing, corrections and indicator creation by statisticians, data scientists and academics.  Statistical products of national statistical offices, sometimes Eurostat itself, not to mention data providers that are not part of the system of national statistical offices, such as the European Audiovisual Observatory, are plagued with data errors that are corrected and amended relatively slowly. We believe that unless the &lt;em&gt;European Music Observatory&lt;/em&gt; becomes part of Eurostat (a highly unlikely organizational scenario), it &lt;em&gt;should embrace the priniciples of open collaboration in creating its indicators&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID has been releasing some of its data processing, integration and indicator creation code on an open-source license on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/doc/FAQ/R-FAQ.html#What-is-CRAN_003f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Comprehensive R Archive Network&lt;/a&gt;, or CRAN, is a collection of sites which carry identical material, consisting of the R distribution(s), the contributed extensions, documentation for R, and binaries. (More information in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Comprehensive_R_Archive_Network&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;our&lt;/a&gt; documentation.) &lt;em&gt;We would like to find funding to release thousands of reproducible data sets and the reproduction code from source to end result on an open data, open collaboration basis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-economic-impact-assessment-code&#34;&gt;Our economic impact assessment code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iotables&lt;/a&gt; package programmatically creates gross-value added, employment, taxation effect and multiplier indicators from real national accounts data for all EU countries by providing a data processing and modelling software to implement the use cases of the 

&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/documents/3859598/5902113/KS-RA-07-013-EN.PDF/b0b3d71e-3930-4442-94be-70b36cea9b39?version=1.0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurostat Manual of Supply, Use and Input-Output Tables&lt;/a&gt;. It was released on 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ropengov.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rOpenGov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The package was originally designed for the economic impact assessment of film production in Hungary and for the Slovak music industry. (See 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;related&lt;/a&gt; publication.) With the help of this package, we can, for example, calculate the effect of 1 million euro crisis relief package on the GDP, employment and future tax receipts between car manufacturing, banking, the music industry and book publishing in &lt;em&gt;all EU countries&lt;/em&gt;. By releasing our software code, we could compare test results on calculating economic impact indicators for the creative industries and other industries with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/articles/united_kingdom_2010.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UK statistical office&lt;/a&gt;. We want to release more and more of CEEMID&amp;rsquo;s software code, so that professional statisticians can validate that they work perfectly or suggest improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;creating-regional-indicators&#34;&gt;Creating regional indicators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second major open-source release makes it possible to create regional statistical time series and data panels from Eurostat&amp;rsquo;s regional data - not only for the creative industries, although our original aim was to support scientific research into book piracy in a project with IVIR at the University of Amsterdam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While national borders do not change frequently, the borders of more than 1000 European NUTS1, NUTS2 and NUTS3 regions change on average every three years.  The change of regional boundaries makes time-wise comparison very difficult.  Because the current statistical regulations to do not make it compulsory that member states re-cast their historical data after a boundary change, Eurostat does not contain, for example, comparable data on French or Lithuanian or Hungarian regions in the previous decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID&amp;rsquo;s program code does exactly this, because it traces, and whenever possible, corrects boundary changes back till 2007.  We released this very complicated program code as part of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ropengov.github.io/eurostat/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurostat&lt;/a&gt; R package within the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ropengov.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rOpenGov&lt;/a&gt; initiative.  This program package has tens of thousands of users in research institutions, industry and in the national statistical offices themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released the program code, because it requires special geostatistical knowledge, and we believe it is such a critical application that only open peer-review can guarantee its flawless and error-free work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-the-centre-of-europe-to-the-european-music-observatory&#34;&gt;From the Centre of Europe to the European Music Observatory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically CEEMID started out as the &lt;em&gt;Central and Eastern European Music Industry Databases&lt;/em&gt; out of necessity following a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceemid.eu/post/2013-11-18_cisac_goodgov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CISAC Good Governance Seminar for European Societies&lt;/a&gt; in 2013. The adoption of European single market and copyright rules, and the increased activity of competition authority and regulators required a more structured approach to set collective royalty and compensations tariffs in a region that was regarded traditionally as data-poor with lower quantity of industry and government data sources available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014 three societies, Artisjus, HDS and SOZA realized that need to make further efforts to modernize the way they measure their own economic impact, the economic value of their licenses to remain competitive in advocating the interests vis-?-vis domestic governments, international organizations like CISAC and GESAC and the European Union. They signed a Memorandum of Understanding with their consultant to set up the CEEMID databases and to harmonize their efforts. The decentralized, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Main_Page#Data_integration&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data integration&lt;/a&gt; strategy chosen by CEEMID however allowed a quick expansion of CEEMID to be a Pan-European data resource.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes!Delft Co-Lab</title>
      <link>/post/yes-delft-co-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/yes-delft-co-lab/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I have been searching around for a good incubation program for the transition of the data, software and of course people in the loose CEEMID network into a real company, and I was fascinated by the professionalism and unique viewpoint of Yes!Delft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I view on CEEMID as a professional success that brought together dozens of small entities with the help of dozens of dedicated people from the content side. But CEEMID is financially hardly viable and needs a new business model and a new organizational approach to sustain itself and grow. CEEMID started as a cooperation project, not as an institution, but now, as the biggest music &amp;amp; creative sector data project in Europe, and most likely, in the world, it acquired enough know-how and data to institutionalize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/events/colab-nov15/&#34;&gt;intro&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“Research over the past 4 decades has shown that startups that are co-founded by a team are more successful. In the Co-Lab workshop, as a single founder, founding team, or entrepreneurial minded person, you’ll get the tools and connections to find that new member of your dream team to help you reach the top!”&lt;/em&gt; (See the entire &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/CO-LAB-GUIDE.pdf&#34;&gt;Co-Lab Guide on their website&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID made its biggest growth in 2019, it got in touch with dozens of new partners in a series of new countries from Austria to Armenia, but its reorganization into a startup was a debacle. Our research product was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/&#34;&gt;big international success&lt;/a&gt;, but the continuation is far from certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Co-Lab gave me very important insight into why. For me, the most important lesson was that it is not the team member who has the most desired or important technical skills who may be the best co-founder to make a successful organization, but the one who will best complement myself and other co-founders. Skills can be bought on the job market once the business model is validated and the revenues are coming. To get there, you need co-founders with a strong dedication, diverse educational and cultural background, and complementing psychological traits to overcome the difficulties of the first period, where the business model is not yet validated and there is no money coming in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reporting</title>
      <link>/project/reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;strong&gt;reproducible reports&lt;/strong&gt; are automated, self-refreshing documents, that contain data pipelines to the original data sources, the analytical code and the narrative assessment in a single file.  These reports are saving potentally thousands of error-prone human working during the compilation of very complex technical documentations, such as regulatory filings or complex research documentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because they are retrieving the latest available data from the Client&amp;rsquo;s internal systems and from external data sources, they can be re-freshed daily, weekly, monthly or annually. The program is refreshing the data visualizatoin, the data tables, the data citations and bibliography, and they re-create the statistical and descriptive technical annexes at every compilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages-of-reproducible-reporting&#34;&gt;Advantages of reproducible reporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reproducible report allows independent assessment and duplication of the programmatic results. This is a guarantee of high quality and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviewability&lt;/strong&gt; means that our application’s results are can be assessed and judged by our user’s experts, or experts they trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducibility&lt;/strong&gt; means that we are providing data products and tools that allow the exact duplication of our results during assessments.  This makes sure that all logical steps can be verified. Reproducibility ensures that there is no lock-in to our applications. You can always chose a different data and software vendor, or compare our results with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are creating applications that are confirmable and auditable. These are usually required by the ethical guidelines and professional standards of our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmability&lt;/strong&gt; means that using our applications findings leads to the same professional results as other available software and information. Our data products use the open-source statistical programming language R. We provide details about our algorithms and methodology to confirm our results in SPSS or Stata or sometimes even in Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auditability&lt;/strong&gt; means that our data and software is archived in a way that external auditors can later review, reproduce and confirm our findings.  This is a &lt;em&gt;stricter form of data retention&lt;/em&gt; that most organizations apply, because we do not only archive results step-by-step but all computational steps – as if your colleagues would not only save every step in Excel but also their keystrokes. While auditability is a requirement in accounting, but we are extending this approach to all the quantiative work of a professional organization in an advisory or consulting capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because our data applications are confirmable and auditable, they are the best suited to meet the internal or external regulatory compliance of organizations, for example, reporting to external regulators or supervisory boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;internationalization-and-localization&#34;&gt;Internationalization And Localization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the tables, visualizations, citations and repeating technical documentations are created programatically, they are ideally suited for multi-language environments. Our reproducible research reports are capable of creating a master (English or generic) report and the skeletons of translations with translated and well-placed, translated illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; is based on our data collection in 12 countries. Every visualization and data cited in the report is programatically created, and can be refreshed or translated automatically. It was 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;presented&lt;/a&gt; as a good case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Open Data</title>
      <link>/project/open_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/open_data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Europe, municipalities, state authorities, governments, and the EU itself are creating vast data assets to serve various public needs.  Since 2003 the EU and its members states have theoretically opened these vast data resources for the re-use of the market sector when there are no privacy or national security concerns present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right after the opening of these data assets, it was estimated that the value of re-used public sector data, for example geographical, company registry, court, transport infrastructure data is around 25-47 billion euros. In the last 15 years, there have been signficant new investments into data assets, and futher innovation on using data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, the re-usable public data offers a consistent and cheap alternative to private data collection, for example, pan-European surveying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages-of-psi&#34;&gt;Advantages of PSI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are vast data assets available for marginal cost, or for free, in size and value that could not be profitably financed by the private sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-use of taxpayer funded research increases the value for tax money, and avoids unnecessary duplication of data investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not possible to collect past data in the present. Public sources, however, often contain hidden data going back for 10-20 years or even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;difficulties-of-psi&#34;&gt;Difficulties of PSI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-usable data was created for a different purpose. While the data may be of high quality, it is likely not to be processed in the form the re-user wants to see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is often not documented, or not documented for the purpose of re-use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is often difficult to find.  It is technically re-usable, but even its existence is unknown for most business users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The direct data costs of PSI are usually low - users only have to pay marginal costs, or sometimes they are not charged for a fair use of the data. However, the data processing costs are significant, because the data was not prepared for the business users needs.  The data processing requires a special understanding of statistical standards and public data. This is one of our specialities - besides having a very detailed &amp;lsquo;treasure map&amp;rsquo; of European PSI.  We are creating thousands of high-quality, pan-European business and policy indicators from open data sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legal-background&#34;&gt;Legal Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the EU, open data is governed by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=1561563110433&amp;amp;uri=CELEX:32019L1024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Directive on open data and the re-use of public sector information - in short: Open Data Directive (EU) 2019/1024&lt;/a&gt;. It entered into force on 16 July 2019. It replaces the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/ALL/?uri=CELEX:32003L0098&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Public Sector Information Directive&lt;/a&gt;, also known as the ‘PSI Directive’ which dated from 2003 and was subsequently amended in 2013. The founder of CEEMID, Daniel Antal has been involved in Open Data and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_psi_2009/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PSI since 2008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp; The Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativeflip.creativehubs.net/2019/12/03/flipping-the-odds/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference&lt;/a&gt; – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel&amp;rsquo;s presentation was focused around the question on invisibility of the CCI sector in the economic, education and labour policymaking, and the low level of data use in fact-based cultural policy design, and the following policy design problems. Our CEE Music Industry Report 2020 created with the help and support of Consolidated Independent was used as a use case for the problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post is an edited version of Daniel&amp;rsquo;s presentation and the subsequent panel discussion with the stakeholders and organizers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEE Report builds on the results of the first 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://czdev.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Czech&lt;/a&gt; music industry reports are compared with Armenian, Austrian, Bulgarian, Lithuanian, Serbian and Slovenian data and findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/publications/cee_report_2020_frontcover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;invisibility&#34;&gt;Invisibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measurement problems and the ‘invisibility’ of creative and cultural industries is a consequence of the fact that these industries are predominantly comprised of microenterprises and individual, freelancing entrepreneurs.  Even larger entities, such as collective management organizations can be classified as small enterprises.
In the EU, small- and medium enterprises, and especially microenterprises usually have reduced reporting duties to the statistical authorities and tax authorities (which is the most important secondary source of government statistics in anonymized, aggregated form.)  This means that the supply side is not visible for policymakers. The recommendation is to conduct sample-based surveys among these microenterprises, but very few member states do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem is that on the demand side, not all member states create statistics.  ESSNet-Culture created recommendations how to measure cultural access and participation, which is a broader term than cultural consumption, as it includes non-market forms, for example, liturgical music, amateur acting, and so on.  The European Commission sometimes makes excellent, but not detailed 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/usecase/cap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CAP surveys&lt;/a&gt;, which are the most important sources of Eurostat’s relevant pan-European statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID has been making such surveys, both on the supply side (in music and film) and in the audience side (in music, film, theatre, opera, and artistic activities) in several member states, and has plenty of experience with using the EU-mandated CAP surveys of 2007 and 2013. The CEE report relies on the latter date set in first part of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/audience.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;audience analysis&lt;/a&gt;. Our work was already presented in 2015 as a best use case in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/creating_better_2015/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Creating better national cultural statistics with Eurobarometer datasets and ESSNet-Culture technical recommendations&lt;/a&gt; at GESIS, which maintains the Eurobarometer archives, on the Eurobarometer Symposium 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gesis.org/fileadmin/upload/events/EB-Symposium/Announcement_EB_Symposium.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Four Decades of Surveying Europe –
Perspectives on Academic Research with the European Commission’s Eurobarometer Surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the EU the lowest hanging fruit would be to critically assess the past surveys, including the partial CAP survey made in 2017 for the cultural heritage part of culture, and the national surveys conducted by CEEMID and its partners, and to mandate an annual or biannual CAP survey within the Eurobarometer series, probably as a specially sampled “Special Eurobarometer”.  This would very significantly reduce the costs compared to a country-to-country basis, and probably could be shared by other institutions, for example, with the European Audiovisual Observatory.  This alone would greatly increase the demand / consumption side information on the services of creative and cultural enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the panel discussion Consolidated Independent highlighted the problem of leaving sample-based statistics making to the industry itself, which leads to myopical incentives to create ‘policy-based evidence’ that is cherry picked by industry trade associations to fit their often not very well thought out policy agenda.  In our view, the most important role of a future European Music Observatory would be to set standards to data collection and integration.  The music industry is  one of the most data-rich industries globally, but the publicly available, verified, trustworthy information is scarce both for policy-making and for business planning among microenterprises who have know specialized research know-how. Our already existing, representative 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://survey2019.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;national surveys&lt;/a&gt; should and could be extended to the whole Europe with the quality control and visibility offered by such an Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;industry-organization&#34;&gt;Industry organization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very significant challenge with evidence-based policymaking, or, in fact, with any policy making is that the extremely fragmented nature of the industry makes national and EU-level consultations very difficult.  Most of the workforce is neither a classical employer nor employee but works as a freelancer or a micro-entrepreneur. Their views are very rarely represented by trade unions or employee associations or chambers of commerce. Despite all efforts on EU level to make the social dialogue more representative for atypical and flexible work forms, the problems and the views of the creative and cultural sectors are largely unrepresented in policy debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prime example of this problem is the very heavy over-taxation of the music industry that we have shown in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt; national music industry reports, and in other documents in Croatia.  The problem is not only characteristic for the music industry, but generally all CCIs because they share similar economic properties: no real chance to use tax breaks, high level of labour input and high level of value added.  While policy makers and granting authorities spend much time on trying to improve the financing of this sector, in fact, reducing over-taxation would make a much more imminent impact on the liquidity, profitability and growth opportunities of the sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in the making of economic and tax policies, the fragmented creative and cultural industries hardly can represent their special situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;policy-issues&#34;&gt;Policy issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from taxation issues, which significantly reduce the liquidity, profitability and growth opportunities of these sectors in many EU countries, particularly in the CEE, where corporate taxes are low but value-added taxes are high, there are other important policy problem that reduce the long-term growth capacity of the sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very small enterprise size leads to missing strategic human resources (HR) and research and development (R&amp;amp;D) functions in almost all enterprises – including simple market research activities.  Companies with 1-2 employees do not have specialized management and support functions, and thus they have a very strong handicap in HR and R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of this problem is the motion picture and TV industry.  These industries were comprised of medium-sized enterprises in the 1980s with significant in-house education functions. The current structure of these industries, however, resembles music, with almost all enterprises staying below the 5-person threshold.  In our experience, based on development needs assessments in the Hungarian motion picture and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://czdev.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Czech music industry&lt;/a&gt;, this creates an acute skills and labor shortage.  Missing skills cannot be well replaced by recruitment, or with strategic HR development via life-long learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to very reduced opportunities to participate in, and create life-long learning schemes, there are very little chances to engage in market research and R&amp;amp;D.  While the music industry, for example, is one of the most data-driven industries in the world, the microenterprise size does not allow that these enterprises commission market research or hire data scientists. This leads to very asymmetrical relationships with the main distributors of music and media content on platforms that are owned by global data companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations&#34;&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel made a few concrete recommendations in the panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating the European Music Observatory, and the creation of similar industry initiatives, and commissioning collaborative (multi-stakeholder) market research, as CEEMID works in many countries, can only replace the missing market research function in the extremely fragmented industries, such as motion picture production, the music industry, but to a certain degree architecture and design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A low-hanging fruit would be a critical assessment of the previous Pan-European CAP surveys and the comparable national CAP surveys conducted by CEEMID and its partners following the ESSNet Culture recommendations and the inclusion of the CAP surveys in an annual or bi-annual form in the Eurobarometer (Special) series. A Special Eurobarometer may be more suitable because usually a non-proportional weighting of the sample gives the best value for money in these surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critically reviewing the participation of micro-enterprises in the current forms of social dialogue and looking for formal or informal ways to increase participation in policy making can gradually lead to more creative-friendly economic regulation and tax policies.  The Hungarian Music Industry Report 2015 and the Slovak Music Industry Report 2019 contains very interesting case studies for this problem that we briefly summarize in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEE Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critically reviewing the few examples from mainly Nordic member states where collective agreements and other collaborative institutions allow microenterprises and freelancers to participate in life-long learning problems can help designing policies that will gradually reduce the huge skill gap of the CCIs in management know-how, data know-how, or renew their technical skills necessary in the production of their services and content. Our work with the Hungarian National Film Fund and surveys among more than a thousand film makers can give much insight into this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-links&#34;&gt;Further links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research findings were earlier presented and discussed in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Vienna&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prague&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-11-18-bush/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Budapest&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/slovak_report19/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bratislava&lt;/a&gt; with stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow Creative FLIP project on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/creativeflip_eu?lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020</title>
      <link>/publication/ceereport_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ceereport_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativeflip.creativehubs.net/2019/12/03/flipping-the-odds/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference&lt;/a&gt; – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEE Report builds on the results of the first 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://czdev.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Czech&lt;/a&gt; music industry reports are compared with Armenian, Austrian, Bulgarian, Lithuanian, Serbian and Slovenian data and findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research findings were earlier presented and discussed in Vienna, Prague, Budapest and Bratislava with stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the earlier presentations in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;#posts&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; section of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Central European Music Industry Report is the result of a co-operation that started among stakeholders in three EU countries five years ago to measure the economic value added of music – the basis of a modern royalty pricing system. This gave birth to CEEMID, originally the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Databases, a data integration programme that now in 2020, covers all of Europe. CEEMID fulfils similar roles to the planned European Music Observatory and supports all pillars of the future pan-European system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comparison of Western and Eastern music audiences reveals key demographic differences that make the unchanged adoption of business practices from mature markets in the region questionable. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/audience.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt; of this report will show these differences and their consequences on music markets, in terms of visiting and acquisition likelihood, frequency, seasonality and purchasing capacity. This is an example of how CEEMID fulfils the role of Pillar 3 (music, society and citizenship) in the planned European Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/supply.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt; contrasts market demand with the supply strategies of musicians. CEEMID has been surveying music professionals, including artists, technicians and managers about their working conditions, market conditions and plans for five years across a growing number of countries. In 2019 we invited 100 national and regional stakeholders to distribute our surveys. In some countries, our surveys already have several years of historic data, making the resulting musician database probably the largest ever source of data about how music is produced and how musicians live. We are constantly looking for partners to roll out this survey to new countries in new languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEE region has comparative advantages in big music events like festivals, and it has become one of the most important hubs for cultural tourism in the world. We explain this phenomenon in Chapter 4 by showing the differences in demand composition, demography and supply of venues in the second chapter. The lack of a modern and dense network of permanent music venues gave rise to magnificent music festivals in the CEE. Open’er, Sziget and Exit are among the biggest and best festivals in the world, closely followed by several smaller festivals in all countries. The share of festivals in the live music market is many times higher than in Western Europe and they provide vital export revenues to the local music economies. However, they play a limited role in finding new audiences for local artists, as they are increasingly programming for Western audiences by providing shows of international hits. They can only very partially fill in the gaps left by the small venue problem that hit the emerging markets harder than the UK or Australia, where policy action had been already taken to reverse the decline of the availability of smaller live music venues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the recording side, our analysis shows that modern digital services are growing at a faster rate than in mature markets. Because of lower repertoire competition, streaming quantities are similar for a typical Austrian, Czech, Hungarian, Polish or Slovak track than in the mature markets. However, revenue growth is limited because of the interplay of several analysed factors. Our analysis of the live and recorded music markets shows that CEEMID fulfils the roles of the Pillar 1 (music economy) of the planned European Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recorded music sales revenue in the region comes from streaming platforms, just like in the mature markets. Successful sales strategies require a solid knowledge of the global marketplace and the ability to understand and train sales algorithms. Micro-enterprises, such as independent labels, have very limited ability to cope with these functions, given that they do not have market research or R&amp;amp;D functions. CEEMID and Consolidated Independent have started initiating open, national R&amp;amp;D consortia to create the necessary concentration in data assets, analytical capacity and budgets to close this gap. As a first step, CEEMID and Consolidated Independent have created a large, independent music dataset based on hundreds of millions of royalty statement entries to create our market indexes, styled after stock market and bond market indexes. Streaming opportunities are fast changing as roll-out of streaming services is happening at a different rate in various territories; subscription charges and the exchange rate to the producer’s currency vary and repertoire competition emerges in the market. Our volume and revenue indexes in 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/export.html#recexport&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chapter 5.3&lt;/a&gt; are aimed at creating sales algorithms that optimize sales volumes and expected revenues. We believe that this analysis also reveals that CEEMID partially fulfils the roles of Pillar 2 (music diversity and circulation) and feeds important data into Pillar 4 (innovation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The region has far bigger untapped potential than most music business executives believe. Households in the region spend a significantly lower share of their recreational budget on music than their Western, Southern or Nordic peers. The region has a lot of untapped cultural purchasing power because servicing is particularly challenging in both the live and recorded sides of the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This upside potential cannot be tapped without better pricing. Royalty levels are often very low in the region. Due to many combined effects analysed in this short report, the gap between royalties earned in the CEE and Western Europe is several times bigger than the difference in GDP or national average wage. These gaps are partly caused by special interests preventing collective management from charging appropriate tariffs for restaurants, media companies or electronic appliance importers and manufacturers, and partly by unfavourable taxation of cultural products and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was designed to create economic evidence on royalty pricing, private copying compensation and the creation of economic value added in the industry. In the first Hungarian Music Industry Report of ProArt and in the first Slovak Music Industry Report we have shown that economic and taxation policies of the CEE countries aimed to support car and electronics manufacturing create a distorted, unfavourable economic regime for creative industries. We want to help local stakeholders with economic evidence to correct these discriminatory policies during the overhaul of the EU VAT system. We have been helping various national organizations with economic evidence, presented in the light of latest EU jurisprudence, to improve their pricing activities. Our thousands of indicators were also used in ex ante evaluations of granting schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, all EU member states will change their copyright administration legislation because of the national implementations of the 2019/790 Digital Single Market directive. CEEMID provides evidence in several countries about the size and impact mechanism of the value transfer, and generally the widespread use of the copyright exemption for private copying. We believe that the thousands of pan-European music industry indicators that we have aggregated over the five years will play a vital role in these regulatory processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID fulfils its roles with a very thorough exploitation of the EU’s 17-years-old Open Data regime with the re-use of public sector information, and a very careful mapping of the music industry. These maps help us conduct annual surveys among musicians and the audience, and they help us connect (always with pre-approval and with a user mandate) to industry databases. We do not only cover the EU countries, but increasingly (potential) candidate countries and neighbourhood countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our vision, this data collection and integration, i.e. Pillars 1-3 should be available for all music stakeholders, should remain public and publicly funded. The last Pillar of the observatory, innovation, is where private entities should compete. The founders of CEEMID and Consolidated Independent believe that this report demonstrates the business and policy benefits of such a system with the analysis of the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European music markets. We believe that this way CEEMID is in a position to serve most of the planned functions of the envisioned European Music Observatory, and we are looking for ways to make either our thousands of indicators, or our data collection and integration software open source and available for all stakeholders in the EU and its neighbours. CEEMID was born out of necessity to level out the different levels of public research and statistical coverage of the EU member states. In our view, private entities in the future should focus their investments in Pillar 4 of the planned observatory, i.e. competing in innovation with creating new models, algorithms and services based on data that is available throughout the European Union without giving further advantage to the already mature markets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surveys</title>
      <link>/project/music_observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/music_observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most important technical guideline on cultural statistics is the &lt;em&gt;Final Report of the Woking Group European Statistical System Network on Culture&lt;/em&gt; (in short: ESSnet-Culture) [@frank_guy_essnet-culture_2012].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESSnet-Culture gave a thorough overview of cultural data sources, guidelines on standardizing data, and a technical definition of the domain, including an exact mapping of cultural and creative activities and occupations to statistical nomenclatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;icet&#34;&gt;ICET model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultural participation extends beyond the market-oriented forms of &amp;ldquo;cultural consumption&amp;rdquo; and include non-market forms, such as private copying or liturgical events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ESSnet-Culture working group endorsed the ICET model of quantifying cultural participation.   The aim of the ICET model is to create representative surveys, but it is a very good framework to join survey data with other data sources.  For example, the music industry and the audiovisual sector usually has extensive transaction data on most market-oriented activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Information&lt;/em&gt;: to seek, collect and spread information on culture;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communication and community&lt;/em&gt;: to interact with others on cultural issues and to participate in cultural networks;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoyment and expression&lt;/em&gt;: to enjoy exhibitions, art performances and other forms of cultural expression, to practice the arts for leisure, and to create online content;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transaction&lt;/em&gt;: to buy art and to buy or reserve tickets for shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The generic questionnaire was developed by Jos de Haan and Andries van den Broek at the Netherlands Institute for Social Research, originally for extending cultural participation surveys to digital forms of culture [@de_haan_virtuele_2008; @de_haan_nowadays_2012]. This methodology was endorsed by ESSnet-Culture, and a rather detailed guideline can be found in the report of the &lt;em&gt;Task Force on Cultural Practices And Social Aspects Of Culture&lt;/em&gt;, in the ESSNet-Culture technical report (in general: pp. 236-242, survey methodology and harmonization pp. 242-255, recommendations: pp. 273-274; with examples on how to use the question hierarchy on pp. 397-417.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;target-population&#34;&gt;Target Population&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the target population is representative members of the general public, such as in the case of audience surveys, we use 
&lt;a href=&#34;#cap&#34;&gt;CAP&lt;/a&gt; surveys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the target population is a professional or microenterprise group, such as performing artists or record labels, we use our 
&lt;a href=&#34;#professional&#34;&gt;Professional group surveys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap&#34;&gt;CAP surveys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESSnet-Culture has reviewed several pan-European CAP manifestations, and based on the recommendations, further CAP surveys were carried out in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2001: Europeans&amp;rsquo; Participation in Cultural Activities (2001)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEE CAP 2003:  Candidate Countries Eurobarometer 2003.1 New Europeans and Culture, all later EU member states of the EU27, except for Croatia, but including Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2006:  Within the EU-SILC Module 2006 On Social Participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2007:  Includes the EU27 + United Kingdom but not Croatia, Romania and Bulgaria, conducted within Eurobarometer European Cultural Values (2007)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2013: Includes the EU27 + Croatia (only few weeks before the country&amp;rsquo;s accession.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2015: Within the EU-SILC Module 2015 On Social/Cultural Participation And Material Deprivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on these guidelines and examples, we have carried out several in-depth music and audiovisual domain oriented CAP surveys:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2014: a large, but non-representative online sample to test the methodology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2015:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slovakia CAP 2015:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Croatia CAP 2017:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2017:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slovakia CAP 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;professional&#34;&gt;Professional Group Surveys&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Observatory</title>
      <link>/project/observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;observatory&lt;/strong&gt; is a location used for observing terrestrial or celestial events. The European Commission and the Council of Europe are supporting numerous data observatories to support research and development and evidence-based policymaking. We are creating automated observatories following the best practices of reproducible research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satellite Report grew out of a such an observatory, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-start-a-data-observatory&#34;&gt;How To Start A Data Observatory?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;private observatory&lt;/strong&gt; is a data integration system, which automatically collects external information, processes it and professionally joins it with internal data resources. We offer this to 
&lt;a href=&#34;#business&#34;&gt;business&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;#science&#34;&gt;scientific research&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ngo&#34;&gt;think tank and NGO&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;#journalism&#34;&gt;journalism&lt;/a&gt; partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;collaborative observatory&lt;/strong&gt; is a data integration system that has a map to collaborating institutions’s data resources, and is able to exploit their synergies by automatically combining their data, triggered by an authorization of all involved parties. We offer this to Consortia of various entities. Daniel&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/project/ceemid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID project&lt;/a&gt; developed since 2014 is a good example of a collaborative observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;public observatory&lt;/strong&gt; is a collaborative observatory that intends to make at least some of its data assets available as open data. ode chunk to prevent printing of the R code that generated the plot. We offer this for the European Union and its Consortia. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.satellitereport.com/index.php?title=Observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;See some observatories »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our observatories fulfil important functions in data collection, processing, integration, and automated modelling. We provide these services as custom software as service products in the form of data applications. To design a good observatory that fulfils your business, policy, scientific or journalistic needs, we provide data curating as a consulting service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few public observatories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eafo.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Alternative Fuels Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is an European Commission funded initiative which provides open and free information, amongst others to support Member States with the implementation of EU Directive 2014/94 on the deployment of alternative fuels infrastructure. The EAFO is maintained by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eafo.eu/knowledge-center/consortium&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EAFO Consortium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.energypoverty.eu/about/about-observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EU Energy Poverty Observatory&lt;/a&gt; (EPOV) is an initiative by the European Commission to help Member States in their efforts to combat energy poverty. It exists to improve the measuring, monitoring and sharing of knowledge and best practice on energy poverty, and it is developed by a consortium of universities, think tanks, and the business sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clustercollaboration.eu/eu-initiatives/european-cluster-observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Observatory for Clusters and Industrial Change&lt;/a&gt; to help Europe&amp;rsquo;s regions and countries in designing better and more evidence-based cluster policies and initiatives. This platform is funded by the EU programme for
the Competitiveness of Enterprises and SMEs (COSME).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clusterobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cluster Observatory&lt;/a&gt; of the Center for Strategy and Competitiveness at the Stockholm School of Economics, which started out originally as the European Cluster Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reproducible-research&#34;&gt;Reproducible research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that a modern data observatory should be as much reproducible and automated as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Following reproducible research principles leads to higher data quality, especially if it is based on open-source code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reproducible data can be automatically documented, which makes teamwork, collaboration and instant use far more efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reproducible research products offer far more efficient supervision and audit.  Quality control is cheaper and easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-open-data-open-collaboration&#34;&gt;Open source, open data, open collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the EU, open data is governed by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=1561563110433&amp;amp;uri=CELEX:32019L1024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Directive on open data and the re-use of public sector information - in short: Open Data Directive (EU) 2019 / 1024&lt;/a&gt;. It entered into force on 16 July 2019. It replaces the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/ALL/?uri=CELEX:32003L0098&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Public Sector Information Directive&lt;/a&gt;, also known as the ‘PSI Directive’ which dated from 2003 and was subsequently amended in 2013. The public sector offers tens of billions&amp;rsquo; euro worth data &amp;mdash; but without a free lunch.  While the data is available free or at marginal cost, it is processed to the needs of public authorities, public services, and require special know-how to be put to a secondary business or research use. Our founder, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/author/daniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt;, has been involved in Open Data and PSI since 2003. Our expertise guarrantee that in the field of economics, finance, social sciences, and most policy areas your observatory starts with hundreds, or even thousands of re-used public sector indicators, often with a decade-long or even longer history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the open source 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=R_%28programming_language%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;statistical programming language R&lt;/a&gt;, and various open source R programs.  We also release some of our mission-critical code developed to create business and policy indicators &amp;mdash; see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/publication/eurobarometer_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/publication/iotables_2018/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iotables&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/publication/regions_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://retroharmonize.satellitereport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt;. Our important code goes through anonymous peer-review, and open for external review, audit. For example, this allowed us to compare test results on calculating economic impact indicators for the creative industries and other industries with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/articles/united_kingdom_2010.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UK statistical office&lt;/a&gt;. You can even modify our code &amp;ndash; you just cannot copyright and close it for commercial use. In our view, this guarrantees the highest quality, but it also gives assurrances of transparency and makes vendor lock-in impossible. While developing these packages requires our special knowledge, their rich and peer-reviwedd documentation makes sure that you can always find a team member, or hire a data analyst who can work with them without us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of open source software and the open source R statistical language allows a continuous peer-review of data ingestion, processing, corrections and indicator creation by statisticians, data scientists and academics.  Statistical products of national statistical offices, sometimes Eurostat itself, not to mention data providers that are not part of the system of national statistical offices, such as the European Audiovisual Observatory, are plagued with data errors that are corrected and amended relatively slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-integration-instead-of-centralisation&#34;&gt;Data integration instead of centralisation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our observatories by design are flexible and decentralized. Our continuous 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Main_Page#Data_Integration&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data integration&lt;/a&gt; allows to join and publish any data the observatory and its member have access to, and have rights and intentions to share or publish. We only keep metadata, i.e. a &amp;lsquo;data map&amp;rsquo; to make sure that whatever the Observatory&amp;rsquo;s members want to share or publish is always automatically available for processing and publication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iotables R package</title>
      <link>/publication/iotables_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/iotables_2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://iotables.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iotables&lt;/a&gt; processes all the symmetric input-output tables of the EU member states, and calculates direct, indirect and induced effects, multipliers for GVA, employment, taxation. These are important inputs into policy evaluation, business forecasting, or granting/development indicator design. iotables is used by about 800 experts around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Add your privacy policy here and set &lt;code&gt;draft: false&lt;/code&gt; to publish it. Otherwise, delete this file if you don&amp;rsquo;t need it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms</title>
      <link>/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Add your terms here and set &lt;code&gt;draft: false&lt;/code&gt; to publish it. Otherwise, delete this file if you don&amp;rsquo;t need it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
