<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>/tag/books/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>books</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 11:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>books</title>
      <link>/tag/books/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feasibility Study On Promoting Slovak Music In Slovakia &amp; Abroad</title>
      <link>/publication/listen_local_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/listen_local_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/publications/Listen_Local_Feasibility%20study_2020_SK.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;direct download&lt;/a&gt; in Slovak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/publications/Listen_Local_Feasibility%20study_2020_EN.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;direct download&lt;/a&gt; in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, realizing the low visibility and income-generating potential of Slovak music, the legislation introduced an amendment to the broadcasting act to regulate local content in radiostreams. The Slovak content promoting policy was well-intended but not based on any impact assessment, and it reached its goal only partially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Slovak broadcasting quotas in comparison with other national quotas a very simple, and they are impossible to measure, which makes both compliance and enforcement very difficult. Radio editors do not get any help to find music that fits into the playlists and fulfil the quota obligations – in many cases, it is impossible for them to find out if a song actually meets the quota requirements. For the same reason, neither is enforcement possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another deficiency of the broadcasting quotas is that because of its fuzzy target, it is not clear whom it tries to help, and it has few friends. It is unclear how performers, composers or Slovak music producers can benefit from the system. Furthermore, it only helps a few genres, and it decreases the chances of other Slovak music in instrumental and non-Slovak language genres (for example, classical, jazz, rock) to be heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And at last, radio is losing its importance in music discovery. New generation find the music during their music discovery age on YouTube and digital streaming platforms. A Slovak content promoting policy that does not work on digital streaming platforms will be obsolete when radio content providers will switch to digital streaming in the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Feasibility Study follows the following logic:&lt;/strong&gt;
In the first chapter we introduce various music recommendation systems in the context of local content promotion polices, like local mandatory content quota regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second chapter, we consider the market-based or creative industry economy supporting policy goals, measurements, and potential support given to artists and producers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then turn in the third chapter to content-based local regulations promoting the use of the Slovak language or Slovak music content, irrespective of the performers and producers nationality, residence or ethnicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce the idea of the &lt;strong&gt;Slovak Music Database&lt;/strong&gt;, a comprehensive, mainly opt-in, opt-out database that of Slovak artists and Slovak music that should be supported by the local content regulation and other policies. We also create a Demo Slovak Music Database to understand the problem and scope of the creation of the comprehensive version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project website contains the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/project/demo-sk-music-db/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Slovak Music Database&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also created a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/project/demo-app/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Recommendation System&lt;/a&gt;. We explain here 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/post/2020-11-23-alternative-recommendations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;why&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##Research questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are the total market shares of Slovak music relatively low both on the domestic and the foreign markets?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can we measure the market share of the Slovak music in the domestic and foreign markets?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can we measure the value gap between what some media platforms, most particularly the biggest YouTube, does not pay out to the Slovak stakeholders within Slovakia?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the interplay of the various definitions on market share and national quota targets?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How ‘shadow-markets’ of home copying and unlicensed media platforms, such as YouTube impact market shares directly and national quotas indirectly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can modern data science, predictive microeconomics and statistics help increase the market share of Slovak music in Slovakia and abroad?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the entire Reprex team who contributed to the English version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Emily H. Clarke, musicology
Stef Koenis, musicologist, musician
Dr. Andrés Garcia Molina, data scientist, musicologist, editor
Kátya Nagy, music journalist, research assistant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the Slovak version:
Dominika Semaňáková, musicologist, editor
Dáša Bulíková, musician, translator&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring the Visibility and Accessibility of European Creative Content on the World Market: The Need for Copyright Data Improvement in the Light of New Technologies</title>
      <link>/publication/european_visibilitiy_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/european_visibilitiy_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please give us ideas, comments to our pre-print manuscript, which is available on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3785272&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SSRN&lt;/a&gt; our for &lt;a href=&#34;/media/publications/SSRN-id3785272.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;direct download&lt;/a&gt; here on Data &amp;amp; Lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the European Strategy for Data, the European Commission highlighted the EU’s ambition to acquire a leading role in the data economy. At the same time, the Commission conceded that the EU would have to increase its pools of quality data available for use and re-use. In the creative industries, this need for enhanced data quality and interoperability is particularly strong. Without data improvement, unprecedented opportunities for monetising the wide variety of EU creative and making this content available for new technologies, such as artificial intelligence training systems, will most probably be lost. The problem has a worldwide dimension. While the US have already taken steps to provide an integrated data space for music as of 1 January 2021, the EU is facing major obstacles not only in the field of music but also in other creative industry sectors. Weighing costs and benefits, there can be little doubt that new data improvement initiatives and sufficient investment in a better copyright data infrastructure should play a central role in EU copyright policy. A trade-off between data harmonisation and interoperability on the one hand, and transparency and accountability of content recommender systems on the other, could pave the way for successful new initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can scholarly pirate libraries bridge the knowledge access gap? An empirical study on the structural conditions of book piracy in global and European academia</title>
      <link>/publication/scholarly_pirate_libraries_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/scholarly_pirate_libraries_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PLOS One&lt;/a&gt; is the fourth most influential multidisciplinary journal after Nature, and Science, and Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America (based on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scimagojr.com/journalrank.php?category=1000&amp;amp;area=1000&amp;amp;order=h&amp;amp;ord=desc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;H index&lt;/a&gt;.) On December 3, 2020 it published 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0242509&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt; co-authored by Dr. Balazs Bodo, associate professor at the Institute for Information Law (IViR), Daniel Antal (Reprex, Demo Music Observatory), a data scientist interested in reproducible research, as an independent researcher, and Zoltan Puha, a Data Science PhD at Tilburg University, JADS. PLOS (Public Library of Science) is a nonprofit Open Access publisher, empowering researchers to accelerate progress in science and medicine by leading a transformation in research communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article utilizes the our reproducible datasets created with our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://regions.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; package, and builds on many years of expertise in empirical research on the field of music and audiovisual piracy, home copying and private copying compensation (see for example 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Private Copying in Croatia&lt;/a&gt;.)  Our aim is to provide reliable, high quality indicators for the creative industries not only on national, but provincial, state, regional and metropolitan area level, too, because these levels are often more relevant for creators, performers and policy-makers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topic of the paper is Library Genesis (LG), the biggest piratical scholarly library on the internet, which provides copyright infringing access to more than 2.5 million scientific monographs, edited volumes, and textbooks. The paper uses advanced statistical methods to explain why researchers around the globe use copyright infringing knowledge resources. The analysis is based on a huge usage dataset from LG, as well as data from the World Bank, Eurostat, and Eurobarometer, to identify the role of macroeconomic factors, such as R&amp;amp;D and higher education spending, GDP, researcher density in scholarly copyright infringing activities.&lt;/p&gt;















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-created-a-global-and-a-far-more-detailed-european-model-for-pirate-book-downloads&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;journal.pone.0242509.g002.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;We created a global and a far more detailed European model for pirate book downloads.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;journal.pone.0242509.g002.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We created a global and a far more detailed European model for pirate book downloads.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main finding of the paper is that open access, even if it is radical, is not a panacea. The hypothesis of the research was that researchers in low-income regions use piratical open knowledge resources relatively more to compensate for the limitations of their legal access infrastructures. The authors found evidence to the contrary. Researchers in high income countries and European regions with access to high quality knowledge infrastructures, and high levels of funding use radical open access resources more intensively than researchers in lower income countries and regions, with less resourceful libraries. This means that while open knowledge is an important resource to close the knowledge gap between centrum and periphery, equality in access does not translate into equality in use. Structural knowledge inequalities are both present and are being reproduced in the context of open access resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper is unique not just because of the data it is based on. It also sets new standards in interdisciplinary legal research by publishing the paper, the data and the software code in the same time in open access repositories, following reproducible research best practices &amp;mdash; the practices that we want to promote in our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; and further data observatories to serve business, evidence-based policy and scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
