<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Antal, CFA | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/author/daniel-antal-cfa/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/author/daniel-antal-cfa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 08:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/author/daniel-antal-cfa/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inquiry Into The Live Music Industry In Wales</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-06-welsh-covid-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-06-welsh-covid-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In July 2020, Professor Paul Carr of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://staff.southwales.ac.uk/users/381-pcarr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;University of South Wales&lt;/a&gt; was commissioned by 
&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Senedd Cymru – the Welsh Parliament&lt;/a&gt; to create a report examining the ‘&lt;em&gt;state of play&lt;/em&gt;’ in the post Covid-19 music industries in Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;WATCH: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pcarr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@pcarr&lt;/a&gt; came to give evidence to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SeneddCWLC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@SeneddCWLC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; for our inquiry into Live Music Industry in Wales 🎵 &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/GtrYPOg8iW&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/GtrYPOg8iW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Senedd CWLC (@SeneddCWLC) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SeneddCWLC/status/1185216516201111555?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;October 18, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SeneddCWLC/status/1185216516201111555?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click through&lt;/a&gt; to see a short interview with Prof. Paul Carr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industries in Wales consist of both part-time and full-time stakeholders and  although dominated by live and recording sectors, also comprise of other sub-sectors, and like in other countries that we surveyed in Central and Eastern Europe, many stakeholders in the music industries are freelancers, following 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/supply.html#creators-of-music&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;multi-track careers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prof. Carr&amp;rsquo;s report is particularly interesting for our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; project because the Welsh nation is a part of a larger entity, the United Kingdom, and many important statistical products may need to be recreated for this sub-national level &amp;mdash; something we have been doing with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;our survey retroharmonization&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://regions.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regional statistical tools&lt;/a&gt; for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Welsh Music Industries in a Post-Covid World&lt;/em&gt; will be presented to the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://senedd.wales/en/bus-home/committees/Pages/Committee-Profile.aspx?cid=445&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Culture, Welsh Language and Communications Committee&lt;/a&gt; later this month, and we will publish the entire report in English and start a discussion around it, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Racist Music Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We want big data algorithms to work for small venues, undiscovered bands, and all artists coming from diverse walks of life. We often find that big data works against them, and our Listen Local Initiative was designed to change this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big data algorithms will increase injustice and breach social norms if they are trained on improper data, or the algorithms are biased &amp;ndash; this is why we place so much emphasis on algorithm transparency and input data transparency. Facebook, Apple or Spotify are often criticized for helping the spread of hate, for example.  But how can an algorithm turn racist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Kraemer &amp;amp; Steve Holden reported on BBC recently that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/newsbeat-54613907&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spotify, Apple Music, Deezer and YouTube found recently hosting racist music&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; and they removed it after the BBC’s investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Spotify, public playlists and &amp;ldquo;suggested artists&amp;rdquo; did make it easier to find extreme content: In some cases, users created playlists that collated songs and bands associated with the National Socialist Black Metal (NSBM) movement, mainly from Eastern Europe and Russia. Anti-Semitism and glorification of the Holocaust was commonn in their lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can an algorithm become racist?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is trained on the tastes and habits of “white people”, it will less likely recommend “black music.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a music is coming from a “black” community, it will probably not recommend it in the “white community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the algorithm learns that taste of racists people, it will provide them with more racist material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can replace &lt;code&gt;black&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;white&lt;/code&gt; with any &lt;code&gt;minority&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;majority&lt;/code&gt; group.  Take &lt;code&gt;Slovak&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;American&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;major release&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;independent release&lt;/code&gt;. European independent music makers may feel a minority compared to international majors.  The problem with algorithms is that they can ruthlessly reinforce injustice, because they just learn how to do something better, faster, and more than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fight for the removal of inappropriate content from the &lt;em&gt;training set&lt;/em&gt;. If you see any non-English hateful songs on these platforms, let us know, because English-language moderation is just the tip of the iceberg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the training sets of the algorithms behind sales or listening recommendations are inclusive. Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local Initative&lt;/a&gt; is an early beta of a recommendation system that makes sure that locally relevant music gets recommended to locally relevant audiences, and does not need to go into an uneven fight with giants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the external verification of the algorithm and its results. We will allow multiple levels of audit for all our algorithms, and we make all critical elements of our data products open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few examples that the tides are turning:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justin Joffe: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://observer.com/2017/02/capitalism-has-suppressed-black-musicians&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Capitalism Has Long Suppressed the Contributions of Black Musicians&lt;/a&gt;  2017/02/02&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Sisaro: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/01/arts/music/music-industry-black-lives-matter.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Music Industry Is Wrestling With Race. Here’s What It Has Promised&lt;/a&gt; 2020/07/01&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kali187/29537032568/in/photolist-M161Jd-Fb3bBZ-2hL9Zw2-oHvory-oHvRMx-oZY9Gw-oZZXBz-oHvMod-oZZXzR-oHvMrj-oHvo5w-7a1jrw-HmVzFz-W45Mq3-GMhHU5-26MJg25-29hg18w-vv7kap-24mAJA5-2dRDUMa-8Hk58E-7UskvS-akZE6J-E6kKTp-2V2uSq-2gsHaES-2gsGZ1K-2gsH2Ct-2gsGZre-2gsHdvw-2gsHg6G-2gsHfpX-2gsH2ok-2gsHcrY-2gsHd3c-2gsHdnf-2gsGXKt-2gsGVJV-2gsGW3R-2gsHe7S-2gsHgAK-2gsGWvu-2gsGXmx-2gsGVCc-yUw5E2-2gsGYPx-2gsGZSe-818JBs-FBqXev-gYrUWa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Janusz Kaliszczak&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duka’s Mission: Collaborate With Musicians From Every Country On Earth</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cologne-based musician and film producer, 
Damir Bašić aka Duka decided to try to collaborate with recording artists from all over the world in his new project.  Originally from Sarajevo, Bosnia-Herzegovina, he finished last year putting their former band’s songs into a 40-minute feature film 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OvJ0NlAFjCQ&amp;amp;t=1715s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Delta wave (2019) with English subtitles&lt;/a&gt; and started to look for a new music film challenge.  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjcWWrl-DEnNg-qOxRZfRSg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Propeler&lt;/a&gt;, with one Bosnian ‘l’, had to move on with a new drummer, and Duka wanted to find himself a new music project in his new town, Cologne, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is now making a series of songs, where he is the author of all music and lyrics, but he is inviting recording artists from all over the word to make recorded audio and video performances. He gives much freedom to the performing artists to interpret his songs the way they like, and he dreams that one day, when the pandemia is gone, he will be able to perform the entire set live. These songs are released on all platforms that Distroid covers under the name Duka Base (see for example Spotify 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/album/1YX2VxJe0ecWwVvvdY19Jg?si=KbObLWXgR4yCKY0ZBd7DGg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/36cf6MBy60g&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=36cf6MBy60g&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Duka Base - Watch Me (feat. Amina Kamran)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duka was initially struggling with the same problem as we do in Data &amp;amp; Lyrics when we try to explain our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; projects. “It was hard at the beginning to convince artists to take a part in the show, because it was hard to describe the whole idea. After the first show, everything went better, because the artist could see exactly what I wanted from them. Now, the response is way better of course.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then it started to go smoothly. “All those artists have had their own home studios, and it went quick and well. But it&amp;rsquo;s a bit harder to record the video, because all the artists with whom I worked are musicians, and not filmmakers. All in all, I am very happy with the willingness of the artists to do it as best they can, and at the end, I am happy with the outcome. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting for me how I talked with everyone the same way I would talk with someone in Cologne. The core of producing something is the same, or at least very similar no matter where you live.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FI2KoWkeR3M&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FI2KoWkeR3M&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#3 DMM Podcast Show / PAKISTAN / Amina Kamran / &amp;ldquo;Watch Me&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of the global ambition, Duka does not make a living from creating music. He has a dayjob as a motion designer at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.denkwerk.com/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Denkwerk&lt;/a&gt;, which is not connected to his musician career. He just moved to Cologne in 2018, so he is not yet integrated in the scene of the German town while he continues to follow the Sarajevo scene as much he can &amp;mdash; though, of course, his musician friends are as much stranded as anybody else in Europe in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/1YX2VxJe0ecWwVvvdY19Jg&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Did We Start The Demo Music Observatory?</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-27-why-start-music-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-27-why-start-music-observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was contacted during the consultation period of the Feasibility Study of the European Music Observatory. That led to an uneasy series of conversations with the consultants of this project, and a very enlightening series of conversations with European civil servants, music industry organizations, music managers and artists.  My main pitch was that every single assumption of this project is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They started from the assumption that there is hardly any data available on the European music scene &amp;ndash; whereas we found while building up CEEMID, errr, a pan-European music data observatory, is that music is one of the most data-driven industries in the world, it is choking in numbers, and the reason why this data is not visible is very different. They were talking about lack of data in fields where we already had about 2000 pan-European indicators ready. (See 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/presentation/ceemid-observatory.html#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Introducing the CEEMID Observatory, 9/28/2019&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;large self-contained html file, takes time to load into browser&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;big-data-creates-injustice&#34;&gt;Big data creates injustice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry is scattered: it has the author’s or publishing side, the recording side, a large live music business and usually a very environment for classical (art) music. Within these segments there are hundreds of organizations in each EU country, and each have their own small or large datasets. The music industry has plenty of data, but it is not integrated, and it is often hidden from organizations that may have a conflicting agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-27-why-start-music-observatory/three_income_streams_croatia.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fragmentation: Three income streams in Croatia&#34; title=&#34;Fragmentation: Three income streams in Croatia&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fragmentation of data makes these players easy prey in the era of big data. Companies who monopolise big datasets first and create 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/roots-of-unity/review-weapons-of-math-destruction/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;weapons of math destruction&lt;/a&gt; in the forms of algorithms that work for them, can take an unusually large share of the money created throughout the value chain. Proprietary, uncontrolled, big data trained algorithms reinforce inequality &amp;mdash; this makes Google’s YouTube, Spotify, but also Netflix in films or Amazon in books so powerful against its competitors, but also against competition regulators or suppliers &amp;mdash; in this case songwriters, video producers, filmmakers, book publishers and authors.  If their algorithm works against a creator, the creator is doomed, because half of the global sales are driven by secret algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;big-data-vs-small-datasets-research-automation&#34;&gt;Big Data vs Small Datasets, Research Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem of the music industry is not too little, but too much data. Music is drowning in numbers, and it has too little resources to turn much data into valuable information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our concept of the European Music Observatory is to pool enough resources to create value for rightsholders, talent managers, venues, festivals and the entire music ecosystem. Most music organization employ 1-5 people, and even the largest national organization, like collective management organizations, fall under the EU definition of &lt;em&gt;small- and medium sized enterprises&lt;/em&gt;. They do not have data scientists, market researchers, forecasters.  They are small organizations with small research budgets and very little time for researching. Nevertheless, with more than 60 partners in 12 countries we have shown that this is possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we turned 700 million royalty statements into meaningful indicators about 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/market.html#recmarket&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the price and volume growth&lt;/a&gt; in 20 European streaming markets;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;calculated the value gap and the value of private copying in Hungary and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatia&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;helped closing the royalty gap in Hungary and Slovakia by helping collective management to significantly increase their royalty collection;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;digital_gap_2018.jpg&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; alt=&#34;Difference between potential market (household cultural spending) and actual digital music revenues&#34; title=&#34;Closing the royalty gap in Europe&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;helped granting agencies to make more relevant 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/grants/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;grant calls&lt;/a&gt; and designed indicators to measure the impact of their grants;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;started the creation of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;local recommendation engines&lt;/a&gt; that help the circulation of the small nation repertoires or city scenes in Europe or beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-has-data-but-you-need-a-map&#34;&gt;Music Has Data, But You Need A Map&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scattered industries tend to be riddled with conflicts of interests.  While working with royalty collection management societies in the last 7 years I often saw that songwriters, producers and performers are often fighting each other for slices of the pie that is just too small. That means that national members of CISAC (GESAC in Europe), IFPI, and AEPO-ARTIS often do not share data with each other, although their income is below any legally acceptable threshold. They have individually very rich datasets that in many jurisdictions just never meet. Labels, small publishers are so little organizations that they do not have a data scientist, let alone a dedicated IT person, or even an HR professional to hire the services of data scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were able to collect at least 70% of the information content of the planned European Music Observatory, and far more, than most of the 50 data observatories we examined in Europe, because we took an approach inspired in open source software development: continuous opt-in, opt-out data integration, focusing on the synergies that partners can achieve, instead of aiming at endless discussions and compromises on sharing data. We never take away proprietary data from anybody, we just connect data among partners, and enrich it with open data. We would like to guide the industry from hierarchical database planning to the philosophy of open collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;automated&lt;/a&gt; most of the research tasks, to make it less costly, less error-prone, and require less labour input.  We can automate most of the data collection, data processing, imputation, validation, documentation, reporting, even some modelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invested into harvesting the vast 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/project/open_data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;open data&lt;/a&gt; of the European Union and its member states.  In the EU, most taxpayer funded research data is freely available, but at a cost of significant data reprocessing cost. If the data was originally collected to calculate to inflation or monitor tax revenues, it needs to be significantly altered for the music industry to be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have found a way to connect many small data sources and open data. We can create big data from much small data, and deploy analytics, algorithms on collective datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgetify: Popular Music That Nobody Listens To</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you work on recommendation engines, particularly recommendation engines that are different from the ones developed by large media or streaming platforms, you do not want to consider goals and directions that you follow, but also the road where you do not want to end up at all. For me, Forgetify has always been a puzzling and wonderful application, because it shows purely where your artists do not want to end up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forgotify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful application that is “recommending” you songs that have never been played on Spotify.  Music from artists that has not been played by their fans, their friends or foes, brothers and sisters, children and grandchildren! I use recommendations in quotation marks, because their recommendations are usually based on your taste. Forgetify just picks you a song that has not been played on Spotify ever. (Never been played means that somebody may have started it, but very soon stopped playing the song.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What connects me to Forgetify particularly is their motto: “We love music.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can learn from their website, there are millions of Spotify songs that have been played only partially or never at all. And that is exactly the opposite that our partners want to achieve when they work with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to create several playlists with Forgetify.  All I did is that I took their “recommendation” and put it on a list, then hit next.  I skipped tracks that were not licensed to the Netherlands, or which were not music tracks but spoken words, for example sound recordings of stand-up comedies. Then I put these tracks on three lists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;something that I felt was appropriate called &lt;code&gt;classical music&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;another that is &lt;code&gt;popular music&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and another which is a mix of historical recordings, and other music which I think has such a special audience that it would not make a good mix with the other two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3Gs4kJzmFiMNMfPAuhmC6P&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eightsome Reel Pt 1&lt;/a&gt; by the &lt;em&gt;Bob Smith&amp;rsquo;s Ideal Band&lt;/em&gt; is a digitalized re-release of the LP re-release of 78&#39;&#39; records from the 1930s, and it is obviosuly no competitor for a modern classical or pop music track. Even the labels &lt;code&gt;popular music&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;classical music&lt;/code&gt; would call for further explanation, but we&amp;rsquo;ll get there another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s see what we have after removing historical, traditional folk, spoken word and classical music tracks in the supposedly &lt;code&gt;popular music&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ldquo;recommendations&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/1kxZfYZBsDSdWhMVXQMCss&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to the use of the the word “recommendations”, the expression of “popular music” is a bit ironic here, because we are talking about music that is anything but popular, at least not on Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First let&amp;rsquo;s make a very short 
&lt;a href=&#34;#comparison&#34;&gt;comparison&lt;/a&gt; of the current global hits, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a subjective list&lt;/a&gt; that I created for this month and started to use for explaining our recommendations, my &lt;em&gt;Forgetify Pop October 2020&lt;/em&gt; list.  I will follow these songs in the coming years, and will keep adding new forgotten songs to my list. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll reflect on why these songs are 
&lt;a href=&#34;#forgotten&#34;&gt;forgotten&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparison&#34;&gt;A Quick Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next comparison uses some musicology and sound engineering
“features” of the songs on the three lists. These characteristics
are themselves recognized by algorithms, and they are used for Spotify’s own recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_comparison_forgetify.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything is clear from these boxplots is that there is nothing clear about forgotten songs. The boxplot&amp;rsquo;s box show the typical values of popularity or other features, and the line starting from the box still relatively frequent values.  The long boxes of the Forgetify Pop list show that there are all sorts of music on Forgetify: screechy and not, danceable and not, cheerful and sad. My subjective list is shorter and more pronounced: it contains songs that I found to be a good match to listen together.  The current global hits are less similar than my personal selection, but far more homogeneous than all those millions of songs that end up in the forgotten long tail of the catalogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;forgetify_october_features.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the only thing that connects this playlist is that the songs are not classical or world/folk music, and that they are forgotten. The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/62y0aOSPRK1rL7lo780cgH&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This Time&lt;/a&gt; single from 2009 by the Intonated (3 listeners this month, including myself) is heavy guitar music. It is dark. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/album/6cCHMZdMkfhpebJ0s6rRNR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Perdido&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;em&gt;Candido Featuring Al Cohn&lt;/em&gt; album released in 1956 by the 
Cándido Camero (6945 monthly listeners) is a cheerful jazz song. It is likely that this song actually has an audience, but not on Spotify. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C%C3%A1ndido_Camero&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cándido&lt;/a&gt; was born as Candido de Guerra Camero in 1921 in Havana, and with his 99 years he is one of the oldest living artists on Spotify. He recorded this album almost 40 years before the internet was opened for the public. For his life long achievement in Afro-Cuban jazz he received the National Endowment for the Arts Jazz Masters Award in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal favorite from the Forgetify Pop list is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/21nQDfg5BMxp7vGARpOBmo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Groovy &amp;amp; Linda&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;em&gt;Neon Princess&lt;/em&gt; album released in 1968 by Tom Parrott (39 monthly listeners). It is a nice hippy song with the favorite effect of &amp;lsquo;68, the inclusion of a sitar.  The song is not very good, the sitar and the guitar make a rather chaotic mix, but Tom Parrott (born in 1944, Washington DC, United States) is not forgotten because he was bad. There are many songs on Forgetify that I would like to skip in seconds, but Parott&amp;rsquo;s music can stay with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgotten&#34;&gt;Why Are Songs Forgotten?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One seemingly trivial reason is the age of the music. The current global hits are very new releases. The songs I curated for this months were released 2-25 years ago, though some of them are featured with newer re-releases on Spotify. Many songs on Forgetify are much older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_popularity_age.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research and other&amp;rsquo;s research show that people &lt;em&gt;typically&lt;/em&gt; listen less and less music as they age. There are many people who listen to music lifelong, but others do it less and less, or completely drop the habit. And a large majority of the people tend to listen to similar music that she liked in her teenage years. For most young women and men, the music discovery period ends with school,  &lt;em&gt;typically&lt;/em&gt; in some post-secondary education institution. Later, they are no longer together with ther cohort peer-grew, but with people from all age and demographic groups when they work. Very few songs become perennial hits, and most of them lose their audience as the fans are getting older, and drop the habit of listening to music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can you make sure that your music will have a healthy audience for many years to come? Make sure that teenagers in your country get access to local music, for example, via the school radios, and by bringing them to local shows. That people have a chance to discover it. Build a large enough audience while your band is active who will stay loyal to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important factor is the country where the music was released. Most of the current global hits come from the United States, and some from the United Kingdom, South Korea, Germany and Russia. My personal selection included the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deus.be/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dEUS&lt;/a&gt; from Antwerpen, Belgium, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davidkitt.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;David Kitt&lt;/a&gt; from Dublin, Ireland, and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theharmaleighs.com/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Harmaleighs&lt;/a&gt; Nashville, TN, are Americans who were released by 
Nettwerk Music Group in Vancouver, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;country_of_origin_forgetify.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forgotten tracks come from all over the world.  Many of them are Americans, because the US has the biggest recording industry and recorded far the most songs in the last 100-120 years. But on Forgetify my first 50 finds contained songs from Brazil, Finland, France, India, Palestine and Spain, not to mention plenty of classical recordings made all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify has a global audience, but it&amp;rsquo;s main audiences are in the US, Japan, South Korea, Germany and the United Kingdom.  It&amp;rsquo;s algorithms are trained to serve these audiences, and its new content is coming from these countries. And it recommends very goods songs from these places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because concert and festival promoters, and even radio editors are often basing their decisions on YouTube, Spotify, Apple Music followers, streams and likes, the global platforms may make it extremely difficult for niche genres (for example, ancient or classical music), or small nation artists (such as Slovaks, Belgians) or older artists to get heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally do not believe that it is entirely the platform&amp;rsquo;s fault. Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local initiative&lt;/a&gt; is aiming to use these platforms better, and find global audiences for great music made in small nations and small towns, or niche genres.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: Open Collaboration Experiment &amp; Feasibility Study</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Big data creates injustice.”&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil, author of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/roots-of-unity/review-weapons-of-math-destruction/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can train machine learning algorithms on millions of music fans, then you can very precisely find listeners in Bratislava, entire Slovakia, in the Slovak diaspora in the United States.  In Utrecht, in Flanders, in Japan. If you cannot, then your sales will be driven by Spotify, Apple, Amazon or Google’s YouTube. And you fill compete with millions, tens of million of songs in your own city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have access to the entire analytics toolkit to fine-tune your mastering, your instruments, your tempo, when you know how to plug into the radio editors pre-screening, then you have chance for airplay. If you are all small, even local content guidelines, such as national radio quotas or public radio targets will not help you, because you remain invisible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the support of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sgda.sk/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Arts Council&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soza.sk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SOZA&lt;/a&gt;, non-profit civic association representing more than 2,600 rights holders in Slovakia and over 1 million abroad (musical works composers, lyrics and publishers), and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ci-info.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Consolidated Independent&lt;/a&gt;, a music distributor platform 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/reprexbv/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reprex&lt;/a&gt; is preparing a feasibility study for the collaborative, transparent research tool and application that helps you to find your way to radio playlists, connect to fans in your own city, country, and in other towns along viable tour routes.  Make music export more of a science than a guessing game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;listen_local_mindmap.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first step, &lt;em&gt;until the end of 2020&lt;/em&gt;, we are going to create a demo application and a feasibility study with quantitative musicologists and data scientists. The demo application will show how to use AI to place the music of the volunteering bands and labels’s repertoire on radio lists and personal playlists.  Our feasibility study will show how different local content guidelines (radio quotas, public broadcaster targets, and other tools) can affect the market share of small local and national repertoires, and will provide culture policymakers and competition authorities with insight how to make the algorithm-driven music streaming, broadcasting marketplace more even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-you-participate-in-the-experiment&#34;&gt;How can you participate in the experiment?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first phase of the experiment, &lt;strong&gt;only artists and their groups released on Spotify&lt;/strong&gt; can participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation in the experiment is free&lt;/strong&gt;.  The research findings, including potential targets for your music, will be fully open, transparent and free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an artist, you can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;simply fill in a form&lt;/a&gt; identifying your music on Spotify, filling in a few biographical data about yourself (or your band, ensemble, group). We do not ask any financial data, and only very limited personal information. We only ask about city affiliations, targeted cities, age, experience level, and language of your lyrics, if you do not play instrumental music. In our experience, these factors are very important among musicology and sound engineering quality measures. (Read a bit more about our data 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/#data-use&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data use&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a &lt;strong&gt;fan of independent music&lt;/strong&gt;, please, &lt;strong&gt;forward this post&lt;/strong&gt; to a band that you would love to see in our project, or a local music venue that you would like to visit again after the covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_analysis.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project originally started out of Slovakia, Hungary, Czechia and Poland, but we only found funding in Slovakia for a low-budget, open source, open data, open collaboration experiment. &lt;strong&gt;Participation is open anywhere in the world&lt;/strong&gt;, but we are &lt;strong&gt;focusing on a viable post-covid tour route&lt;/strong&gt; around Budapest – Bratislava – Vienna – Salzburg – Munich – Ruhr – the Netherlands – Belgium. We hope to give guidance on targeting both recorded and live music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you represent several artists&lt;/strong&gt; as a talent manager, music publisher, record label, granting agency or music export office, please get in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;touch with us&lt;/a&gt; for onboarding. We will ask you to contribute a small sum on a crowdsourcing basis to expand our experimental project, but the small financial contribution is not a mandatory requirement. (See budget and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/#transparency&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;transparency&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October Playlist: Wounded Egos</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every month I create a playlist for my friends and myself – a habit that I have started with mixtapes. This month reflects our team’s journey into one of the world’s most prestigious 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;startup validation
lab&lt;/a&gt; in the AI field, in a year when the recession is deeper than ever since the World War 2, the music business is devastated by the pandemic, and our team is forced to lockdown, follow this excellent validation lab on Zoom screens, meet our first clients online, and learn to work together in a socially distanced way. The songs I chose are subjectively important to me, a bit maybe even controversial ones, and probably very different from the music that you are listening to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to use this example as a start of series how we are
thinking about connecting musicians and their fans in new ways with the help of AI and big data. How we are planning to bring back life to the small venues after the pandemic? How we try to keep the link between musicians and their audience alive in this very sad year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_analysis.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this chart you can see a short analysis of my &lt;code&gt;Wounded Egos&lt;/code&gt; playlist. It is a very personal, subjective playlist. Subjectivity is very important to us, because we want to use the
insights from big data and machine learning in a very personal way to
the music community: fans, artists, technicians, managers, labels,
publisher and all the ecosystem. You can play my playlist in Spotify’s embedded player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below the music player you find a very short 
&lt;a href=&#34;#comparison&#34;&gt;comparison&lt;/a&gt; of the current global hits and the current hits in the Netherlands on Spotify. This time I would like to illustrate the difference of my listening habits from the global mainstream, and I won&amp;rsquo;t go in depth to how we want to make more relevant recommendations. These are the difference that we are trying to capture for local music scenes, cities, countries in our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen_local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you find it interesting why I chose these songs in October 2020, you read about 
&lt;a href=&#34;#october-playlist&#34;&gt;my choices&lt;/a&gt; as a personal recommendation at the end of the post&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/3WyQdQgSipGzQ9a7N5xC1s&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparison&#34;&gt;A Quick Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My playlist is a very subjective and curated playlist&amp;hellip; (&lt;em&gt;I curated it myself, after all!&lt;/em&gt;) These songs are very different from the songs that people are more likely listening to around me in the Netherlands, or all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My subjective list for October 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: 1. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/14LSfvkF3PS0k81FAe6PFk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wounded Egos&lt;/a&gt;  -  2. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3MKXdtTufdX4BwVbuJqFGW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sirens&lt;/a&gt;  -  3. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3A8ZDfxmb75kFl5Cqr2pIf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Panic&lt;/a&gt;  -  4. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3ezOmKfYasIe0QeWyWiucU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t Stop&lt;/a&gt;  -  5. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2rvxQwn7rGR0ZmHvwP4AmG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Michael And Heather At The Baggage Claim&lt;/a&gt;  -  6. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/6Uhhwk8oJc8SLloZIAQksB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Machinist&lt;/a&gt;  -  7. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7lBpCteEdS5WbOnzbVmWiR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Royal Screw Up&lt;/a&gt;  -  8. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/49UDOG8DoBajXTJSTqfRMg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kyoto&lt;/a&gt;  -  9. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0qZ9rwAonJvO91GK9nqqma&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Yours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Netherlands Top 50 on Spotify (3rd week of October 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;: 1. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3tjFYV6RSFtuktYl3ZtYcq&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mood (feat. iann dior)&lt;/a&gt;  -  2. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7hxHWCCAIIxFLCzvDgnQHX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lemonade (feat. Gunna, Don Toliver &amp;amp; NAV)&lt;/a&gt;  -  3. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/6cx06DFPPHchuUAcTxznu9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Head &amp;amp; Heart (feat.  MNEK)&lt;/a&gt;  -  4. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0NuAnAqjZjuGtcWXJOxUyl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;In De Schuur&lt;/a&gt;  -  5. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2MlOUXmcofMackX3bxfSwi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jerusalema (feat. Nomcebo Zikode)&lt;/a&gt;  -  6. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/5u1n1kITHCxxp8twBcZxWy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Holy (feat. Chance The Rapper)&lt;/a&gt;  -  7. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/32Q0JiYuVr2mcxfRIPyEBS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Más Más Más&lt;/a&gt;  -  8. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/4afGO0WTInDhK2C3dolz8z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;De Overkant&lt;/a&gt;  -  9. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/58trym7xUwRuXnBY7hKqC9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Door De Wind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Top 50 on Spotify (3rd week of October 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;: 1. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3tjFYV6RSFtuktYl3ZtYcq&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mood (feat. iann dior)&lt;/a&gt;  -  2. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7hxHWCCAIIxFLCzvDgnQHX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lemonade (feat. Gunna, Don Toliver &amp;amp; NAV)&lt;/a&gt;  -  3. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/4Oun2ylbjFKMPTiaSbbCih&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WAP (feat. Megan Thee Stallion)&lt;/a&gt;  -  4. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/1yoMvmasuxZfqHEipJhRbp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hawái&lt;/a&gt;  -  5. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0t1kP63rueHleOhQkYSXFY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dynamite&lt;/a&gt;  -  6. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/1tkg4EHVoqnhR6iFEXb60y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;What You Know Bout Love&lt;/a&gt;  -  7. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0PvFJmanyNQMseIFrU708S&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;For The Night (feat. Lil Baby &amp;amp; DaBaby)&lt;/a&gt;  -  8. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0VjIjW4GlUZAMYd2vXMi3b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blinding Lights&lt;/a&gt;  -  9. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/5u1n1kITHCxxp8twBcZxWy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Holy (feat. Chance The Rapper)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The most streamed songs in the Netherlands overlap with the most streamed songs all over the world, but there is no overlap with my list.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to create locally relevant recommendations. If you live in
Antwerpen, and you are looking for bands that you can see on a small
stage after the pandemic, we will recommend you great music from
Northwestern Belgium and the South of Holland. If you want to visit San Diego after the pandemic, we’ll recommend you music from the San Diego scene. If you want to fill up with good music a local content quota, such as a national and city relevant quota in your radio, we will help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next comparison uses some musicology and sound engineering
“features” of the songs on the three lists. These characteristics
are themselves recognized by algorithms, and they are used for Spotify’s own recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_comparison.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt; My songs
are independent songs, far less popular than the global hits. My
playlist is mainly indie rock, so far less danceable, less loud than the current hits, but it is more energetic! The average tempo is similar to the hits, but I tend to chose slower songs, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s &lt;code&gt;valence&lt;/code&gt; is a quantitative measure that aims to capture the
positiveness conveyed by the a sound recording(e.g.happy, cheerful,
euphoric on the positive side, and sad, depressed, angry on the negative side). Another striking difference among my list and the two hitlists is the far broader scale of emotions conveyed by the songs that I selected for October 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next blogposts we will explain some details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-playlist&#34;&gt;Wounded Egos: Daniel’s October Playlist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Gaz Coombes - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/14LSfvkF3PS0k81FAe6PFk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wounded Egos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting up a company, building a team in the times of corona, social
distancing, zoom calls and narcissistic world leaders is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. dEUS - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3MKXdtTufdX4BwVbuJqFGW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sirens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“You gotta pick your fights, you’ve got work to do”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which makes you think that you have to resist the Sirens call. This
record came out the day before I went to my CFA exam, which was the most gruelling test in my life. I just downloaded it, put it on the car hifi, pressed play and did the 8 hour test without error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Harmaleighs - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3A8ZDfxmb75kFl5Cqr2pIf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Don’t Panic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“But what if that’s all I’m good at?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t Panic surprised me so much that it found its way to my September
and October playlist, too. If something is perfect, it is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon Spencer Blues Explosion - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3ezOmKfYasIe0QeWyWiucU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Can’t
Stop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I just can’t stop”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I need to go back to the basics. Jon Spencer is as good as
Elvis must have been on stage. I never saw Elvis on stage, I am too
young for that, but old enough to have seen Jon Spencer on a large and
small stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fountains of Wayne - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2rvxQwn7rGR0ZmHvwP4AmG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Michael And Heather At The Baggage Claim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Michael &amp;amp; Heather at the baggage claim tired of playing the waiting
game”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The covid pandemic not only froze the entire music industry, and put
many artists, venues, managers, technicians on life support, but claimed many lives in the audience and in the music community. I still come to tears when I recall that early March day when I learned that Adam Schlesinger, my favourite lyricist and songwriter died. I was alwayshoping that I will show him what we were doing. We will certainly dedicate something to his memory along the way. For 15 years, when I was sad, I just picked one of the Fountains of Wayne records, and put it on. For this playlist, I chose a bittersweet song, which probably has the best poetry written in independent music ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify falls for the typical Schlesinger trick: the melody is very
upbeat, the lyrics is bittersweet. Spotify risks to put it into the
positive and danceable category, at least, within my list, though I find it just a bit less gloomy than 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3A8ZDfxmb75kFl5Cqr2pIf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Don’t
Panic&lt;/a&gt; and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7lBpCteEdS5WbOnzbVmWiR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Royal Screw
Up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japanese Breakfast - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/6Uhhwk8oJc8SLloZIAQksB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Machinist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How can I fight a kingdom of your demons?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t complain about the big algorithms of the big company. Spotify’s algorithm brought Japanese Breakfast to me. We just want to take a less individualist approach to making recommendations. Michelle Zauner is on the feminine side of this list, and I just can’t get enough of her music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s analysis finds this song to be less danceable and dark, which is exactly why Japanese Breakfast is such a curious artist project. It is experimental pop music that twists well-known pop clichés into original new songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soccer Mommy - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7lBpCteEdS5WbOnzbVmWiR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Royal Screw Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“And I want an answer to all my problems”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Soccer Mommy’s new record came out in March, I could not resist
reaching out to the sound engineering team to convey my congratulations. Soccer Mommy is the youngest artist on this list with a huge talent, and the team that she works with is just world class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phoebe Bridgers - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/49UDOG8DoBajXTJSTqfRMg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kyoto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You called me from a payphone / They still got pay phones”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular song on the playlist, a true global independent hit.
Phoebe Bridgers is hot, and she 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/155586901702555/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;may be a
killer&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Kitt - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0qZ9rwAonJvO91GK9nqqma&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;It’s Yours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify sees this song as the most danceable and most positive song. And it is so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Websites Is Not Easy</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-14-making_websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-14-making_websites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often find myself in a crossfire between artists and managers who want more transparency and innovation and collective management societies that see themselves as the last stable pillar for music composers, producers and performers to collect their royalties. I was in Bratislava preparing a project with the Slovak societies when a Belgian music professional, Suzanne Verschueren working in the Slovak music industry showed my Moon Moon Moon’s Journal Entry 10. A letter of complaint to the Dutch collective management societies, Buma and Stemra. In a song.  With video animation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaEKUy6KGE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-14-making_websites/playjournal10.png&#34; alt=&#34;Click on image to play video&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaEKUy6KGE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click on image to play video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately contacted Moon Moon Moon, because I had a better laugh at a music industry insider joke, and because I realized that this is one of the many bridges that we need to close if we want to build the European Music Observatory. (See our Demo Music Observatory 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Buma/Stemra reached out to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/moonmoonmoontheband&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon&lt;/a&gt; within a day of the release, and within a week they figured out where did the 1500 euro go, apologized for the mistake. The band and the collective management organization have been working together ever since as best friends forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this story is not over.  A year later, the video had less than 1000 views on YouTube.  How is it possible, when the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLA58ktFjlFijWiHTbTju4-OnswRmjKTC9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon Journal Entries&lt;/a&gt; are so good?  My 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/team/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;startup team&lt;/a&gt; decided to team up with the MMM collective to figure out how it is possible that with all the might of the artificial intelligence of YouTube’s and Spotify’s algorithms this gem is not world famous yet.  And yes, we are working with a sister society of Buma/Stemra in Slovakia to make this happen, who, in spite of their bad rep among artists, have been fighting with me side by side since 2016 to make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to design an app that connects artists and their fans in a better way, using the same might of the algorithms, but working for the small band.  We will re-release the Journal Entries as an album, and we will create algorithms that will find audiences for MMM all over in the Netherlands and Belgium, and in Japan, and probably in many other countries on the way from Utrecht to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tw0zYd0eIlk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kyoto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-links&#34;&gt;Further links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bumastemra.nl/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Buma/Stemra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/moonmoonmoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/v3upRs7?fbclid=IwAR04uKn_1TurL6cZArdwMigw9BDXpVqp9AXL3W12U94a69SeobDBT6jCbSo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon on Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaEKUy6KGE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal Entry 10: Growing a Beard While Using The New Buma/Stemra Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://icons8.com/icons/set/play&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Play icon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product/Market Fit Validation in Yes!Delft</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 15:31:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate our product market/fit in two segments, business/policy research and scientific research, with a supporting role given to data journalism. Because we want to follow a bootstrapping strategy, we must focus on those clients where we find the highest value proposition, which is of course easier said than done.  We see much interest in our offering from other continents, therefore we truly welcome the opportunity that we can do this on a truly global business canvas in one of the worlds’ 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/news/yesdelft-among-the-top-5-business-incubators-in-the-world/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;top five incubators&lt;/a&gt;, the number 2 university-backed incubator in the world, second to none in Europe, in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/focus-areas/artificial-intelligence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain&lt;/a&gt; Validation Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Europe hundreds of thousands of microenterprises, such as record labels, video producers or book publishers are facing data and AI giants like Google’s YouTube, Apple Music, Spotify, Netflix or Amazon. If the recommendation engines of these giants do not recommend their songs, films or books, then their investments are doomed to fail, because about half of the global sales are driven by AI algorithms. When they make a claim for the missing money, they will immediately find themselves in a dispute with gigabytes of data that they can only handle with a data scientist, even though they do not even have an IT professional or an HR professional to make the hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An awful lot of money, creativity and real values are at stake, and we want to be on the creator’s side, their technician’s side, their manager’s side when they want to get a fair share from the pie and they want to help these industry leader to make the pie grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unesco.org/new/en/culture/themes/creativity/arts-education/research-cooperation/observatories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UNESCO&lt;/a&gt; and the EU have been promoting as an organizational solution the fragmentation problem with the so-called data observatories that are pooling the business, policy, and scientific research needs of various domains, like music. This is an idea that we really like, and we believe that our research automation solutions can help these observatories to grow faster as ecosystems, create better quality and more timely data and research products and a far lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define ourselves as a reproducible research company inspired by the philosophy of open collaboration, based on open-source software and open data. We want to explore various revenue models around these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not committed to open source licensing if more permissive licensing policies provide us with better opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to explore various data-as-service models, because we do not want to be locked into the position of cheap open data vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to deploy AI applications that really help earning money in these sectors with playlisting, recommendation engines, forecasting applications, or royalty valuations, because our open collaboration approach brings up enough data sooner to than its alternatives, because it manages inherent conflicts of interests, fragmentation, and decentralization better than hierarchical solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January CEEMID reached its peak: we introduced a 12-country 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproducible research project&lt;/a&gt; made with only freelancers in Brussels, presented as best use case of evidence-based policy design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February Daniel visited the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/yes-delft-co-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft Co-Lab&lt;/a&gt; to find out who would be the best co-founder to re-launch CEEMID as an enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April we started to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;release our data&lt;/a&gt; as open data for validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month ago we 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started-up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we launched the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few other 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/annex.html#other-observatories&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data observatories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.palato.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Palato&lt;/a&gt; in the Hague, where we took our selfie and had an absolutely amazing dinner after the pitch. Check them out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting-up</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-08-24-start-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-08-24-start-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big day has come: the co-founders singed off the documents at the public notary and started the registration of a reproducible research start-up in Leiden.  We got a lot of support from our friends! Your encouragement gives us a lot of energy to accomplish our first milestones, and to get Reprex B.V. going!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex means &amp;lsquo;reproducible example&amp;rsquo; in data science.  When you are stuck with a problem, creating a reproducible example allows other computer scientists, statisticians, programmers or data users to solve it. In 80% of the cases, you usually find the solution while creating a generalized example.  In the 20% other cases, you can reach out for help easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming days, we are launching demo versions of our headline products, data observatories. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; will be a fully automated online service that every day collects, processes, cleans, and publishes scientifically valid data about European music.  Very soon after we will launch two other observatories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative and cultural sector, NGOs, most research institutions, data journalism teams are usually very small, and they do not have internal IT or data science capacities.  We would like to provide them a transparent, high quality, and fully open source solution to acquire data, process it without errors, document it and make sense of it. We would like to embrace the idea of open collaboration among creative enterprises, scientific researchers, NGOs, data journalists and policymakers with our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work will comply with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/opa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Policy Analysis&lt;/a&gt; standards developed by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkeley Initiative for Transparency in the Social Sciences&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cega.berkeley.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Effective Global Action&lt;/a&gt; and the four principles of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/reproducible/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproducible research&lt;/a&gt;: reviewability, replicability, confirmability and auditability.  We believe that these standards apply in reproducible finance, empirical evidence presentation in courts, or advocating sound policies and producing high-quality journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;help&#34;&gt;Do you want to help our start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to enter into the Validation Lab of one of the best artificial intelligence incubators in early September. Talented team members, letters of intents and assignments from organizations will give a lot of credibility to our start 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/team/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Meet our team »&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put as in contact with people who love to write code in R and interested in automating business and social science research and primary data collection such as surveying. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/#featured&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out what sort of code we create »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduce us to people who need data and information to make better informed decision and analysis in music, film, book publishing, photography services or socially responsible finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share contacts of data journalists who would like to develop stories from big survey programs like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/commfrontoffice/publicopinion/index.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.afrobarometer.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Afrobarometer&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latinobarometro.org/lat.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lationbarometro&lt;/a&gt;, or base their storytelling on data and its visualizations. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://retroharmonize.satellitereport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;See our survey harmonization examples »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know such people?  Send over this post or connect us in an email or social media message!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks again for your good wishes and encouragements, and hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regionalized Cultural Access and Participation (Books And Libraries) And Science Attitudes Variables</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-22-regional-eurobarometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-22-regional-eurobarometer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My new R package, Eurobarometer, helps the creation of data panels and regionalized statistics from the Pan-European survey’s microdata. This allows the creation of many new statistical indicators for the CEEMID Music Observatory and for many market and policy research tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example dataset (Antal 2020) was created from the microdata of the
Eurobarometer 79.2 survey using the development version of the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/antaldaniel/eurobarometer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer R package&lt;/a&gt;.
The dataset can be downloaded from

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3759811&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;. It will be used in a forthcoming academic publication about book piracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-access--participation-variables&#34;&gt;Cultural Access &amp;amp; Participation Variables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The read a book variable is a weighted sum of the responses that chose
from &lt;code&gt;QB1 How many times in the last twelve months have you read a book?&lt;/code&gt; any answer apart from “not in the last 12 months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/book-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Individuals Who Read A Book&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;library-access&#34;&gt;Library Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The library access variable is a weighted sum of the responses that
chose from &lt;code&gt;QB1 How many times in the last twelve months have you visited a public library?&lt;/code&gt; any answer apart from “not in the last 12 months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/library-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Individuals Who Visited A Library&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;limited-library-access&#34;&gt;Limited Library Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limited library access is a weighted sum of the responses that chose from the question block
&lt;code&gt;QB2 And for each of the following activities, please tell me why you haven’t done it or haven’t done it more often in the last 12 months? ... Visited a public library&lt;/code&gt; the answer option &lt;code&gt;Limited or poor quality of this activity in the place where you live.&lt;/code&gt; In this case, the number of respondents is rather low and this is not a very reliable statistic on regional level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Individuals Who Have Poor Local  Library&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;science--technology-attitudes&#34;&gt;Science &amp;amp; Technology Attitudes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supports open access variable is a weighted sum of yes answer
options to the &lt;code&gt;QD 17 Do you think that the results of publicly funded research should be made available online free of charge?&lt;/code&gt;
question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/openaccess-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Individuals Who Have Poor Local  Library&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demography&#34;&gt;Demography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet access question is a weighted sum of responses to the
answer option for &lt;code&gt;D46 Which of the following do you have? - An Internet connection at home&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/internetaccess-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Individuals Who Have Internet Access At Home&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet access question is a weighted sum of responses to the
answer option for &lt;code&gt;D15 What is your current occupation? - student&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/students-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Regional Student Population&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-source--data-processing&#34;&gt;Data Source &amp;amp; Data Processing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source of the data is the microdata file stored in GESIS for the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://dbk.gesis.org/dbksearch/sdesc2.asp?db=e&amp;amp;no=5688&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurobarometer 79.2
survey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data file contains the microdata for the Eurobarometer 79.2 survey (TNS Opinion &amp;amp; Social 2013), which includes a Cultural Access and Participation Survey (see (Haan and Broek 2012; Bína, Vladimir et al.2012)) and a Science &amp;amp; Technology Attitude survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey samples are designed to represent the national population,
with the exceptions of Northern Ireland, the former East- and
West-Germany, and the Turkish community on Cyprus. These samples are
designed to be representative for these populations, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For weighting we used the w1 weights, which allow for
post-stratification based on gender, education level and community size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of the Republic of Cyprus, Estonia, Latvia, Luxembourg and
Malta regionalization is not necessary because the entire countries are equivalent to a single NUTS2 region in terms of size and homogeneity. In these countries the weighting produces representative statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, due to a problem with the original data file, no regional information is available for the Republic of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Germany, Great Britain and Italy, data can be summarized on the level of NUTS1 territories, and we are imputing these values into the constituent (smaller sub-)regions on NUTS2 levels. In the case of the remaining countries it can be summarized on NUTS2 levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the survey samples are designed to be nationally representative, the regional sub-samples are not necessarily representative, and often they are very small. For post stratification purposes, we created a “dirty weighting”, Using the national w1 post-stratification weights, but centered to an average value of 1 for each region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that this causes problems on more detailed answer options (on the level levels of the questionnaire’s question hierarchy.) Except for the science attitudes and the library quality questions, we used relatively simple questions that are less affected by the small,
potentially biased sample size&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A better option would be the creation of new, regional
post-stratification weights. We believe that this would be a very
interesting, but very big research task that would potentially need the cooperation of the survey’s producer, Kantar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: &lt;em&gt;This was originally posted on Daniel&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2020-04-22-regional-eurobarometer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://eurobarometer.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt; became a much more useful and ex post survey harmonization tool after Marta joined the development efforts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel, Antal. 2020. “Regionalized Cultural Access and Participation
(Books And Libraries) And Science Attitudes Variables 2013.” Zenodo.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3759811&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3759811&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bína, Vladimir, Chantepie, Philippe, Deboin, Valérie, Kommel, Kutt,
Kotynek, Josef, and Robin, Philippe. 2012. “ESSnet-CULTURE, European
Statistical System Network on Culture. Final Report.” Edited by Frank,
Guy.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&#34;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haan, Jos de, and Andries van den Broek. 2012. “Nowadays Cultural
Participation - an Update of What to Look for and Where to Look for It.”
In &lt;em&gt;ESSnet-CULTURE, European Statistical System Network on Culture.
Final Report.&lt;/em&gt;, 397–417. Luxembourg.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&#34;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/culture/our-policy-development/documents/ess-net-report-oct2012.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TNS Opinion &amp;amp; Social. 2013. “Cultural Access and Participation. Special Eurobarometer 399 Report.” European Commission.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/public_opinion/archives/ebs/ebs_399_en.pdf&#34;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/public_opinion/archives/ebs/ebs_399_en.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First CEEMID Regional Open Data Release</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internet use: participating in social networks (creating user profile, posting messages or other contributions to facebook, twitter, etc.) [percentage of individuals]&lt;/em&gt; shows the development of social media use in the past 10 years in very high detail.  Social media is one of the most important ways to communicate with fans and find audiences for gigs, performances and to share new releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/dataanimation/internet_use_social_networks.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Social media use 2011-2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chosen dataset is highlighting several new priorities of CEEMID.  This indicator, which is based on a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://appsso.eurostat.ec.europa.eu/nui/show.do?dataset=isoc_r_iuse_i&amp;amp;lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurostat statistical product&lt;/a&gt;, has a much higher data quality than the Eurostat release, it is easier to use, and goes beyond the detail of national statistics.  It contains data on 411 territories in Europe, including countries, provinces and smaller regions, even some metropolitan areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset is available on the European open research data repository, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/record/3754574#.XpimX8gzbIU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;. It will be updated annually. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3754574&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/DOI/10.5281/zenodo.3754574.svg&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The processing information is available in the dataset.  First, we have used our open source software to correct the regional boundary changes during the decade (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-02-13-regional_eurostat/&#34;&gt;Programatic Approach To Work With European Regional Data Panels&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When data was missing in the end of the dataset, we used the last observation carry forward, when in the beginning, the next observation carry backwards data.  Gaps in the data were interpolated using linear interpolation. Whenever data was available on a larger (provincial level), we imputed it to the smaller regional units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data contains standard national / regional references according the European NUTS2013 standard for backwards compatibility. Further documentation will be available on our methodology on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;documentation.ceemid.eu&lt;/a&gt; wiki website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last, the data was put into a table that complies with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstatsoft.org/article/view/v059i10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidy data&lt;/a&gt; principles for easier processing on computers and immediate use in spreadsheet applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use this in your article? Further research? Collaboration? Let&amp;rsquo;s get in touch on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or via 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;danielantal.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2011)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_238711_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2015)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_246037_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2019)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_250355_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2011)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_247818_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2015)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_247520_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2019)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_243997_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Social Distancing in Europe</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People around the world are facing newer and newer exponential charts everyday. We’re all hoping for new information about the progress against the coronavirus. Unfortunately, the vast majority of these charts is meaningless. In fact, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/coronavirus-case-counts-are-meaningless/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;coronavirus case counts are meaningless&lt;/a&gt;, unless they are done with very heavy statistical knowledge, and even then they are very messy. Countries have different testing and hospitalization protocols, death certificating standards, and there are less and more trustworthy governments. We do not really know the severity of the local epidemics and the relative success of public health policies.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/countryclusters.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Clustering countries on current lockdown strictness and change&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/countryclusters_huc63f6ee1cc1b69a8e28d2c9e7295fd18_347025_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;338&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/difference_summary_en.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Changes in community space use, end of March and early April&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/difference_summary_en_huc7370673eb468102ac3ad5af70997f54_262570_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/work_home_change_EN.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Growth in time spend at home and in the workplace since January&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/work_home_change_EN_huf1bc5f0534491039237e4dc526b79bf4_336010_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, we have some timely information on how people and the economy react to the epidemic, because there are ongoing, frequent, and comparable data sources on various consequences of the epidemic.  A particularly interesting big data source is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blog.google/technology/health/covid-19-community-mobility-reports/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google’s geolocational reporting&lt;/a&gt; on how people’s time spent in homes, workplaces, parks, shopping areas and recreational areas change. Google gets plenty of realtime data from hundreds of millions of people and compares them by days in the week and local time with the ‘baseline’ scenario before the outbreak of the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the locational data of various smartphones and application data, we know that people spend 10-15% more time at home since January, and 40-50% less in their workplaces.  Similar data is available for other locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/post/2020-04-15-covid/work_home_en_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stay at home or go to the workplace?&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While people are spending less time in the workplace and more at home in every European country, there are significant differences.  Countries in the top left corner, most notable Sweden, switched less from workplaces to homes.  On the bottom right corner, Spain and Italy, which were most hit by the epidemic, are in the most severe form of lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some outliers, like Romania, where people stay a lot more at home, but not so much less in the workplaces – probably they cannot afford to stay clear of the job, but they are reducing other activities.  Or, in the case of Germany, people spend a lot more time in parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/post/2020-04-15-covid/difference_summary_en_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Differences in space use in Europe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grouped the countries according to their dynamics.  Looking at Belgium and Luxembourg, we see that they are more locked down than the typical European country, but they are moving up in the first week of April compared to the last week of March. This is very much in line with their improving strain on the health system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/post/2020-04-15-covid/countryclusters_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Clusters of countries&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is worrying is that there appears to be a significant asynchronicity in the Schengen zone, where people and goods should move around freely.  The peripheric countries, which are less densely populated, often less integrated into the global transport and travel routes, are getting into the local epidemics later, and are acting later.  This is logical from a national point of view, but given that the European economy is very much integrated, it will prolong the pain.  The Netherlands, France and Germany need plenty of seasonal agricultural workers from the Southeast, where the lockdown is just getting really strict.  While some of their regions see improving national epidemic situations, the easing will increase the intensity of the local epidemic if a large number of workers will arrive from countries that are just going into the epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efficient solution, as many public health officials keep saying, would be a synchronized effort to contain the virus.  The different pace and strictness of social distancing measures will mean that the local epidemics will not be in synchronization, and the countries will re-infect each other, this way prolonging the economic and social cost of this devastating pandemic.  While health policy is a national competence in the European Union, in fact, the European economic and social life is so much integrated, not only within the Schengen Zone, but even with future, prospective and candidate members states in the Balkans, that a far more coordinated public health policy would be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use this in your article? Further research? Collaboration? The data &amp;amp; code is available in a private github repo. Let&amp;rsquo;s get in touch on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or via 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;danielantal.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please quote this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel (2020): Comparing Social Distancing in Europe (March, April 2020). figshare. Preprint. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.12124194.v1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.12124194.v1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp; The Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativeflip.creativehubs.net/2019/12/03/flipping-the-odds/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference&lt;/a&gt; – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel&amp;rsquo;s presentation was focused around the question on invisibility of the CCI sector in the economic, education and labour policymaking, and the low level of data use in fact-based cultural policy design, and the following policy design problems. Our CEE Music Industry Report 2020 created with the help and support of Consolidated Independent was used as a use case for the problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post is an edited version of Daniel&amp;rsquo;s presentation and the subsequent panel discussion with the stakeholders and organizers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEE Report builds on the results of the first 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Croatian&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://czdev.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Czech&lt;/a&gt; music industry reports are compared with Armenian, Austrian, Bulgarian, Lithuanian, Serbian and Slovenian data and findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/publications/cee_report_2020_frontcover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;invisibility&#34;&gt;Invisibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measurement problems and the ‘invisibility’ of creative and cultural industries is a consequence of the fact that these industries are predominantly comprised of microenterprises and individual, freelancing entrepreneurs.  Even larger entities, such as collective management organizations can be classified as small enterprises.
In the EU, small- and medium enterprises, and especially microenterprises usually have reduced reporting duties to the statistical authorities and tax authorities (which is the most important secondary source of government statistics in anonymized, aggregated form.)  This means that the supply side is not visible for policymakers. The recommendation is to conduct sample-based surveys among these microenterprises, but very few member states do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem is that on the demand side, not all member states create statistics.  ESSNet-Culture created recommendations how to measure cultural access and participation, which is a broader term than cultural consumption, as it includes non-market forms, for example, liturgical music, amateur acting, and so on.  The European Commission sometimes makes excellent, but not detailed 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/usecase/cap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CAP surveys&lt;/a&gt;, which are the most important sources of Eurostat’s relevant pan-European statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEEMID has been making such surveys, both on the supply side (in music and film) and in the audience side (in music, film, theatre, opera, and artistic activities) in several member states, and has plenty of experience with using the EU-mandated CAP surveys of 2007 and 2013. The CEE report relies on the latter date set in first part of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/audience.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;audience analysis&lt;/a&gt;. Our work was already presented in 2015 as a best use case in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/creating_better_2015/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Creating better national cultural statistics with Eurobarometer datasets and ESSNet-Culture technical recommendations&lt;/a&gt; at GESIS, which maintains the Eurobarometer archives, on the Eurobarometer Symposium 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gesis.org/fileadmin/upload/events/EB-Symposium/Announcement_EB_Symposium.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Four Decades of Surveying Europe –
Perspectives on Academic Research with the European Commission’s Eurobarometer Surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the EU the lowest hanging fruit would be to critically assess the past surveys, including the partial CAP survey made in 2017 for the cultural heritage part of culture, and the national surveys conducted by CEEMID and its partners, and to mandate an annual or biannual CAP survey within the Eurobarometer series, probably as a specially sampled “Special Eurobarometer”.  This would very significantly reduce the costs compared to a country-to-country basis, and probably could be shared by other institutions, for example, with the European Audiovisual Observatory.  This alone would greatly increase the demand / consumption side information on the services of creative and cultural enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the panel discussion Consolidated Independent highlighted the problem of leaving sample-based statistics making to the industry itself, which leads to myopical incentives to create ‘policy-based evidence’ that is cherry picked by industry trade associations to fit their often not very well thought out policy agenda.  In our view, the most important role of a future European Music Observatory would be to set standards to data collection and integration.  The music industry is  one of the most data-rich industries globally, but the publicly available, verified, trustworthy information is scarce both for policy-making and for business planning among microenterprises who have know specialized research know-how. Our already existing, representative 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://survey2019.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;national surveys&lt;/a&gt; should and could be extended to the whole Europe with the quality control and visibility offered by such an Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;industry-organization&#34;&gt;Industry organization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very significant challenge with evidence-based policymaking, or, in fact, with any policy making is that the extremely fragmented nature of the industry makes national and EU-level consultations very difficult.  Most of the workforce is neither a classical employer nor employee but works as a freelancer or a micro-entrepreneur. Their views are very rarely represented by trade unions or employee associations or chambers of commerce. Despite all efforts on EU level to make the social dialogue more representative for atypical and flexible work forms, the problems and the views of the creative and cultural sectors are largely unrepresented in policy debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prime example of this problem is the very heavy over-taxation of the music industry that we have shown in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak&lt;/a&gt; national music industry reports, and in other documents in Croatia.  The problem is not only characteristic for the music industry, but generally all CCIs because they share similar economic properties: no real chance to use tax breaks, high level of labour input and high level of value added.  While policy makers and granting authorities spend much time on trying to improve the financing of this sector, in fact, reducing over-taxation would make a much more imminent impact on the liquidity, profitability and growth opportunities of the sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in the making of economic and tax policies, the fragmented creative and cultural industries hardly can represent their special situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;policy-issues&#34;&gt;Policy issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from taxation issues, which significantly reduce the liquidity, profitability and growth opportunities of these sectors in many EU countries, particularly in the CEE, where corporate taxes are low but value-added taxes are high, there are other important policy problem that reduce the long-term growth capacity of the sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very small enterprise size leads to missing strategic human resources (HR) and research and development (R&amp;amp;D) functions in almost all enterprises – including simple market research activities.  Companies with 1-2 employees do not have specialized management and support functions, and thus they have a very strong handicap in HR and R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of this problem is the motion picture and TV industry.  These industries were comprised of medium-sized enterprises in the 1980s with significant in-house education functions. The current structure of these industries, however, resembles music, with almost all enterprises staying below the 5-person threshold.  In our experience, based on development needs assessments in the Hungarian motion picture and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://czdev.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Czech music industry&lt;/a&gt;, this creates an acute skills and labor shortage.  Missing skills cannot be well replaced by recruitment, or with strategic HR development via life-long learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to very reduced opportunities to participate in, and create life-long learning schemes, there are very little chances to engage in market research and R&amp;amp;D.  While the music industry, for example, is one of the most data-driven industries in the world, the microenterprise size does not allow that these enterprises commission market research or hire data scientists. This leads to very asymmetrical relationships with the main distributors of music and media content on platforms that are owned by global data companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations&#34;&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel made a few concrete recommendations in the panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating the European Music Observatory, and the creation of similar industry initiatives, and commissioning collaborative (multi-stakeholder) market research, as CEEMID works in many countries, can only replace the missing market research function in the extremely fragmented industries, such as motion picture production, the music industry, but to a certain degree architecture and design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A low-hanging fruit would be a critical assessment of the previous Pan-European CAP surveys and the comparable national CAP surveys conducted by CEEMID and its partners following the ESSNet Culture recommendations and the inclusion of the CAP surveys in an annual or bi-annual form in the Eurobarometer (Special) series. A Special Eurobarometer may be more suitable because usually a non-proportional weighting of the sample gives the best value for money in these surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critically reviewing the participation of micro-enterprises in the current forms of social dialogue and looking for formal or informal ways to increase participation in policy making can gradually lead to more creative-friendly economic regulation and tax policies.  The Hungarian Music Industry Report 2015 and the Slovak Music Industry Report 2019 contains very interesting case studies for this problem that we briefly summarize in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEE Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critically reviewing the few examples from mainly Nordic member states where collective agreements and other collaborative institutions allow microenterprises and freelancers to participate in life-long learning problems can help designing policies that will gradually reduce the huge skill gap of the CCIs in management know-how, data know-how, or renew their technical skills necessary in the production of their services and content. Our work with the Hungarian National Film Fund and surveys among more than a thousand film makers can give much insight into this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-links&#34;&gt;Further links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research findings were earlier presented and discussed in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Vienna&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prague&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-11-18-bush/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Budapest&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/slovak_report19/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bratislava&lt;/a&gt; with stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow Creative FLIP project on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/creativeflip_eu?lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Czech Music Development Program &amp; Comparative Market Research</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was presenting some highlights from the work we started with in the organization of SoundCzech with 25 music professionals representing more than 20 stakeholders in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/2019_10_09_praha/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; evaluation workshop in the context of the comparative 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the full presentation, including slides not shown in the workshop 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/presentation/nouvelle-prague&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The presentation is a self-contained big file of 20Mb, takes time to load.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work is done in a collaborative manner with the open Research Consortium started by SoundCzech, CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent.  We would like to invite any Czech stakeholders, or even individuals to join our efforts.  Because in the music sector, all organization are microenterprise or small enterprise sized, they usually have no significant market research, innovation and strategic HR management capacities. We hope to give them in each country useful tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very interesting part of the discussion in the morning was around transparency and potential conflict between stronger and weaker markets. Thank you for all colleagues who came on a Saturday morning after great showcase concerts the night before, and let&amp;rsquo;s stay in touch!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Press release: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zamp.hr/clanak/pregled/2197/studija-naknade-za-privatno-kopiranje-btl-u-hrvatskoj-drasticno-ispod-prosjeka-eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Studija: Naknade za privatno kopiranje (BTL) u Hrvatskoj drastično ispod prosjeka EU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short summary in Croatian: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zamp.hr/uploads/documents/Saetak_studije_na_hrvatskom_jeziku.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Privatno kopiranje u Hrvatskoj&lt;/a&gt;
Full text in English: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zamp.hr/uploads/documents/Studija_privatno_kopiranje_u_Hrvatskoj_DA_CEEMID.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Private Copying in Croatia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central European Music Industry Report Presentation</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 08:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had the first public and panel discussion of the forthcoming Central European Music Industry Report.  After mapping and analysing in depth the music industries of several CEE countries, I put together with the help of Consolidated Independent and state51 a regional report in previously unseen detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can review the whole 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/presentation/CEE_Music_Report.html&#34;&gt;presentation here&lt;/a&gt; (10Mb self-contained HTML file, takes some time to load).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 
&lt;a href=&#34;post/2016-04-20_makk15&#34;&gt;mapping&lt;/a&gt; and analysing (see most recently 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovakia&lt;/a&gt;) in depth the music industries of several CEE countries, with the help of Consolidated Independent I put together a regional report in previously unseen detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The live music part explains the different demography and other demand drivers of the CEE region for concerts, resulting in high seasonality, low venue profitability, an unusually high vulnerability of small venues – and as a result an unusually strong music festival scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For recordings, the report shows the royalty gap in comparison to Western Europe and the difficulties of labels and publishers to create value added to musicians.  In the absence of a fully functional recording market, musicians are more reliant on collective management revenues than in the rest of Europe – yet in many countries collective management has profound difficulty in asking the correct price for music or collecting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/ceemid/expenditure_private_cultural_cinema_theatre_concert_filled_plot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Consumer demand for music events&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When analysing the music flows among European countries, and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/cross_border_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;export-import flows&lt;/a&gt; of other emerging markets in Latin America and the worlds most stable ones, like that of the United States, Brazil and Japan, we must realize that these nations face an uphill battle to get into the better paying markets and at the same time to protect their domestic market from increasing import substitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music grants could be an important tool to balance the disadvantaged position of CEE musicians in this global competition.  Austria and Hungary has a strong popular music support program, but usually the availability and suitability of grants is lower in those countries where musicians and their technical and managerial team would need it most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/dataanimation/is_grant_animation_1000_no_loop.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Accessibility and suitability of music grants&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very grateful for the support given by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ci-info.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Consolidated Independent&lt;/a&gt; in the making of this report. CI is the market leader in managed services for the digital music industry, connecting the best independent music with the opportunities of the global market. With their data science team, we put together data from about 700,000,000 royalty statement documents about the whole region. I believe that this is the first time that a global player releases large amounts of data to help understanding the changing music landscape in the era of digital streaming. Equally thankful for Franz Hergovich (Music Austria) for inviting us to discuss these findings on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/waves_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Waves Music Showcase Festival and Conference&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;on 27 September 2019&lt;/em&gt;  with Márton Náray (SoundCzech) and Péter Benjámin Tóth (Artisjus). And of course, the most important people to thank for are the more than 2000 musicians, managers and technicians who participated in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2019-06-07_ceemid_survey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID Music Professional Survey&lt;/a&gt;, which is one of the main data sources of this report, where no other information was available. You can find out more about the data sources 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/usecase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The report will be shortly released in a free downloadable ebook, and musicians, who requested it, will receive their personalized mini-reports shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All feedback is, as always, welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The whole report can be downloaded for free from the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soza.sk/aktuality/235/soza-zverej%C5%88uje-historicky-prvu-spravu-o-slovenskom-hudobnom-priemysle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;homepage of SOZA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press reports in Slovak:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SME: [SOZA predstavila prvú Správu o slovenskom hudobnom priemysle](Čítajte viac: &lt;a href=&#34;https://domov.sme.sk/c/22084685/soza-predstavila-historicky-prvu-spravu-o-slovenskom-hudobnom-priemysle.html&#34;&gt;https://domov.sme.sk/c/22084685/soza-predstavila-historicky-prvu-spravu-o-slovenskom-hudobnom-priemysle.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kreatívna Europa: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cedslovakia.eu/clanky/sprava-o-slovenskom-hudobnom-priemysle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Historicky prvá Správa o slovenskom hudobnom priemysle prináša okrem analýz aj odporúčania pre budúcnosť&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hungarian:
Új Szó: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ujszo.com/kultura/tudomanyosan-a-hazai-zeneiparrol&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tudományosan a hazai zeneiparról&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/86x5wKAlsIetxA&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel/spva-o-hudobnom-priemysle-na-slovensku-sharpe-2018&#34; title=&#34;Spáva o hudobnom priemysle na Slovensku&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Spáva o hudobnom priemysle na Slovensku&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dániel Antal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
