<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>surveys | Creative Data Observatories</title>
    <link>/tag/surveys/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/surveys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>surveys</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 11:31:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>surveys</title>
      <link>/tag/surveys/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible Survey Harmonization: retroharmonize Is Released</title>
      <link>/post/2020-09-21-retroharmonize_release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 11:31:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-09-21-retroharmonize_release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our original intention was to make surveying more accessible for music and creative industry partners, by relying more on already existing survey data, and better designing complementary, smaller surveys, becasue surveying, opinion polling is becoming increasingly expensive in the develop world.  People are less and less likely to sit down for an interview in their houses.  We have tried to harmonize our custom surveys, particuarly with Kantar in Hungary and Focus in Slovakia with exisiting EU projects.  But we ended up making a part of international survey harmonization across countries and throughout years easier to automate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/packages/ab_plot1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Harmonized results from Afrobarometer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surveys are like sensors for natural sciences and industrial production. They are essential for almost any social and economic statistical indicator, for calculating the inflation, parts of the GDP, participation in education programs.  Making surveys easier to harmonize and exploit more already existing survey data can bring down research cost, and can increase research value at the same time. (See our earlier blog post 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-07-10-retroharmonize/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Increase The Value Of Market Research With Open Data And Survey Harmonization&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you are an R user, you can use &lt;code&gt;install.packages(“retroharmonize”)&lt;/code&gt; to get the released 0.1.13 version and make tutorials with real Eurobarometer or Afrobarometer microdata.  With &lt;code&gt;devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;antaldaniel/retroharmonize&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt; you can already install the current development version 0.1.14, which handles perl-like regex, which will be necessary for our next tutorial in the making for 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arabbarometer.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Arab Barometer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize package website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/antaldaniel/retroharmonize/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize on github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>retroharmonize R package for survey harmonization</title>
      <link>/publication/retorharmonize_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/retorharmonize_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of &lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; is to provide tools for reproducible
retrospective (ex-post) harmonization of datasets that contain variables
measuring the same concepts but coded in different ways. Ex-post data
harmonization enables better use of existing data and creates new
research opportunities. For example, harmonizing data from different
countries enables cross-national comparisons, while merging data from
different time points makes it possible to track changes over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retrospective data harmonization is associated with challenges including
conceptual issues with establishing equivalence and comparability,
practical complications of having to standardize the naming and coding
of variables, technical difficulties with merging data stored in
different formats, and the need to document a large number of data
transformations. The &lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; package assists with the latter
three components, freeing up the capacity of researchers to focus on the
first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the &lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; package proposes a reproducible
workflow, including a new class for storing data together with the
harmonized and original metadata, as well as functions for importing
data from different formats, harmonizing data and metadata, documenting
the harmonization process, and converting between data types. See

&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/reference/retrohamonize.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
for an overview of the functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;code&gt;labelled_spss_survey()&lt;/code&gt; class is an extension of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://haven.tidyverse.org/reference/labelled_spss.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;haven’s
labelled_spss
class&lt;/a&gt;. It not
only preserves variable and value labels and the user-defined missing
range, but also gives an identifier, for example, the filename or the
wave number, to the vector. Additionally, it enables the preservation –
as metadata attributes – of the original variable names, labels, and
value codes and labels, from the source data, in addition to the
harmonized variable names, labels, and value codes and labels. This way,
the harmonized data also contain the pre-harmonization record. The
stored original metadata can be used for validation and documentation
purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vignette 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/articles/labelled_spss_survey.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Working With The labelled_spss_survey
Class&lt;/a&gt;
provides more information about the &lt;code&gt;labelled_spss_survey()&lt;/code&gt; class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/articles/harmonize_labels.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonize Value
Labels&lt;/a&gt;
we discuss the characteristics of the &lt;code&gt;labelled_spss_survey()&lt;/code&gt; class and
demonstrates the problems that using this class solves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also provide two extensive case studies illustrating how the
&lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; package can be used for ex-post harmonization of data
from cross-national surveys on the example of the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/articles/afrobarometer.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Afrobarometer&lt;/a&gt;
and the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/articles/eurobarometer.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt;.
The creators of &lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; are not affiliated with either
Afrobarometer, Eurobarometer, or the organizations that designs,
produces or archives their surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the &lt;code&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/code&gt; project is released with a

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/version/2/0/code_of_conduct/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Contributor Code of
Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.
By contributing to this project, you agree to abide by its terms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase The Value Of Market Research With Open Data And Survey Harmonization</title>
      <link>/post/2020-07-10-retroharmonize/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-07-10-retroharmonize/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last weeks I have been releasing the early source code of two R packages, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/publication/retorharmonize_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; harmonization infrastructure of surveys, and  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/publication/eurobarometer_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt; for Eurobarometer-specific work, complemented by my earlier release of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/publication/regions_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt;, which tracks about 20,000 regional boundary changes of French departments, Polish voivodeships and Hungarian counties, and other sub-national divisions of about 32 European countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very technical terms of &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; or retrospective harmonization hide opportunities that can significantly increase the value for money in empirical market research, potentially increasing the value of a high-cost, high-value survey to multiple times of its euro value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my work, I have used &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; harmonized questionnaires with EU survey programs, for example, the harmonized CAP surveys to determine the characteristics of concert audiences in a country, or people who download music to their computers.  The EU has been opening up its own survey programs in a piecemeal fashion, and surveys used by the European Commission, the Parliament, or even the national statistical offices are becoming more and more available.  After harmonizing the questions, I can apply &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; harmonization of the results, too, resulting in a far more valuable research document:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can usually compare the basic values, such as concert visiting likelihood in the past – for example, I surveyed Hungary and Slovakia first in 2015, but immediately could compare with 2013 and 2007 data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dataanimation/concert_hu_animation_smooth.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Harmonized concert visiting questions over time&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I get international benchmarks for free, for example, German, Czech, French data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/music/cee_concert_demography_16x9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Harmonized concert visiting questions accross countries&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the hierarchical nature of CAP surveys, I can make reasonable estimates of details that I survey only in one or few countries, such as visiting jazz concerts, and not concert only; or copying non-licensed music to devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is no free lunch here.  I can access millions of euros values of survey data, but nobody will make prepare it for my use. These surveys were processed for different users and different uses and joining them with my data is a very difficult task that I had been doing better and better in the past 5 years. To make this work as error-free as possible, I will publish the critical elements of the code as open source software on CRAN soon - the github release is an early version of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the current momentum is due to a new contributor to these packages, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://martakolczynska.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marta Kołczyńska&lt;/a&gt;, who is an excellent R programmer and a bright academic in international survey harmonization and reproducible research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related&#34;&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eurobarometer.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://regions.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eurobarometer R package</title>
      <link>/publication/eurobarometer_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/eurobarometer_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please review the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eurobarometer.dataobservatory.eu/articles/workflow.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surveys</title>
      <link>/project/music_observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/music_observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most important technical guideline on cultural statistics is the &lt;em&gt;Final Report of the Woking Group European Statistical System Network on Culture&lt;/em&gt; (in short: ESSnet-Culture) [@frank_guy_essnet-culture_2012].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESSnet-Culture gave a thorough overview of cultural data sources, guidelines on standardizing data, and a technical definition of the domain, including an exact mapping of cultural and creative activities and occupations to statistical nomenclatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;icet&#34;&gt;ICET model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultural participation extends beyond the market-oriented forms of &amp;ldquo;cultural consumption&amp;rdquo; and include non-market forms, such as private copying or liturgical events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ESSnet-Culture working group endorsed the ICET model of quantifying cultural participation.   The aim of the ICET model is to create representative surveys, but it is a very good framework to join survey data with other data sources.  For example, the music industry and the audiovisual sector usually has extensive transaction data on most market-oriented activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Information&lt;/em&gt;: to seek, collect and spread information on culture;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communication and community&lt;/em&gt;: to interact with others on cultural issues and to participate in cultural networks;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoyment and expression&lt;/em&gt;: to enjoy exhibitions, art performances and other forms of cultural expression, to practice the arts for leisure, and to create online content;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transaction&lt;/em&gt;: to buy art and to buy or reserve tickets for shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The generic questionnaire was developed by Jos de Haan and Andries van den Broek at the Netherlands Institute for Social Research, originally for extending cultural participation surveys to digital forms of culture [@de_haan_virtuele_2008; @de_haan_nowadays_2012]. This methodology was endorsed by ESSnet-Culture, and a rather detailed guideline can be found in the report of the &lt;em&gt;Task Force on Cultural Practices And Social Aspects Of Culture&lt;/em&gt;, in the ESSNet-Culture technical report (in general: pp. 236-242, survey methodology and harmonization pp. 242-255, recommendations: pp. 273-274; with examples on how to use the question hierarchy on pp. 397-417.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;target-population&#34;&gt;Target Population&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the target population is representative members of the general public, such as in the case of audience surveys, we use 
&lt;a href=&#34;#cap&#34;&gt;CAP&lt;/a&gt; surveys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the target population is a professional or microenterprise group, such as performing artists or record labels, we use our 
&lt;a href=&#34;#professional&#34;&gt;Professional group surveys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap&#34;&gt;CAP surveys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESSnet-Culture has reviewed several pan-European CAP manifestations, and based on the recommendations, further CAP surveys were carried out in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2001: Europeans&amp;rsquo; Participation in Cultural Activities (2001)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEE CAP 2003:  Candidate Countries Eurobarometer 2003.1 New Europeans and Culture, all later EU member states of the EU27, except for Croatia, but including Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2006:  Within the EU-SILC Module 2006 On Social Participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2007:  Includes the EU27 + United Kingdom but not Croatia, Romania and Bulgaria, conducted within Eurobarometer European Cultural Values (2007)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2013: Includes the EU27 + Croatia (only few weeks before the country&amp;rsquo;s accession.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2015: Within the EU-SILC Module 2015 On Social/Cultural Participation And Material Deprivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on these guidelines and examples, we have carried out several in-depth music and audiovisual domain oriented CAP surveys:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2014: a large, but non-representative online sample to test the methodology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2015:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slovakia CAP 2015:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Croatia CAP 2017:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2017:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slovakia CAP 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;professional&#34;&gt;Professional Group Surveys&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Observatory</title>
      <link>/project/observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;observatory&lt;/strong&gt; is a location used for observing terrestrial or celestial events. The European Commission and the Council of Europe are supporting numerous data observatories to support research and development and evidence-based policymaking. We are creating automated observatories following the best practices of reproducible research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satellite Report grew out of a such an observatory, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-start-a-data-observatory&#34;&gt;How To Start A Data Observatory?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;private observatory&lt;/strong&gt; is a data integration system, which automatically collects external information, processes it and professionally joins it with internal data resources. We offer this to 
&lt;a href=&#34;#business&#34;&gt;business&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;#science&#34;&gt;scientific research&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ngo&#34;&gt;think tank and NGO&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;#journalism&#34;&gt;journalism&lt;/a&gt; partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;collaborative observatory&lt;/strong&gt; is a data integration system that has a map to collaborating institutions’s data resources, and is able to exploit their synergies by automatically combining their data, triggered by an authorization of all involved parties. We offer this to Consortia of various entities. Daniel&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/project/ceemid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID project&lt;/a&gt; developed since 2014 is a good example of a collaborative observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;public observatory&lt;/strong&gt; is a collaborative observatory that intends to make at least some of its data assets available as open data. ode chunk to prevent printing of the R code that generated the plot. We offer this for the European Union and its Consortia. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.satellitereport.com/index.php?title=Observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;See some observatories »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our observatories fulfil important functions in data collection, processing, integration, and automated modelling. We provide these services as custom software as service products in the form of data applications. To design a good observatory that fulfils your business, policy, scientific or journalistic needs, we provide data curating as a consulting service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few public observatories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eafo.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Alternative Fuels Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is an European Commission funded initiative which provides open and free information, amongst others to support Member States with the implementation of EU Directive 2014/94 on the deployment of alternative fuels infrastructure. The EAFO is maintained by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eafo.eu/knowledge-center/consortium&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EAFO Consortium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.energypoverty.eu/about/about-observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EU Energy Poverty Observatory&lt;/a&gt; (EPOV) is an initiative by the European Commission to help Member States in their efforts to combat energy poverty. It exists to improve the measuring, monitoring and sharing of knowledge and best practice on energy poverty, and it is developed by a consortium of universities, think tanks, and the business sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clustercollaboration.eu/eu-initiatives/european-cluster-observatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Observatory for Clusters and Industrial Change&lt;/a&gt; to help Europe&amp;rsquo;s regions and countries in designing better and more evidence-based cluster policies and initiatives. This platform is funded by the EU programme for
the Competitiveness of Enterprises and SMEs (COSME).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clusterobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cluster Observatory&lt;/a&gt; of the Center for Strategy and Competitiveness at the Stockholm School of Economics, which started out originally as the European Cluster Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reproducible-research&#34;&gt;Reproducible research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that a modern data observatory should be as much reproducible and automated as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Following reproducible research principles leads to higher data quality, especially if it is based on open-source code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reproducible data can be automatically documented, which makes teamwork, collaboration and instant use far more efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reproducible research products offer far more efficient supervision and audit.  Quality control is cheaper and easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-open-data-open-collaboration&#34;&gt;Open source, open data, open collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the EU, open data is governed by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=1561563110433&amp;amp;uri=CELEX:32019L1024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Directive on open data and the re-use of public sector information - in short: Open Data Directive (EU) 2019 / 1024&lt;/a&gt;. It entered into force on 16 July 2019. It replaces the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/ALL/?uri=CELEX:32003L0098&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Public Sector Information Directive&lt;/a&gt;, also known as the ‘PSI Directive’ which dated from 2003 and was subsequently amended in 2013. The public sector offers tens of billions&amp;rsquo; euro worth data &amp;mdash; but without a free lunch.  While the data is available free or at marginal cost, it is processed to the needs of public authorities, public services, and require special know-how to be put to a secondary business or research use. Our founder, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/author/daniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt;, has been involved in Open Data and PSI since 2003. Our expertise guarrantee that in the field of economics, finance, social sciences, and most policy areas your observatory starts with hundreds, or even thousands of re-used public sector indicators, often with a decade-long or even longer history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the open source 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=R_%28programming_language%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;statistical programming language R&lt;/a&gt;, and various open source R programs.  We also release some of our mission-critical code developed to create business and policy indicators &amp;mdash; see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/publication/eurobarometer_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/publication/iotables_2018/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iotables&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://satellitereport.com/publication/regions_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://retroharmonize.satellitereport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt;. Our important code goes through anonymous peer-review, and open for external review, audit. For example, this allowed us to compare test results on calculating economic impact indicators for the creative industries and other industries with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/articles/united_kingdom_2010.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UK statistical office&lt;/a&gt;. You can even modify our code &amp;ndash; you just cannot copyright and close it for commercial use. In our view, this guarrantees the highest quality, but it also gives assurrances of transparency and makes vendor lock-in impossible. While developing these packages requires our special knowledge, their rich and peer-reviwedd documentation makes sure that you can always find a team member, or hire a data analyst who can work with them without us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of open source software and the open source R statistical language allows a continuous peer-review of data ingestion, processing, corrections and indicator creation by statisticians, data scientists and academics.  Statistical products of national statistical offices, sometimes Eurostat itself, not to mention data providers that are not part of the system of national statistical offices, such as the European Audiovisual Observatory, are plagued with data errors that are corrected and amended relatively slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-integration-instead-of-centralisation&#34;&gt;Data integration instead of centralisation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our observatories by design are flexible and decentralized. Our continuous 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu/index.php?title=Main_Page#Data_Integration&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data integration&lt;/a&gt; allows to join and publish any data the observatory and its member have access to, and have rights and intentions to share or publish. We only keep metadata, i.e. a &amp;lsquo;data map&amp;rsquo; to make sure that whatever the Observatory&amp;rsquo;s members want to share or publish is always automatically available for processing and publication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
