<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>surveys | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>/tag/surveys/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/surveys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>surveys</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>surveys</title>
      <link>/tag/surveys/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Observatory</title>
      <link>/project/music_observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/music_observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most important technical guideline on cultural statistics is the &lt;em&gt;Final Report of the Woking Group European Statistical System Network on Culture&lt;/em&gt; (in short: ESSnet-Culture) [@frank_guy_essnet-culture_2012].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESSnet-Culture gave a thorough overview of cultural data sources, guidelines on standardizing data, and a technical definition of the domain, including an exact mapping of cultural and creative activities and occupations to statistical nomenclatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;icet&#34;&gt;ICET model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultural participation extends beyond the market-oriented forms of &amp;ldquo;cultural consumption&amp;rdquo; and include non-market forms, such as private copying or liturgical events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ESSnet-Culture working group endorsed the ICET model of quantifying cultural participation.   The aim of the ICET model is to create representative surveys, but it is a very good framework to join survey data with other data sources.  For example, the music industry and the audiovisual sector usually has extensive transaction data on most market-oriented activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Information&lt;/em&gt;: to seek, collect and spread information on culture;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communication and community&lt;/em&gt;: to interact with others on cultural issues and to participate in cultural networks;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoyment and expression&lt;/em&gt;: to enjoy exhibitions, art performances and other forms of cultural expression, to practice the arts for leisure, and to create online content;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transaction&lt;/em&gt;: to buy art and to buy or reserve tickets for shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The generic questionnaire was developed by Jos de Haan and Andries van den Broek at the Netherlands Institute for Social Research, originally for extending cultural participation surveys to digital forms of culture [@de_haan_virtuele_2008; @de_haan_nowadays_2012]. This methodology was endorsed by ESSnet-Culture, and a rather detailed guideline can be found in the report of the &lt;em&gt;Task Force on Cultural Practices And Social Aspects Of Culture&lt;/em&gt;, in the ESSNet-Culture technical report (in general: pp. 236-242, survey methodology and harmonization pp. 242-255, recommendations: pp. 273-274; with examples on how to use the question hierarchy on pp. 397-417.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;target-population&#34;&gt;Target Population&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the target population is representative members of the general public, such as in the case of audience surveys, we use 
&lt;a href=&#34;#cap&#34;&gt;CAP&lt;/a&gt; surveys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the target population is a professional or microenterprise group, such as performing artists or record labels, we use our 
&lt;a href=&#34;#professional&#34;&gt;Professional group surveys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap&#34;&gt;CAP surveys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESSnet-Culture has reviewed several pan-European CAP manifestations, and based on the recommendations, further CAP surveys were carried out in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2001: Europeans&amp;rsquo; Participation in Cultural Activities (2001)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEE CAP 2003:  Candidate Countries Eurobarometer 2003.1 New Europeans and Culture, all later EU member states of the EU27, except for Croatia, but including Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2006:  Within the EU-SILC Module 2006 On Social Participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2007:  Includes the EU27 + United Kingdom but not Croatia, Romania and Bulgaria, conducted within Eurobarometer European Cultural Values (2007)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2013: Includes the EU27 + Croatia (only few weeks before the country&amp;rsquo;s accession.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2015: Within the EU-SILC Module 2015 On Social/Cultural Participation And Material Deprivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on these guidelines and examples, we have carried out several in-depth music and audiovisual domain oriented CAP surveys:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2014: a large, but non-representative online sample to test the methodology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2015:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slovakia CAP 2015:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Croatia CAP 2017:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2017:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slovakia CAP 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;professional&#34;&gt;Professional Group Surveys&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Musician Career Paths</title>
      <link>/post/2017-02-03_career_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2017-02-03_career_path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the 20th century the first career step was to get on stage and create a credible live performance. After several years on the stage musician’s got a recording contract, and usually even later they registered their first composition. The recording stream was the most important revenue source. The making of a record was expensive and offered considerable royalties or advances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century the live music stream is far more important than the recordings. Creating recordings is much cheaper and stage performances are expensive. Musicians usually create their music, also register it as a music work and offer it to the public on an online portfolio of mp3 downloads, YouTube and music streams.  Often they are booked for their first live performance after publishing a recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean for the musician and the manager?  First and foremost that traditional career development strategies do not work anymore. A convincing stage performance is mandatory with a good touring strategy.  Recordings are often not profitable, but equally important in building the audience. Making the recording stream a revenue stream instead of the cost stream requires a very good understanding of the costs and benefits of the different digital channels. CEEMID also contains market information on these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Career information in CEEMID&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Milestones of the musician’s career&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Level of professionalization, secondary career paths&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Income level and basic live standards information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production and concert volumes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revenue breakup in all the three major income streams, i.e. publishing, recording and live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is available for Croatia, Hungary and Slovakia. Breakup by genre, gender, birth year, age cohort, capital  / countryside is also possible.  Similar surveys are being conducted in the film production industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
