<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>surveys | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/surveys/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/surveys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>surveys</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>surveys</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/surveys/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Observatory</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data is power, and &lt;code&gt;big data creates injustice&lt;/code&gt;.  Organizations that control large amounts of data, for example, the entire listening history of hundreds of millions of people in all major countries of the world, can train algorithms and robots that drive most of the music in the world.  They can make your investment into a sound recording successful or doomed. They can circumvent or help a local content regulation, reinforce, or disable a national cultural policy goal.  A country may introduce national artist quotas on radio, if all the youth will be personally recommended foreign songs in their music discovery age in the very same country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;We want big data to work for small venues, independent labels, startups, great and undiscovered artists.&lt;/code&gt; We believe that you cannot make a successful album launch, a market entry or introduce a successful cultural policy without large amounts of well processed and correctly analysed data. We want to create a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; that integrates the small data of many small bands, small labels, small venues, small countries, and mount correct the injustice. Make algorithms transparent and the competition fair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020 most of the data is proprietary to a few, U.S.-based companies, while most of the paying audience is the European Union. This year, many European governments started to challenge the competition conditions. The tide is turning, and we do not see this as an EU-US rivalry, because many players of the American music industry share all the pains of the European music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; in September 2020 and got into the presitgious 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. Our demo observatory is an example how we believe the European Data Observatory should be built. An observatory is a permanent observation point for social and economic data. We want to prove that this process can be made cost-effectively and efficiently, providing a high-quality, valuable and timely product by employing best practices in research automation and open source software, using open data in open collaboration with the music industry, artists, technicians and managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to support the European music industry and our friends in North America, Australia, and all over the world to turn the tables with @ref(innovation) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/innovation.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;innovation&lt;/a&gt; coming from the open source community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to help you to create alternative recommendation engines that actually recommend songs from your country, and we want to give you very clear export market targets with the help of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/innovation.html#ai&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AI&lt;/a&gt;. Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local Initiative&lt;/a&gt; is aiming to create recommendation engines for cities and regions, and make sure that local bands are recommended to local audiences and audiences in the regions where they will be touring after the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want your evidence to stand a fighting chance against large teams of professional legal and economics teams on the other side with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/innovation.html#valuation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;proper valuations and damage claims&lt;/a&gt;.  And we want to present all those hundreds and thousands of pages automatically, going through dozens and dozens of automated &amp;ldquo;unit-tests&amp;rdquo; until nobody can find errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want you to be able to prove to your fans, the press, your economy minister that music in many countries has not been at the mercy of the taxpayer, but has been carrying far heavier tax burdens than manufacturers.  We want to make your case that the music industry plays a vital role in the European economic recovery and job creation, because we can create 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/innovation.html#valuation#eia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;economic impact assessments&lt;/a&gt; on GDP, employment, tax, import and export effects automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because music and culture are often managed at the level of cities, regions and communities, we want to give you all the data on sub-national levels, whether for regions, metropolitan areas or smaller divisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why we are launching now or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; and soon its twin, the Creative and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ccs.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cultural Sectors Demo Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, because video producers, book authors, magazine publishers, film distributors and public broadcasters are sharing the pains of the music industry. We believe that the tides are turning because both regulators and these industries have started to fight back, and there is an awful lot of value, money and creativity is at stake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; The &lt;code&gt;European Music Observatory&lt;/code&gt; should fully exploit the EU&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;open data&lt;/strong&gt; regime. (See our examples: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;our first open data release&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; It should be transparent, the indicator design should be based on open-source statistical software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; The European Music Observatory must embrace evidence-based 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/approach.html#opa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;open Policy Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; The observatory must allow a seamless 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/approach.html#dataintegration&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data integration&lt;/a&gt; between open data, and highly confidential proprietary data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; The open collaboration principle must allow an easy opt-in and opt-out for small and larger, public and private organizations, and offer for full transparency for all users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; It should not re-collect data that already exists. Instead it should create policies, synergies and incentives that bring that data to light.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Musician Career Paths</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-02-03-music_career_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2017-02-03-music_career_path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the 20th century the first career step was to get on stage and create a credible live performance. After several years on the stage musician’s got a recording contract, and usually even later they registered their first composition. The recording stream was the most important revenue source. The making of a record was expensive and offered considerable royalties or advances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century the live music stream is far more important than the recordings. Creating recordings is much cheaper and stage performances are expensive. Musicians usually create their music, also register it as a music work and offer it to the public on an online portfolio of mp3 downloads, YouTube and music streams.  Often they are booked for their first live performance after publishing a recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean for the musician and the manager?  First and foremost that traditional career development strategies do not work anymore. A convincing stage performance is mandatory with a good touring strategy.  Recordings are often not profitable, but equally important in building the audience. Making the recording stream a revenue stream instead of the cost stream requires a very good understanding of the costs and benefits of the different digital channels. CEEMID also contains market information on these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Career information in CEEMID&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Milestones of the musician’s career&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Level of professionalization, secondary career paths&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Income level and basic live standards information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production and concert volumes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revenue breakup in all the three major income streams, i.e. publishing, recording and live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is available for Croatia, Hungary and Slovakia. Breakup by genre, gender, birth year, age cohort, capital  / countryside is also possible.  Similar surveys are being conducted in the film production industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
