<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Listen Local | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Listen Local</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dataandlyrics.com/media/icon_hu5bfde8608118b47b475864b70fd224b4_21674_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Listen Local</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;I lived in the mountains for six years, and I loved it because it was a place where you needed to rely on yourself to survive.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-15-marie_de_la_montagne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-15-marie_de_la_montagne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- HERE I WOULD INCLUDE A BREIF INTRODUCTION ABOUT WHO MARIE IS AND WHY WE&#39;RE INTERVIEWING HER
Please go ahead and extend it

--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marie works in Prague, and helps musicians&amp;rsquo; careers, particularly in TV and feature film synchronization.  She is also a performing artists, whose music is connected to different parts of Europe. We interviewed her because of our shared interest in how music crosses borders.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, you&amp;rsquo;re currently living in Prague, after spending several years located in France, London, and Berlin. What was this journey like for you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got locked down in Prague actually. I intended to move to Berlin after leaving London, as my pianist lives there and has kids. It seemed like the best next destination, but it just didn’t work out. Lockdown came out of the blue and I decided to stay in Czech Republic. I eventually found an apartment in Prague and a job I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do all my life, so I think this is it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now work for a label and I am in charge of our sync &amp;amp; publishing department. My professional focus is still abroad for the most part which helps me work towards my ambitions, yet also come back to my roots. I feel like this is what I really needed for my creativity to strive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- HERE I WOULD INCLUDE A BREIF INTRODUCTION ABOUT WHO MARIE IS AND WHY WE&#39;RE INTERVIEWING HER--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where would you like to find an audience for your music?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a great question, one that is hard to answer in my case since I am local in several places. I would say that because my songs are in English and draw inspiration from Irish and British folk music - I started writing when I found Lisa Hannigan and her melody based songs - they will resonate with people in these territories more than they probably will in Czechia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider myself a storyteller. My music is a space to communicate emotions about experiences we might not always talk about. I love performing live and I can see myself doing this anywhere, but mostly in Europe. I feel very close to all the countries I’ve lived in, so France and even the UK. I always build a small fanbase where I live, and then uproot again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  This is the script to include a jpg or png file.  If it is large, it will be ready for zooming in. --&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-marie-on-stage&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/listen_local_interviews/Marie_de_la_Montagne_with_band.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Marie on stage&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Marie on stage
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to spend more time in Central and Eastern Europe too. I feel like I neglected these countries and quite unfairly so. This has been a challenge as touring is always an expense, and since I collaborate with a pianist who has two children, there are practical aspects that I have to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I am not performing much these days. I channeled all my passion for it into my work with other artists and have been a booker, a manager, a filmmaker, a producer, an event organiser, and just kept on learning about the industry whilst swimming in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen Local tries to connect local musicians with local music. Can we say that you are looking for audiences that can be reached from Berlin and Prague, so Western Czechia and the Southeastern part of Germany? Our app is designed to find out where you music mind find audience, and for music lovers, to find artists who are close enough  to visit on a small venue gig.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you could say this is the territory where I would like people to listen to my music. I released my songs which were recorded eight years after we wrote them. Spotify became more dominant in release strategy and I had very little understanding of how it worked, what to pay attention to and how much time goes into release planning. I just decided to put the songs up, and let them live their own life. Now that I know much more about digital, I want to be more intentional about the songs I put out and how I do it. I love visual expression, I love collaboration, and I feel that the spaces I choose to live in &amp;ndash; which I choose because they are beautiful &amp;ndash; play an important role in this. I want to tell the story of how everything lead to where I am now. I always figured it was important to highlight small artist locally and where they performed so that audiences could connect with them and follow them long after, so what you are doing is great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  This code is copy pasted from Spotify.  You can adjust the height to look better.  --&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/artist/7qkfyK1GehyVxF42lDhO5V&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;433&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Having moved around, what do you consider home, in a spiritual or physical sense?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France is really my sacred place. It is a place where I feel insanely inspired and at home. Even from miles away, it gives me a sense of confidence and freedom. I lived in the mountains for six years, and I loved it because it was a place where you needed to rely on yourself to survive. There is no industry there so anything I wanted to exist, I had to create everything myself. And that was amazing, because I proved to myself that I could do anything I decided to. When you are in a city, you always have to ask permissions. As a woman in this industry, no one listens to you. You have to work triple hard for people to let you say or do something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come back to the mountains for consolation, really. I even changed my French surname to mean “from the mountains,” as a way for people to stop focusing on where I am from and more on what I do. It worked, and I became Marie De La Montagne. I identified with that name so much, I had a hard time using my civil surname in my professional life when I became a publisher. Me and my colleague had a lot of laughs about it. It just seemed so strange to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other source of inspiration in music is in America. A lot of people might judge me for saying that, but America doesn’t do what I  mentioned above. I don’t feel so smothered when I work with my American colleagues. When I started to work with supervisors and people around the entertainment industry, I saw new potential, and my storytelling side resonated there. So I aligned myself at that, and wish to connect all these places creatively and also use the opportunities they offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you recommend some music from the region of France where you feel at home? Or some music from the US that inspired you much recently? We are interested in how musical inspiration comes to our artists, physically. We want to understand how music travels via word of mouth, algorithms, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can point you to a few artists that I met and find so inspiring. Definitely Amistat, a twin duo who have Czech roots, lived in Australia, and now live in Germany. We worked together for about two years, and I could listen to their song Love &amp;amp; Light on repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  This code is copy pasted from YouTube.  You can adjust the height to look better.  --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;395&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JcaOd1mSPYo&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also love &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0pylMlxf_0jE256FLv9ZMg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dirt Miller&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8dfUJJ-3op3B5wF5uono0w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lauren Ruth Ward&lt;/a&gt;, both of whom I met in Los Angeles, and I think that they are geniuses. Their songwriting, their social media artistry, and their vocals are mad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  Please add links similarly  --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many artists in Prague who have their own approach to songwriting and I am a huge fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqMfd-lCgyHkd2EYbjwaxDA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Aiko’s&lt;/a&gt;. I love Bookie Baker, especially when they play live. Karel Havlíček who just released a neoclassical album Spoken is someone who inspires me so much with his understanding of being an artist. Out of the artists I met whilst I was in France - check out Jake Morley, Nyna Loren, Fionnuala McKenna, Rob Longstaff, The Pedestrians&amp;hellip; so many great artists! Many of these artists came with us on tour which we filmed, so you can check out the videos we made online as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  This code is copy pasted from YouTube.  You can adjust the height to look better.  --&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;395&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yATAUcdvLHY&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are currently not performing much, instead you are helping other artists.  What is your day job?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My day job now is building a sync &amp;amp; publishing company under a big independent label, which isn’t an easy task and exactly what I love about it. I need to have these big projects that build on the values I mentioned above. We offer all kinds of deals which evolve around artist development. My main focus is synchronization in TV and film, though mostly not in the Czech market. The industry here is not as standardized as it is abroad, and as you probably know through your research, this comes at a great disadvantage for the artists. I want to challenge that, as I feel like music is universal, and the industry is a tool not a master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In your work supporting artists, do you ever use data to help them find an audience?  What are your challenges?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yes! Data are my daily companion. But the challenges are everywhere, starting with artists not even knowing that they need data and what for. And clearing data is incredibly timeconsuming. I keep striving to find ways to understand the insides of the industry better using data so I can compensate for the disadvantages that the Czech market faces by default - language, historical disconnection from the markets around, the small size of the market, and so on. I also know a few people who are very passionate about this topic and new trends in music, in legal, in digital… There are so many ways you can look at this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We really would need more time to talk :)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-about-marie-de-la-montagne&#34;&gt;More about Marie de la Montagne&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find more of about Marie and her work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/mariedelamontagne/?hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt; or her &lt;a href=&#34;https://mariedelamontagne.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and make sure to check out her music!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other artists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Kestner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Duka Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katarzia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-18-where-they-understand-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twentees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Youniverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-04-04-wdekrey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Willemijn de Krey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a label:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tiny Rooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New spotifyr R Package Release</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-17-spotifyr-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 08:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-17-spotifyr-release/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-package-is-an-excellent-starting-to-point-for-r-newbies-to-try-their-hands-on-musicology-analysis-with-a-few-keystrokes-and-of-course-it-is-an-essential-part-of-the-research-infrastructure-of-musicology-worldwide-in-far-more-advanced-applications&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;The package is an excellent starting to point for R newbies to try their hands on musicology analysis with a few keystrokes. And of course, it is an essential part of the research infrastructure of musicology worldwide in far more advanced applications.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/package_screenshots/spotifyr_221_hu756aa7a710bb095433c01a81b33d0d4d_104282_528a72351dde9507786f5c61b240b54f.webp 400w,
               /media/img/package_screenshots/spotifyr_221_hu756aa7a710bb095433c01a81b33d0d4d_104282_912383f38b4aab9eaf611804ae266cf6.webp 760w,
               /media/img/package_screenshots/spotifyr_221_hu756aa7a710bb095433c01a81b33d0d4d_104282_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/package_screenshots/spotifyr_221_hu756aa7a710bb095433c01a81b33d0d4d_104282_528a72351dde9507786f5c61b240b54f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;378&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      The package is an excellent starting to point for R newbies to try their hands on musicology analysis with a few keystrokes. And of course, it is an essential part of the research infrastructure of musicology worldwide in far more advanced applications.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a very long-time user of Charlie Thomson’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/charlie86/spotifyr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;spotifyr R package&lt;/a&gt;, which is probably the most used open-source music analytics software in the world.  It provides programmatic access to the Spotify Web API, which contains access to the former Echo Nest quantitative musicology engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is an essential part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory’s&lt;/a&gt; streaming analysis and our &lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; apps designed for our trustworthy AI experiments and independent artist services.  I am extremely proud to announce that after a very thorough modernization of the package’s exception handling, documentation, and code dependencies that I did in the last week, the package has passed again the peer-review standards and it is back on CRAN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The package is an excellent starting to point for R newbies to try their hands on musicology analysis with a few keystrokes. And of course, it is an essential part of the research infrastructure of musicology worldwide in far more advanced applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should start with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/charlie86/spotifyr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; and get your Spotify Web API access tokens to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-was-the-beatles-favorite-key&#34;&gt;What Was the Beatles&amp;rsquo; Favorite Key?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34; data-lang=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;spotifyr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;beatles&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;get_artist_audio_features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;the beatles&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34; data-lang=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;dplyr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;purrr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;knitr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;beatles&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;key_mode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;sort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;TRUE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;kable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;key_mode&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;n&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;C major&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;D major&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;98&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;G major&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;A major&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;E major&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-your-most-recently-played-tracks&#34;&gt;Get your most recently played tracks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34; data-lang=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;lubridate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;get_my_recently_played&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;limit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;mutate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;        &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;artist.name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;map_chr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;track.artists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;name[1]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;        &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;played_at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;as_datetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;played_at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;        &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;all_of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;track.name&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;artist.name&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;track.album.name&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;played_at&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;kable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;track.name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;artist.name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;track.album.name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;played_at&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;A Case of You&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Tristen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;A Case of You&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2021-06-14 09:54:44&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Paper Cup&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Real Estate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Paper Cup&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2021-06-10 20:20:11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Wrong with You&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Tristen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Wrong with You&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2021-06-10 20:17:24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Animal - Edit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;LUMP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Animal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2021-06-10 20:13:21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Streets Of Your Town&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;DOPE LEMON&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Streets Of Your Town&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2021-06-10 18:23:00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s about right&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;find-your-all-time-favorite-artists&#34;&gt;Find Your All Time Favorite Artists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34; data-lang=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;get_my_top_artists_or_tracks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;artists&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;                             &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;time_range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;long_term&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;                             &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;limit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;.data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;.data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;genres&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;rowwise&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;mutate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;genres&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;paste&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;.data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;genres&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;collapse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;ungroup&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;kable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;genres&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Japanese Breakfast&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;art pop, bubblegrunge, eugene indie, indie pop, indie rock, philly indie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Haley Bonar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;melancholia, stomp and holler&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Balthazar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;belgian indie, belgian rock, dutch indie, dutch rock, ghent indie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Buildings Breeding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;indie fuzzpop&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Angus &amp;amp; Julia Stone&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;australian indie folk, indie folk, stomp and holler&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What could I say?  I travelled Australia listening only to Angus &amp;amp; Julia Stone, the Buildings Breeding have been with me since I discovered them on my first iPod, in one of the first podcasts, the Indiefeed. I created my Kickstarter account back in 2010 to support Haley Bonar&amp;rsquo;s third album. And the year before I was very much into Japanese Breakfast and Balthazar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;find-your-favorite-tracks-at-the-moment&#34;&gt;Find your favorite tracks at the moment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34; data-lang=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;get_my_top_artists_or_tracks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;tracks&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;                             &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;time_range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;short_term&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;                             &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;limit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;mutate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;        &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;artist.name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;map_chr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;artists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;name[1]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;        &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;artist.name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;album.name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;kable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;artist.name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;album.name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Hot &amp;amp; Heavy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Lucy Dacus&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Hot &amp;amp; Heavy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Sea Urchin&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Mystic Braves&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Sea Urchin&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Human&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Freedom Fry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Human&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Hot Motion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Temples&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Hot Motion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Animal - Edit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;LUMP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Animal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-the-most-joyful-joy-division-song&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the most joyful Joy Division song?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the audio feature has to be &lt;code&gt;valence&lt;/code&gt;, a measure of musical
positivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34; data-lang=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;joy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;get_artist_audio_features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;joy division&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34; data-lang=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;joy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;arrange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;valence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;.data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;track_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;.data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;valence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&amp;gt;%&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;kable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;track_name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;valence&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Passover - 2020 Digital Master&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;0.946&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Passover - 2007 Remaster&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;0.941&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Colony - 2020 Digital Master&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;0.829&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Colony - 2007 Remaster&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;0.808&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Atrocity Exhibition - 2020 Digital Master&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;0.790&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if only there was some way to plot joy…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;joyplot-of-the-emotional-rollercoasters-that-are-joy-divisions-albums&#34;&gt;Joyplot of the emotional rollercoasters that are Joy Division&amp;rsquo;s albums&lt;/h3&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-joyplot-of-the-emotional-rollercoasters-that-are-joy-divisions-albums&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Joyplot of the emotional rollercoasters that are Joy Division&amp;#39;s albums&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/README-joyplot-1_hub1d2cca691cf234d2fdbd76f39ba5520_11313_77380d4e5febb74252396d950d237a82.webp 400w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/README-joyplot-1_hub1d2cca691cf234d2fdbd76f39ba5520_11313_0677efa08188bf3d74083af2379326d7.webp 760w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/README-joyplot-1_hub1d2cca691cf234d2fdbd76f39ba5520_11313_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/blogposts_2021/README-joyplot-1_hub1d2cca691cf234d2fdbd76f39ba5520_11313_77380d4e5febb74252396d950d237a82.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;672&#34;
               height=&#34;480&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Joyplot of the emotional rollercoasters that are Joy Division&amp;rsquo;s albums
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentify-a-shiny-app&#34;&gt;Sentify: A Shiny app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://rcharlie.net/sentify/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;app&lt;/a&gt;, powered by spotifyr, allows
you to visualize the energy and valence (musical positivity) of all of
Spotify&amp;rsquo;s artists and playlists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dope-stuff-other-people-have-done-with-spotifyr&#34;&gt;Dope Stuff Other People Have Done with spotifyr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coolest thing about making this package has definitely been seeing
all the awesome stuff other people have done with it. Here are a few
examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://msmith7161.github.io/what-is-speechiness/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Exploring the Spotify API with R: A tutorial for beginners, by a beginner&lt;/a&gt;, Mia Smith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://caitlinhudon.com/2017/12/22/blue-christmas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blue Christmas: A data-driven search for the most depressing Christmas song&lt;/a&gt;, Caitlin
Hudon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rr.sapo.pt/especial/112355/sente-se-triste-quando-ouve-amar-pelos-dois-nao-e-o-unico&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sente-se triste quando ouve “Amar pelos dois”? Não é o único (Do you feel sad when you hear “Love for both?” You’re not alone)&lt;/a&gt;,
Rui Barros, Rádio Renascença&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/angriest-death-grips-data-anger-502168c1c2f0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Using Data to Find the Angriest Death Grips Song&lt;/a&gt;,
Evan Oppenheimer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/WireMonkey/status/1009915034246565891?s=19&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hierarchical clustering of David Bowie records&lt;/a&gt;,
Alyssa Goldberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@simranvatsa5/taylor-f656e2a09cc3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tayloR&lt;/a&gt;, Simran
Vatsa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-work-with-spotifyr&#34;&gt;Our Work with spotifyR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-08-teach-learning-machines/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Trustworthy AI: Check Where the Machine Learning Algorithm is Learning From&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-05-16-recommendation-outcomes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recommendation Systems: What can Go Wrong with the Algorithm?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-25-listen-slovak/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Feasibility Study On Promoting Slovak Music In Slovakia &amp;amp; Abroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify: Popular Music That Nobody Listens To&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key mission of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, which is our modern, subjective approach on how the future European Music Observatory should look like, is to not only to provide high-quality data on the music economy, the diversity of music, and the audience of music, but also on metadata.  The quality and availability, interoperability of metadata (information about how the data should be used) is key to build trustworthy AI systems. We rely on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/charlie86/spotifyr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;spotifyr&lt;/a&gt; to fulfil this mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join our open collaboration Music Data Observatory team as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/authors/curator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data curator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/authors/developer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;developer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/authors/team&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;business developer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trustworthy AI: Check Where the Machine Learning Algorithm is Learning From</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-08-teach-learning-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-06-08-teach-learning-machines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We do care what our children learn, but we do not care yet about what our robots learn from.  One key idea behind trustworthy AI is that you verify what data sources your machine learning algorithms can learn from.  As we have emphasised in our forthcoming academic paper and in our experiments, one key problem that goes wrong when you see too few small country artists, or too few womxn in the charts is that the big tech recommendation systems and other autonomous systems are learning from historically biased or patchy data.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-this-is-precisely-the-type-of-work-we-are-doing-with-the-continued-support-of-the-slovak-national-rightsholder-organizations--in-our-work-in-slovakiahttpsdataandlyricscompublicationlisten_local_2020-we-reverse-engineered-some-of-these-undesirable-outcomes-our-slovak-musicologist-data-curator-dominika-semaňákováhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeuauthordominika-semanakova-explains-how--we-want-to-teach-machine-learning-algorithms-to-learn-more-about-slovak-musichttpsmusicdataobservatoryeupost2021-06-08-introducing-dominika-semanakova-in-her-introductory-interview&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;This is precisely the type of work we are doing with the continued support of the Slovak national rightsholder organizations.  In our [work in Slovakia](https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/listen_local_2020/), we reverse engineered some of these undesirable outcomes. Our Slovak musicologist data curator, [Dominika Semaňáková](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/dominika-semanakova/) explains how  [we want to teach machine learning algorithms to learn more about Slovak music](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-08-introducing-dominika-semanakova/) in her introductory interview.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/listen_local_screenshots/Youniverse_energy_hu4f2585c454c25b089f67461e52617e29_136682_7c765b69752cfbc75521482ab5ee68ec.webp 400w,
               /media/img/listen_local_screenshots/Youniverse_energy_hu4f2585c454c25b089f67461e52617e29_136682_9a395d452e1fc7d4737b0e41de8fa33d.webp 760w,
               /media/img/listen_local_screenshots/Youniverse_energy_hu4f2585c454c25b089f67461e52617e29_136682_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/listen_local_screenshots/Youniverse_energy_hu4f2585c454c25b089f67461e52617e29_136682_7c765b69752cfbc75521482ab5ee68ec.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      This is precisely the type of work we are doing with the continued support of the Slovak national rightsholder organizations.  In our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/listen_local_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;work in Slovakia&lt;/a&gt;, we reverse engineered some of these undesirable outcomes. Our Slovak musicologist data curator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/dominika-semanakova/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dominika Semaňáková&lt;/a&gt; explains how  &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-08-introducing-dominika-semanakova/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;we want to teach machine learning algorithms to learn more about Slovak music&lt;/a&gt; in her introductory interview.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key mission of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, which is our modern, subjective approach on how the future European Music Observatory should look like, is to not only to provide high-quality data on the music economy, the diversity of music, and the audience of music, but also on metadata.  The quality and availability, interoperability of metadata (information about how the data should be used) is key to build trustworthy AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Traitors in a war used to be executed by firing squad, and it was a psychologically burdensome task for soldiers to have to shoot former comrades. When a 10-marksman squad fired 8 blank and 2 live ammunition, the traitor would be 100% dead, and the soldiers firing would walk away with a semblance of consolation in the fact they had an 80% chance of not having been the one that killed a former comrade. This is a textbook example of assigning responsibility and blame in systems. AI-driven systems such as the YouTube or Spotify recommendation systems, the shelf organization of Amazon books, or the workings of a stock photo agency come together through complex processes, and when they produce undesirable results, or, on the contrary, they improve life, it is difficult to assign blame or credit [..] If you do not see enough women on streaming charts, or if you think that the percentage of European films on your favorite streaming provider—or Slovak music on your music streaming service—is too low, you have to be able to distribute the blame in more precise terms than just saying “it’s the system” that is stacked up against women, small countries, or other groups. We need to be able to point the blame more precisely in order to effect change through economic incentives or legal constraints.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-assigning-and-avoding-blame-read-the-earlier-blogpost-herepost2021-05-16-recommendation-outcomes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Assigning and avoding blame, read the earlier blogpost [here](/post/2021-05-16-recommendation-outcomes/).&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide2_hu444ed0a45545f5668012a4d51e6acf8a_1120947_ff8528f59401a8d463e2afdf88286ed7.webp 400w,
               /media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide2_hu444ed0a45545f5668012a4d51e6acf8a_1120947_80deb6cac8b4b561d3489a601eeafd61.webp 760w,
               /media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide2_hu444ed0a45545f5668012a4d51e6acf8a_1120947_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide2_hu444ed0a45545f5668012a4d51e6acf8a_1120947_ff8528f59401a8d463e2afdf88286ed7.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Assigning and avoding blame, read the earlier blogpost &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-05-16-recommendation-outcomes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is precisely the type of work we are doing with the continued support of the Slovak national rightsholder organizations.  In our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/listen_local_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;work in Slovakia&lt;/a&gt;, we reverse engineered some of these undesirable outcomes. Popular video and music streaming recommendation systems have at least three major components based on machine learning. The problem is usually not that an algorithm is nasty and malicious; algorithms are often trained through “machine learning” techniques, and often, machines “learn” from biased, faulty, or low-quality information. Our Slovak musicologist data curator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/dominika-semanakova/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dominika Semaňáková&lt;/a&gt; explains how  &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-08-introducing-dominika-semanakova/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;we want to teach machine learning algorithms to learn more about Slovak music&lt;/a&gt; in her introductory interview.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-read-more-about-our-slovak-music-use-case-herehttpsdataandlyricscompublicationlisten_local_2020&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Read more about our Slovak music use case [here](https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/listen_local_2020/).&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide4_hu76b1600a6ecf427b872176cae2af70d3_524585_6bbbb8d83ce2f88949d3ca7ff8e91d0a.webp 400w,
               /media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide4_hu76b1600a6ecf427b872176cae2af70d3_524585_e74dc6fadfe697a82d9fbc4bb308ed70.webp 760w,
               /media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide4_hu76b1600a6ecf427b872176cae2af70d3_524585_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide4_hu76b1600a6ecf427b872176cae2af70d3_524585_6bbbb8d83ce2f88949d3ca7ff8e91d0a.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Read more about our Slovak music use case &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/listen_local_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These undesirable outcomes are sometimes illegal as they may go against non-discrimination or competition law. (See our ideas on what can go wrong &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/music_level_playing_field_2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?&lt;/a&gt;) They may undermine national or EU-level cultural policy goals, media regulation, child protection rules, and fundamental rights protection against discrimination without basis. They may make Slovak artists earn significantly less than American artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/european_visibilitiy_2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;In our academic (pre-print) paper&lt;/a&gt; we argue for new regulatory considerations to create a better, and more accountable playing field for deploying algorithms in a quasi-autonomous system, and we suggest further research to align economic incentives with the creation of higher quality and less biased metadata. The need for further research on how these large systems affect various fundamental rights, consumer or competition rights, or cultural and media policy goals cannot be overstated.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-incentives-and-investments-into-metadata&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Incentives and investments into metadata&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide5_hu1d77393ea7616f41db3a779a59b4dc05_744762_8f8b77ccf98873f0d723f8a0af4cb28d.webp 400w,
               /media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide5_hu1d77393ea7616f41db3a779a59b4dc05_744762_2ef2beef59b8f70801191a91cdd0b0a8.webp 760w,
               /media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide5_hu1d77393ea7616f41db3a779a59b4dc05_744762_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/presentations/D_Antal_IVIR_Webinar_2021-05-06/Slide5_hu1d77393ea7616f41db3a779a59b4dc05_744762_8f8b77ccf98873f0d723f8a0af4cb28d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Incentives and investments into metadata
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to open and understand these autonomous systems, and this is our mission with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;: it is a fully automated, open source, open data observatory that links public datasets in order to provide a comprehensive view of the European music industry. It produces key business and policy indicators, and research experiment data following the data pillars laid out in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-11-16-european-music-observatory-feasibility/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Feasibility study for the establishment of a European Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-join-our-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-as-a-user-curator-developer-or-help-building-our-business-case&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Join our [Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) as a user, curator, developer or help building our business case.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen_hu92ab229c45ce6811fae4daab656e9cd8_255495_ec85a96366983581855edd8646628bea.webp 400w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen_hu92ab229c45ce6811fae4daab656e9cd8_255495_f956c0ab61fc958984be8487ab6a3eee.webp 760w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen_hu92ab229c45ce6811fae4daab656e9cd8_255495_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/observatory_screenshots/dmo_opening_screen_hu92ab229c45ce6811fae4daab656e9cd8_255495_ec85a96366983581855edd8646628bea.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;395&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Join our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; as a user, curator, developer or help building our business case.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join our open collaboration Music Data Observatory team as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/authors/curator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data curator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/authors/developer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;developer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/authors/team&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;business developer&lt;/a&gt;. More interested in antitrust, innovation policy or economic impact analysis? Try our &lt;a href=&#34;https://economy.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Economy Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; team! Or your interest lies more in climate change, mitigation or climate action? Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/#contributors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Green Deal Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; team!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-more-on-data--lyrics&#34;&gt;Read More on Data &amp;amp; Lyrics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-05-16-recommendation-outcomes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recommendation Systems: What can Go Wrong with the Algorithm?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-04-27-smdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Upgrading the Slovak Music Database: New Data API, New Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-04-14-bandcamp-librarian-2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Working With Localities and Location Tags&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-25-listen-slovak/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Feasibility Study On Promoting Slovak Music In Slovakia &amp;amp; Abroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local: Why We Need Alternative Recommendation Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Racist Music Algorithm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Speak About Music in the Digital Age from Taxonomies to Folksonomies</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the dawn of the digital age we have experienced an unprecedented proliferation of music tied to the emergence of digital tools and media channels that accelerate its production and dissemination. Music streaming platforms like Spotify, media platforms like YouTube, or alternative sales platforms like &lt;a href=&#34;https://bandcamp.com/tags&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; make around 100 million songs available worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a conservative viewpoint the fact that everything is readily exposed to us (i.e. the flooding of content) can be seen as degrading to the cultural experience; conversely, one can celebrate the growth of free digital culture, where music production and promotion is tied to less constrains, and musical experience is enriched by blogs, podcasts and other music promotion services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not need to take sides, but we might agree that the digital explosion does not equate to instant access to relevant content — in certain cases it may trigger the opposite effect. There is so much music out there, with so many releases every week, that even professional users like radio editors, DJs or curators face challenges staying up to date. For the audience, this is even more challenging, and therefore all these platforms rely on some form of AI to make personalized recommendations or to automate the categorization of music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music might have a universal language, but finding music is rooted in natural languages, and users rely on simple verbal identifiers like genre labels. According to their broad &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tagg.org/others/ffabbri9907.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;definition&lt;/a&gt;, musical genres emerge as names to define similarities that identify musical events for the members of a community. These labels aid orientation within the sonic landscape, and make it easier for humans to give recommendations in a human conversation — and they are attached to extra-musical activities, too, because music is a social activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One goes to a concert and meets like-minded people, or at least there is a sense of togetherness triggered by a shared appreciation of the music. Music events are embedded into socio-cultural contexts that may prescribe forms of belonging, dress and behaviour codes, and are prone to economic regulation. Within popular music studies a range of concepts have been developed to grasp such communities, such as subcultures, neo-tribes or music scenes. One must take into account the multitude of sometimes overlapping subgenres and their varying interpretations by music lovers, which makes categorization even harder. More generic genre descriptions, like “rock” or “punk”, may sound straightforward and less confusing, but they are also less useful for uncovering complexities and nuances. More specific categories, like “darkwave” or “cold wave”, are more practical in this regard, but may sound pretty obscure or even esoteric to a non-specialist audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music tech companies that support labels, A&amp;amp;R, music supervisors, DJs, radio editors, music journalists, and the entire music and entertainment industry, attempt to cut through the turmoil of genre labels by providing (and improving) relatively detailed taxonomies, or well-designed labels that help both humans and AI-powered robots to find and connect to music. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.beatport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Beatport&lt;/a&gt;, for example, is focused exclusively on electronic dance music, distributing its catalogue into 33 subgenres (as of Jan 2021, and counting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Beatport’s subgenre categories are not carved in stone. Particularly in electronic dance music, a meta-genre featuring &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.ishkur.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a very high number of subgenres&lt;/a&gt;, such labels are often contested, and when it comes to niche genres, bottom-up, free tagging systems or &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vanderwal.net/folksonomy.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;folksonomies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; may better capture diversity and creativity, although they are less exact by their nature. These tags are rooted in the authentic, verbal descriptions of artists and promoters, and may refer to affective qualities and localities or express free associations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The abundance of subgenres is a hallmark of not only electronic dance music, but also of various indie, hip-hop, jazz or other music that has lively scenes and active, emerging artists. Within electronic dance music, scholars attribute it to various factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subgenre naming can be part of a merchandising strategy, related to a top-down model of genre categorization, where taxonomies are established by vendors or industry representatives such as Beatport. It may also reflect socially accepted musical qualities and innovations; folksonomies, by their nature, are at the forefront of such stylistic innovations. Folksonomies are also supported by certain independent music promotion and marketing websites. Bandcamp, for example, is seen as a reputable platform within the indie music community, and it also provides tagging possibilities for its artists and labels. In certain cases, such tags may offer a refreshing contrast to Beatport’s genre categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a cultural anthropologist, I have been involved in the study of alternative electronic dance music communities and event-based cultures; as is often the case, this interest has permeated into my personal life. Consequently, I have first hand experience of grassroots artists resisting classification to their music on the grounds that such labels are narrow and limiting — especially when they are defined by major industry vendors. At the same time, such categories provide basic orientation within a kaleidoscopic musical landscape, which can be especially useful for newcomers to a music scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/bandcamp-librarian/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bandcamp Dance Librarian&lt;/a&gt; project grew out of these impressions. In short, the project uses the industry taxonomy of Beatport in an attempt to detect stylistic tendencies or repertoires within the Bandcamp libraries of (mainly) grasroots labels. To achieve this, an automatic subgenre classifier is trained on Beatport’s Top-100 lists, which identifies the possible subgenres a track may belong to based on an audio analysis of its musical features. The classifier is then applied to detect the styles a Bandcamp library may belong to. The tracks pertaining to the whole library are first individually analysed, then distributed into groups or clusters based on their possible subgenre affiliations. The project output also show the tags (folksonomies) added by the artists/labels to the Bandcamp pages. It is therefore possible to compare the industry taxonomy of Beatport with artist folksonomies, as long as such tags are provided on Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at a working example. &lt;a href=&#34;https://sonicgroove.bandcamp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sonic Groove&lt;/a&gt; can be described a Berlin-based industrial techno label with strong EBM (Electronic Body Music) influences from a niche side of the electronic dance music spectrum. Neither industrial nor EBM techno are part of the Bandcamp taxonomy, so one can expect that the closest subgenres will be detected by the classifier. After running the Librarian we get a PDF report proposing three clusters with the following timeline distribution (the clustering algorithm may give different results each time):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cluster-0-techno-electro-and-indie-dance&#34;&gt;Cluster 0: Techno, Electro and Indie Dance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Cluster 0: Techno, Electro and Indie Dance&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_0_hudf1c719985a5c35d48958530d95490a1_142084_c8972b0413f620d10d809c96c4f02ce9.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_0_hudf1c719985a5c35d48958530d95490a1_142084_08879027e7448f4de13f46840adec1ec.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_0_hudf1c719985a5c35d48958530d95490a1_142084_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_0_hudf1c719985a5c35d48958530d95490a1_142084_c8972b0413f620d10d809c96c4f02ce9.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;628&#34;
               height=&#34;471&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first group (Cluster 0) is tentatively associated with the (&lt;em&gt;Raw-Deep-Hpynotic&lt;/em&gt;) Techno, (&lt;em&gt;Classic-Detroit-Modern&lt;/em&gt;) Electro and Indie Dance Beatport genres (the numbers in brackets represent confidence values). Three track examples are provided within each cluster, with links to their Bandcamp pages and their associated folksonomies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/6n1b560ejaDz3Gfqj7ZlIa&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cluster-1-techno-to-hard-techno&#34;&gt;Cluster 1: Techno to Hard Techno&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Cluster 1: Techno to Hard Techno&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_1_hu6a6ad821c6cc0fccdc0384bb13ec5376_156811_eae04bd45a06a1bf457e65fd6a9a8bec.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_1_hu6a6ad821c6cc0fccdc0384bb13ec5376_156811_ceb268080ef0cda1e3aae2f31bfcf651.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_1_hu6a6ad821c6cc0fccdc0384bb13ec5376_156811_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_1_hu6a6ad821c6cc0fccdc0384bb13ec5376_156811_eae04bd45a06a1bf457e65fd6a9a8bec.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;628&#34;
               height=&#34;482&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second group is crystallized around more evident techno influences according to the classifier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/465WEBBmdsG2fIrmGq0KwZ&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cluster-2-ambient&#34;&gt;Cluster 2: Ambient&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Cluster 2: Ambient&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_2_hub333d1b7ee6d740ee417d0fdf6040aa8_143353_24e387e04f712bdc62aa1b96c38659dd.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_2_hub333d1b7ee6d740ee417d0fdf6040aa8_143353_98fef55f2b8cd0c03ae2dbd76902642d.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_2_hub333d1b7ee6d740ee417d0fdf6040aa8_143353_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-05-folksonomies/cluster_2_hub333d1b7ee6d740ee417d0fdf6040aa8_143353_24e387e04f712bdc62aa1b96c38659dd.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;628&#34;
               height=&#34;475&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the last cluster is predominantly classified as ambient. The example tracks are highly atmospheric, and their beats are less pronounced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/48snI8H5RyBBinAJh0Zvq0&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tags associated to the tracks refer to subgenres (&lt;em&gt;EBM, industrial and electro&lt;/em&gt;), aesthetic modes (&lt;em&gt;purism, futurism&lt;/em&gt;), localities (&lt;em&gt;Berlin, Hamilton, New York&lt;/em&gt;) and moods (&lt;em&gt;desolation, subway&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the next blogpost I will get into more details on the project, discuss additional examples and touch on possible ramifications of this work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charles, Christopher. 2020. “Genre in Practice: Categories, Metadata and Music-Making in Psytrance Culture”. Dancecult: Journal of Electronic Dance Music Culture, no. 12 (1): 22–47.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fabbri, Franco. 2007. “Browsing Music Spaces: Categories and the Musical Mind”. Critical essays in popular musicology, ed. A. Moore, Aldershot: Ashgate. 49–62.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graham, Stephen. 1996. Sounds of the Underground: A Cultural, Political and Aesthetic Mapping of Underground and Fringe Music. Ann Arbor: University of Michigan Press. 115–124.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;McLeod, Kernbrew. 2001. “Genres, Subgenres, Sub-subgenres and More: Musical and Social Differentiation Within Electronic/Dance Music Communities”. Journal of Popular Music Studies, no. 13 (1): 59–75.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vander Wal, Thomas. 2007. “Folksonomy Coinage and Definition”. Off The Top. &lt;a href=&#34;https://vanderwal.net/folksonomy.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://vanderwal.net/folksonomy.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Music Observatory in the Jump European Music Market Accelerator: Meet the 2021 Fellows and their Tutors</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_ccf12428972a82cbd24bafda54692b2c.webp 400w,
               /media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_f262402b72fb6fe95c1f4bdcb9ce7df4.webp 760w,
               /media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_ccf12428972a82cbd24bafda54692b2c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;281&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the announcement of JUMP, the European Music Market Accelerator, after a careful screening of all applications received, the selection committee composed of all JUMP board members has selected the most promising ideas and projects to be developed together with renowned tutors for this 2021 fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For nine months, the 20 fellows living in many European countries will develop their innovative projects, while receiving a comprehensive 360° training. In addition to specialised workshops by highly qualified experts, each fellow will receive one-on-one tutoring sessions from the most renowned music professionals coming from all over Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 20 selected projects cover a great variety of urgent needs faced within the music sector.
They will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;help fostering social change with projects focusing on diversity in the industry, more fairness and
transparency as well as raising awareness on timely issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;enhance technological development with projects using blockchain, immersive sound and VR and AR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;build bridges between different key actors of the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/documents/JUMP2021_Annoucement_Press_Release_040321.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download the entire JUMP press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex&amp;rsquo;s project, the automated &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; will be represented by Daniel Antal, co-founder of Reprex among other building bridges projects. This project offers a different approach to the planned European Music Observatory based on the principles of open collaboration, which allows contributions from small organizations and even individuals, and which provides higher levels of quality in terms of auditability, timeliness, transparency and general ease of use. Our open collaboration approach allows to power trustworthy, ethical AI systems like our &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; that we started out from Slovakia with the support of the Slovak Arts Council.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-jump-fellows-building-bridges-between-different-key-actors-of-the-ecosystem&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;JUMP fellows building bridges between different key actors of the ecosystem.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/reprex/building_bridges_hu047151272ef115b93f0df472b4421474_585232_3c094c224bfc88c7ce7bef53c3d3adf3.webp 400w,
               /media/img/reprex/building_bridges_hu047151272ef115b93f0df472b4421474_585232_200986da45a608039ecc7c8539d60980.webp 760w,
               /media/img/reprex/building_bridges_hu047151272ef115b93f0df472b4421474_585232_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/reprex/building_bridges_hu047151272ef115b93f0df472b4421474_585232_3c094c224bfc88c7ce7bef53c3d3adf3.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;392&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      JUMP fellows building bridges between different key actors of the ecosystem.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from our &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; the build bridges section &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/groovly/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Groovly&lt;/a&gt; with Martin Zenzerovich, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/from-play-to-rec/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;From Play To Rec&lt;/a&gt; by Jeremy Dunne, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/hajde-radio/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hajde Radio&lt;/a&gt; by Thibaut Boudaud, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/lowdee/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LowDee&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Davidson and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/uno-hu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ONO-HU!&lt;/a&gt; by Gina Akers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meet all the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellows/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JUMP 2021 Fellows&lt;/a&gt;, including the technology and social change professionals!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex is a start-up company based in the Netherlands and the United States that validated its early products in the &lt;a href=&#34;post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Lab&lt;/a&gt; in the Hague. In 2021 we joined the Dutch AI Coalition &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;post/2021-02-16-nlaic/&#34;&gt;NL AIC&lt;/a&gt; and requested membership in the European AI Alliance. Reprex is committed to applying reproducible in an open collaboration with our business, scientific, policy and civil society partners, and facilitate the use of open data and open-source software. Many fellows in the program are connected to other regions, like North America and Australia &amp;ndash; because music is one of the most globalized industries and forms of art in the world!  Reprex is a startup based in the Netherlands and the United States, and we are very excited to collaborate with our peers in new European territories, and in Canada and Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-hope-to-meet-you-in-these-great-events---maybe-not-only-online&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Hope to meet you in these great events - maybe not only online!&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/JUMP_events_2021_huc4ee3afec7ca5a36e31b155ecc339395_183968_66c7d8ef3d90da2990059fac82ae686c.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/JUMP_events_2021_huc4ee3afec7ca5a36e31b155ecc339395_183968_c55ec1e30f1bea8d35c0a5c9bb1a4109.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/JUMP_events_2021_huc4ee3afec7ca5a36e31b155ecc339395_183968_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/JUMP_events_2021_huc4ee3afec7ca5a36e31b155ecc339395_183968_66c7d8ef3d90da2990059fac82ae686c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;307&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Hope to meet you in these great events - maybe not only online!
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/fromplaytorec/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;From Play to Rec&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hajde.fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HAJDE&lt;/a&gt; FR/EN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Independent Labels and Major Record Labels Compete on a Level Playing Field When It Comes to Streaming?</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 07:23:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do Independent Labels and Major Record Labels Compete on a Level Playing Field When It Comes to Streaming? According to the written evidence submitted by Dr. Franco Mariuzzo and Dr. Peter Ormosi to the Economics of music streaming inquiry of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/15122/html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UK Parliament, Digital, Culture, Media, and Sports Committee&lt;/a&gt;, the answer is no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers compared the number of streams for 719 artists represented by the major labels Sony and UMG and 1101 artists represented by independent labels to assess whether similarly popular artists had the same chance to rack up new streams over a period of two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying advanced econometric techniques (you can read their publication before scientific peer-review &lt;a href=&#34;https://poseidon01.ssrn.com/delivery.php?ID=587025086112006006104031017104122104113073037034031091095095089113004080075007105067020007042040000015016073015122067013079078037066031008013103119025115019095109091035012104070084028121027073072117103088016126127066004119110082124031112023000087116&amp;amp;EXT=pdf&amp;amp;INDEX=TRUE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), the researchers ensured that the artists being compared met rigorous statistical similarity criteria. The growth prospects of artists represented by Sony and UMG do not appear to be significantly different. However, the researchers found significant differences in growth prospects when comparing artists associated with major and independent labels.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-umg-and-sony-artitsts-gather-streams-more-quickly-the-two-companies-happen-to-be-spotify-shareholders&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;UMG and Sony artitsts gather streams more quickly. The two companies happen to be Spotify shareholders.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/featured_hub2f9b2409c3a39637e702c75501b18c7_160334_da209c156dd0df62107938faf2dd341a.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/featured_hub2f9b2409c3a39637e702c75501b18c7_160334_be6b465f030115f63c8c54d080aa6656.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/featured_hub2f9b2409c3a39637e702c75501b18c7_160334_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/featured_hub2f9b2409c3a39637e702c75501b18c7_160334_da209c156dd0df62107938faf2dd341a.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;471&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      UMG and Sony artitsts gather streams more quickly. The two companies happen to be Spotify shareholders.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One possible explanation could be that major label artists feature disproportionately in Spotify generated playlists, which gives them access to distributional channels — and consequently revenue — that indie labels do not have. Our simulation results confirm this explanation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying a Gibrat’s law on revenue shares, the competition economists show that even if you only listen to your friend’s music in Slovakia or the Netherlands, most of the subscription fee you pay is allocated to artists such as Ed Sheeran or Ariana Grande.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-major-label-releases-appear-to-generate-more-streams&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Major label releases appear to generate more streams.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/major_vs_indy_scatterplot_hu9cc1496809d6da41eb6c4d784b64bfc9_73709_856ce8d9efaa33facbc532d6ee9f3130.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/major_vs_indy_scatterplot_hu9cc1496809d6da41eb6c4d784b64bfc9_73709_d8b457fbb31f6c58f50205350111a5a0.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/major_vs_indy_scatterplot_hu9cc1496809d6da41eb6c4d784b64bfc9_73709_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/major_vs_indy_scatterplot_hu9cc1496809d6da41eb6c4d784b64bfc9_73709_856ce8d9efaa33facbc532d6ee9f3130.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Major label releases appear to generate more streams.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UMG and Sony artitsts gather streams more quickly. The two companies happen to be Spotify shareholders.
This research is consistent with the findings of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Centre National de la Musique and Deloitte&lt;/a&gt;, which show that the income of certain music genres that major labels invest into —such as rap and Afrobeat — receive about 20% more income than their share in streams at the expense of other genres.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-if-royalty-distribution-were-proportional-to-the-number-of-streams-by-listeners-classical-music-hard-rock-blues-pop-and-rock-labels-and-their-artists-would-get-1724-revenue-per-year&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;If royalty distribution were proportional to the number of streams by listeners, classical music, hard rock, blues, pop, and rock labels and their artists would get 17–24% revenue per year.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/cnm_genre_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_b940b2ff16534e1f5d10dc7c7bbc396d.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/cnm_genre_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_7243f5bb516a1a93b4aa7675f5ed9580.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/cnm_genre_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-01-major-vs-independent/cnm_genre_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_b940b2ff16534e1f5d10dc7c7bbc396d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;595&#34;
               height=&#34;437&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      If royalty distribution were proportional to the number of streams by listeners, classical music, hard rock, blues, pop, and rock labels and their artists would get 17–24% revenue per year.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If royalty distribution were proportional to the number of streams by listeners, classical music, hard rock, blues, pop, and rock labels and their artists would get 17–24% revenue per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our own investigation with &lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; focused on the artists who are never recommended at all and ended up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt;. Our data suggests, but not yet proves, that certain countries of origin have a similar disadvantage. We are building &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; to continuously share, collect data that can help empirically decide questions in such inquiries.  And we’ll join forces with Dr. Mariuzzo and Dr. Ormosi to find it out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-24-music-level-playing-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 21:23:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-24-music-level-playing-field/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our article, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/music-streaming-is-it-a-level-playing-field/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?&lt;/a&gt; is published in the February 2021 issue of CPI Antitrust Chronicle, which is fully devoted to competition policy issues in the music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dramatic growth of music streaming over recent years is potentially very positive. Streaming provides consumers with low cost, easy access to a wide range of music, while it provides music creators with low cost, easy access to a potentially wide audience. But many creators are unhappy about the major streaming platforms. They consider that they act in an unfair way, create an unlevel playing field and threaten long-term creativity in the music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our paper describes and assesses the basis for one element of these concerns, competition between recordings on streaming platforms. We argue that fair competition is restricted by the nature of the remuneration arrangements between creators and the streaming platforms, the role of playlists, and the strong negotiating power of the major labels. It concludes that urgent consideration should be given to a user-centric payment system, as well as greater transparency of the factors underpinning playlist creation and of negotiated agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the entire issue and the full text of our article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Competition Policy International&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2-Music-Streaming-Is-It-a-Level-Playing-Field-By-Daniel-Antal-Amelia-Fletcher-14-Peter-L.-Ormosi.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Antal, co-founder of Reprex Was Selected into the 2021 Fellowship Program of the European Music Market Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-22-jump/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 21:23:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-22-jump/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_ccf12428972a82cbd24bafda54692b2c.webp 400w,
               /media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_f262402b72fb6fe95c1f4bdcb9ce7df4.webp 760w,
               /media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_ccf12428972a82cbd24bafda54692b2c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;281&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Antal, co-founder of Reprex, and co-editor of Data &amp;amp; Lyrics, was selected into 2021 Fellowship program of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JUMP, the European Music Market Accelerator&lt;/a&gt;. Jump provides a framework for music professionals to develop innovative business models, encouraging the music sector to work on a transnational level.  The European Music Market Accelerator composed of MaMA Festival and Convention, UnConvention, MIL, Athens Music Week, Nouvelle Prague and Linecheck support him in the development of our two, interrelated projects over the next nine months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is a demo version of the European Music Observatory based on open data, open source, automated research in open collaboration with music stakeholders. We hope that we can further develop our business model and find new users, and help the recovery of the festival and live music segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; is our AI system that validated third party music AI, such as Spotify&amp;rsquo;s or YouTube&amp;rsquo;s recommendation systems, and provides trustworthy, accountable, transparent alternatives for the European music industry. We hope to expand our pilot project from Slovakia to several European countries in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex is a start-up company based in the Netherlands and the United States that validated its early products in the &lt;a href=&#34;post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Lab&lt;/a&gt; in the Hague. In 2021 we joined the Dutch AI Coalition &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;post/2021-02-16-nlaic/&#34;&gt;NL AIC&lt;/a&gt; and requested membership in the European AI Alliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex is committed to applying reproducible in an open collaboration with our business, scientific, policy and civil society partners, and facilitate the use of open data and open-source software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What If Your Stream Count Would Count For The Artists?</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 09:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contrary to what many believe, your music streaming history plays a relatively small role in the payouts of the artists whose songs you are listening to. The streaming platforms use a MCPS, or market-centred payout system, which is biased towards large market listeners. Contrary to UCPS, or user-centred payout systems, where all streams by all users are tallied up to determine the final distribution of subscription and advertisement revenues, MCPS uses weighted averaging that very heavily favours major music distributors and the biggest global stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We analyze these competition policy problems with Amelia Fletcher and Peter L. Ormosi in our forthcoming publication in a special issue of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Competition Policy International&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Music streaming: is it a level playing field?&lt;/em&gt;. But in the meantime, an interesting impact assessment emerged from France, because the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cnm.fr/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Centre National de la Musique&lt;/a&gt; commissioned Deloitte to make an impact assessment on &lt;a href=&#34;https://cnm.fr/le-cnm-evalue-limpact-dun-changement-eventuel-de-mode-de-remuneration-par-les-plateformes-de-streaming/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a possible change&lt;/a&gt;. Deezer provided a full overview of its 2019 payouts, while Spotify gave a sample of 100,000 artist payouts, and the other streaming services — for example, Apple Music — refused to cooperate with the French government-backed institution. You can read an English language summary and an excellent commentary from Emmanuel Legrand on his blog: &lt;a href=&#34;https://legrandnetwork.blogspot.com/2021/02/user-centric-model-would-not-lead-to.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;User-centric model would not lead to significant changes in the distribution of music streaming royalties&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-which-genres-would-be-winners-and-losers-in-the-fair-payout&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Which genres would be winners and losers in the fair payout?&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/featured_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_bef50eac0b0da091ee6cabca789d86db.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/featured_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_87a0f83e6f423d124f61b004d5e82322.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/featured_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/featured_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_bef50eac0b0da091ee6cabca789d86db.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;595&#34;
               height=&#34;437&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Which genres would be winners and losers in the fair payout?
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair distribution would completely alter the revenues of different genres. The biggest winner would be classical music, but various forms of pop, rock, jazz and disco artists would earn 15–25% more revenue. Currently, rap and hip-hop take about an extra 20% royalty revenue at the expense of these genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The streaming providers, which are directly or indirectly part-owned by major labels, are playing down the results, claiming that the difference would translate only to a few euros per artists at the bottom of the pyramid. In a sense, this is true, because streaming royalties are generally very low. But averaging is extremely misleading, because it includes millions of songs that are out-of-date or for another reason are never heard. In fact, entire scenes and labels would earn about 10% more revenue globally, considering that streaming revenues add up to half or even more of their total recording revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprex Joins The Dutch AI Coalition</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-16-nlaic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 17:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-16-nlaic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reprex, our start-up, is based in the Netherlands and the United States that validated its early products in the &lt;a href=&#34;post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Lab&lt;/a&gt; in the Hague. In 2021, we decided to join the Dutch AI Coalition &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlaic.com/en/about-nl-aic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NL AIC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NL AIC is a public-private partnership in which the government, the business sector, educational and research institutions, as well as civil society organisations collaborate to accelerate and connect AI developments and initiatives. The ambition is to position the Netherlands at the forefront of knowledge and application of AI for prosperity and well-being. We are continually doing so with due observance of both the Dutch and European standards and values. The NL AIC functions as the catalyst for AI applications in our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are particularly looking forward to participating in the Culture working group of NLAIC, but we will also take a look at the Security, Peace and Justice and the Energy and Sustainability working groups.  Reprex is committed to use and further develop AI solutions that fulfil the requirements of trustworthy AI, a human-centric, ethical, and accountable use of artificial intelligence.  We are committed to develop our data platforms, or automated data observatories, and our Listen Local system in this manner. Furthermore, we are involved in various scientific collaborations that are researching ideas on future regulation of copyright and fair competition with respect to AI algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are committed to applying reproducible in an open collaboration with our business, scientific, policy and civil society partners, and facilitate the use of open data and open-source software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring the Visibility and Accessibility of European Creative Content on the World Market: The Need for Copyright Data Improvement in the Light of New Technologies</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-13-european-visibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 18:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-13-european-visibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The majority of music sales in the world is driven by AI-algorithm powered robots that create personalized playlists, recommendations and help programming radio music streams or festival lineups. It is critically important that an artist’s work is documented, described in a way that the algorithm can work with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our research paper – soon to be published – made for the Listen Local Initiative we found that 15% of Dutch, Estonian, Hungarian, or Slovak artists had no chance to be recommended, and they usually end up on &lt;a href=&#34;post/2020-11-17-recommendation-analysis/&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt;, an app that lists never-played songs of Spotify. In another project with rights management organizations, we found that about half of the rightsholders are at risk of not getting all their royalties from the platforms because of poor documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how come that distributors give streaming platforms songs that are not properly documented?  What sort of information is missing for the European repertoire’s visibility?  Reprex is exploring this problem in a practical cooperation with SOZA, the Slovak Performing and Mechanical Rights Society, and in an academic cooperation that involves leading researchers in the field. A manuscript co-authored Martin Senftleben, director of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ivir.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Institute for Information Law&lt;/a&gt; in Amsterdam, and eminent researchers in copyright law and music economics, Reprex’s co-founder makes the case that Europe must invest public money to resolve this problem, because in the current scenario, the documentation costs of a song exceed the expected income from streaming platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the European Strategy for Data, the European Commission highlighted the EU’s ambition to acquire a leading role in the data economy. At the same time, the Commission conceded that the EU would have to increase its pools of quality data available for use and re-use. In the creative industries, this need for enhanced data quality and interoperability is particularly strong. Without data improvement, unprecedented opportunities for monetising the wide variety of EU creative and making this content available for new technologies, such as artificial intelligence training systems, will most probably be lost. The problem has a worldwide dimension. While the US have already taken steps to provide an integrated data space for music as of 1 January 2021, the EU is facing major obstacles not only in the field of music but also in other creative industry sectors. Weighing costs and benefits, there can be little doubt that new data improvement initiatives and sufficient investment in a better copyright data infrastructure should play a central role in EU copyright policy. A trade-off between data harmonisation and interoperability on the one hand, and transparency and accountability of content recommender systems on the other, could pave the way for successful new initiatives. &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3785272&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Download the manuscript from SSRN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;post/2020-12-17-demo-slovak-music-database/&#34;&gt;Slovak Demo Music Database&lt;/a&gt; project is a best example for this. We started systematically collect publicly available information from Slovak artists (in our write-in process) and ask them to give GDPR-protected further data (in our opt-in process) to create a comprehensive database that can help recommendation engines as well as market-targeting or educational AI apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that one of the problems of current AI algorithms that they solely or almost only work with English language documentation, putting other, particularly small language repertoires at risk of being buried below well-documented music mainly arriving from the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are looking for rightsholders and their organizations, artists,
researchers to work with us to find out how we can increase the visibility of European music.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feasibility Study On Promoting Slovak Music In Slovakia &amp; Abroad</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/listen_local_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/listen_local_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Download the study &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/publications/Listen_Local_Feasibility_Study_2020_SK.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in Slovak&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/publications/Listen_Local_Feasibility_Study_2020_EN.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, realizing the low visibility and income-generating potential of Slovak music, the legislation introduced an amendment to the broadcasting act to regulate local content in radiostreams. The Slovak content promoting policy was well-intended but not based on any impact assessment, and it reached its goal only partially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Slovak broadcasting quotas in comparison with other national quotas a very simple, and they are impossible to measure, which makes both compliance and enforcement very difficult. Radio editors do not get any help to find music that fits into the playlists and fulfil the quota obligations – in many cases, it is impossible for them to find out if a song actually meets the quota requirements. For the same reason, neither is enforcement possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another deficiency of the broadcasting quotas is that because of its fuzzy target, it is not clear whom it tries to help, and it has few friends. It is unclear how performers, composers or Slovak music producers can benefit from the system. Furthermore, it only helps a few genres, and it decreases the chances of other Slovak music in instrumental and non-Slovak language genres (for example, classical, jazz, rock) to be heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And at last, radio is losing its importance in music discovery. New generation find the music during their music discovery age on YouTube and digital streaming platforms. A Slovak content promoting policy that does not work on digital streaming platforms will be obsolete when radio content providers will switch to digital streaming in the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Feasibility Study follows the following logic:&lt;/strong&gt;
In the first chapter we introduce various music recommendation systems in the context of local content promotion polices, like local mandatory content quota regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second chapter, we consider the market-based or creative industry economy supporting policy goals, measurements, and potential support given to artists and producers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then turn in the third chapter to content-based local regulations promoting the use of the Slovak language or Slovak music content, irrespective of the performers and producers nationality, residence or ethnicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce the idea of the &lt;strong&gt;Slovak Music Database&lt;/strong&gt;, a comprehensive, mainly opt-in, opt-out database that of Slovak artists and Slovak music that should be supported by the local content regulation and other policies. We also create a Demo Slovak Music Database to understand the problem and scope of the creation of the comprehensive version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project website contains the &lt;a href=&#34;https://listen-local.net/project/demo-sk-music-db/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Slovak Music Database&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://listen-local.net/project/demo-app/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Recommendation System&lt;/a&gt;. We explain here &lt;a href=&#34;https://listen-local.net/post/2020-11-23-alternative-recommendations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;why&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##Research questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are the total market shares of Slovak music relatively low both on the domestic and the foreign markets?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can we measure the market share of the Slovak music in the domestic and foreign markets?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can we measure the value gap between what some media platforms, most particularly the biggest YouTube, does not pay out to the Slovak stakeholders within Slovakia?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the interplay of the various definitions on market share and national quota targets?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How ‘shadow-markets’ of home copying and unlicensed media platforms, such as YouTube impact market shares directly and national quotas indirectly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can modern data science, predictive microeconomics and statistics help increase the market share of Slovak music in Slovakia and abroad?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the entire Reprex team who contributed to the English version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Emily H. Clarke&lt;/strong&gt;, musicology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stef Koenis&lt;/strong&gt;, musicologist, musician&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Andrés Garcia Molina&lt;/strong&gt;, data scientist, musicologist, editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kátya Nagy&lt;/strong&gt;, music journalist, research assistant;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and the Slovak version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dominika Semaňáková&lt;/strong&gt;, musicologist, editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dáša Bulíková&lt;/strong&gt;, musician, translator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo Slovak Music Database</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-17-demo-slovak-music-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 17:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-17-demo-slovak-music-database/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are finalizing our first local recommendation system, Listen Local Slovakia, and the accompanying Demo Slovak Music Database. Our aim is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show how the Slovak repertoire is seen by media and streaming platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the possibilities to give greater visibility to the Slovak repertoire in radio and streaming platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the specific problems why certain artists and music is almost invisible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next year, we would like to create a modern, comprehensive national music database that serves music promotion in radio, streaming, live music within Slovakia and abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To train our locally relevant, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/&#34;&gt;alternative recommendation system&lt;/a&gt;, we filled the Demo Slovak Music Database from two sources. In the &lt;code&gt;opt-in&lt;/code&gt; process we asked artists to participate in Listen Local, and we selected those artists who opted in from Slovakia, or whose language is Slovak. In the &lt;code&gt;write-in&lt;/code&gt; process we collected publicly available data from other artists that our musicology team considered to be Slovak, mainly on the basis of their language use, residence, and other public biographical information. The following artists form the basis of our experiment. (&lt;em&gt;If you want to be excluded from the write-in list, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;write to us&lt;/a&gt;, or you want to be included, please, fill out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe seamless =&#34;&#34; name=&#34;iframe&#34; src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/htmlwidgets/sk_artist_table.html&#34; width=&#34;1000&#34; height=&#34;1050&#34; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/htmlwidgets/sk_artist_table.html&#34;&gt;Click here to view the table on a separate page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern recommendation systems usually rely on data provided by artists or their representatives, data on who and how is listening to their music, and what music is listened to by the audience of the artists, and certain musicological features of the music.  Usually they collect data from various data sources, but these data sources are mainly English language sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with these recommendation systems is that they do not help music discovery, and make starting new acts very difficult. Recommendation systems tend to help already established artists, and artists whose work is well described in the English language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our alternative recommendation system is a utility-based system that gives a user-defined priority to artists released in Slovakia, or artists identified as Slovak, or both. The system can be extended for lyrics language priorities, too.
Currently, our app is demonstration to provide a more comprehensive database-driven tool that can support various music discovery, recommendation or music export tools. Our Feasibility Study to build such tools and our Demo App is currently under consultation with Slovak stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; is developing transparent algorithms and open source solutions to find new audiences for independent music. We want to correct the injustice and inherent bias of market leading big data algorithms. If you want&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;your music and audience&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;to be analysed in Listen Local, fill&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in. We will include you in our demo application for local music recommendations and our analysis to be revealed in December.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: Why We Need Alternative Recommendation Systems</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 17:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-first-version-of-our-demo-application&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;The first version of our demo application&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/03_app_recommend_hue273d4dba573461e5c0230751d669551_145885_0c2fe5ec07c123affc9e64babc1ba7e8.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/03_app_recommend_hue273d4dba573461e5c0230751d669551_145885_7431d48d4896b9f0570da0f6511dab6d.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/03_app_recommend_hue273d4dba573461e5c0230751d669551_145885_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/03_app_recommend_hue273d4dba573461e5c0230751d669551_145885_0c2fe5ec07c123affc9e64babc1ba7e8.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;309&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The first version of our demo application
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommendation systems utilize knowledge about music content and their audiences while also pursuing the objectives or needs of recommenders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest recommendation systems just follow the charts: for example, they select from well-known current or perennial greatest hits. Such a system may work well for an amateur DJ in a home party or a small local radio that just wants to make sure that the music in its programme will be liked by many people. They reinforce existing trends and make already popular songs and their creators even more popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the recommendation engine is supported by big data and a machine learning system &amp;ndash; or increasingly, a combination of several machine learning algorithms &amp;ndash; the general &lt;em&gt;modus operandi&lt;/em&gt; is to exploit information about both content and users in order to achieve certain goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-algorithmic-recommendation-systems-work&#34;&gt;How algorithmic recommendation systems work?&lt;/h2&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-how-recommendation-systems-work&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;How recommendation systems work?&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/mind_map_recommendations_hu598e31fbda7e27fa2531c6d1d2d7129e_95495_a24fefaf48e8a27a63649a2c4e63b745.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/mind_map_recommendations_hu598e31fbda7e27fa2531c6d1d2d7129e_95495_53ec00df9d6fd8bd9fa8bc29323ef591.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/mind_map_recommendations_hu598e31fbda7e27fa2531c6d1d2d7129e_95495_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/mind_map_recommendations_hu598e31fbda7e27fa2531c6d1d2d7129e_95495_a24fefaf48e8a27a63649a2c4e63b745.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;426&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      How recommendation systems work?
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s recommendation system is a mix of content- and collaborative filtering that exploits information about users’ past behaviour (e.g. liked, skipped, and re-listened songs), the behaviour of similar users, as well as data collected from the users&amp;rsquo; social media and other online activities, or from blogs. Deezer uses a similar system that is boosted by the acquisition of Last.fm &amp;ndash; big data created from user comments are used to understand the mood of the songs, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-spotify-makes-16-billion-music-recommendations-each-month-in-2020&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Spotify makes 16 billion music recommendations each month in 2020.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/spotify_discover_weekly_hue95bf4b3b7257937912363dc6117ebbf_2116732_5c803acaaacd388a5120e693bc6ccf5f.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/spotify_discover_weekly_hue95bf4b3b7257937912363dc6117ebbf_2116732_aed5004a2ec97887bf0eb08acdf66536.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/spotify_discover_weekly_hue95bf4b3b7257937912363dc6117ebbf_2116732_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-15-alternative-recommendations/spotify_discover_weekly_hue95bf4b3b7257937912363dc6117ebbf_2116732_5c803acaaacd388a5120e693bc6ccf5f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;427&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Spotify makes 16 billion music recommendations each month in 2020.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube, which plays an even larger role in music discovery, uses a system comprised of two neural networks: one for candidate generation and one for ranking. The candidate generation deep neural network provides works on the basis of collaborative filtering, while the ranking system is based on content-based filtering and a form of utility ranking that takes into consideration the user&amp;rsquo;s languages, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes these systems common is that they maximize the algorithm creators&amp;rsquo; corporate key performance indicators. Spotify wants to be ‘your playlist to life’ and increase the amount of music played during work or sports in the background, during travelling, or active music listening –- i.e. maximizing the number of hours spent using it, and do not let empty timeslots for other music providers, such as radio stations. YouTube and Netflix have similar targets. They are in many ways like commercial radio targets, which want to maximize the time spent listening to the broadcast stream. Radios and YouTube, in particular, have similar goals because they are mainly financed through advertising. For Spotify or Netflix, their key financial motivation is to avoid users&amp;rsquo; cancelling their subscriptions or changing it to different providers, such as Amzon, Apple or Deezer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-problem-with-black-box-recommendation-systems&#34;&gt;What is the problem with black box recommendation systems?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What they also have in common is that they do not aim to give a fair chance to each uploaded song, serve equally every artist, or provide whatever equality of chances for English, Slovak or Farsi language content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They tend to reinforce trends similarly to music charts, but with far bigger efficiency. As the Dutch comedian, author and journalist Arjen Lubach explains the YouTube algorithm, to keep their personal recommendations engaging all the day and all of the night, they create a comfortable universe for the user allows little distraction in. If the user wants to listen to global hit music, or stoner rock, it will never be distracted with anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;710&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FLoR2Spftwg?cc_load_policy=1&amp;origin=http://dataandlyrics.com&amp;cc_lang_pref=en&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zondag met Lubach on Dutch public broadcaster VPRO. Click settings sign to change the language of the captions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with such hyper-personalized media is that they leave no room for public activities.  Public broadcasters, which had a monopoly to television broadcasting in most European countries until the early 1990s, for example, were aiming to air a diversity of news, knowledge and access to local culture. Many countries on all continents have maintained &lt;code&gt;local content guidelines&lt;/code&gt; for broadcasting on public, commercial and community television and radio channels, for example, local music and films, and reliable news as a public service. Personalized media-, social media- and streaming platforms do not have such obligations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black box recommendation systems usually maximize a corporate key performance indicator, and they are not subject to usual public new service or local content regulations that traditional broadcast media is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal and the steps that the algorithm is pursuing is not know to content creators, and they do not know when will the algorithm work for their benefit or against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transparent-and-regulated-ai&#34;&gt;Transparent and regulated AI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our view, utility-based recommendation system can provide a bridge between current, corporate-owned systems that maximize a media or streaming platforms&amp;rsquo; business indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public new service requirements or local content requirements (&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;national quotas&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;) set for commercial broadcasting are similar to utility or knowledge-based recommendation systems. A utility-based recommendation system, for example, would prefer from two candidates for a playlist the one that has a Slovak composer, or a performer from Wales, or which has Farsi lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Demo App creates recommendations on the basis of a pre-existing radio or personal streaming playlist that, by choice, contains a pre-defined ratio of music produced in Slovakia, or performed by Slovak artists. We will soon add Dutch and Hungarian choices to this demo, but naturally, we could add any city&amp;rsquo;s, regions&amp;rsquo;, province&amp;rsquo;s our countries preferences into the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Demo App and accompanying Feasibility Study in Slovakia shows how can a regulator create better broadcasting regulations, learning from the experience with AI-driven streaming platforms, and how can it apply the goals of local content requirements (such as a certain visibility for Slovak or a city-based music) and public service requirements (for example, spreading reliable information or stopping &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hateful music&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;access-for-all&#34;&gt;Access for all&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not believe that the current heated discussion on the re-regulation of AI and music streaming will solve all the problems of independent artists, bands from ethnic or racial minorities, or otherwise vulnerable producers. New regulation can limit the unintended collateral damage of big data algorithms deployed by big corporations, but they will not bring down the benefits of AI to these creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the example of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2020/nov/03/spotify-artists-promote-music-exchange-cut-royalty-rates-payola-algorithm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;controversial&lt;/a&gt; new initiative that let&amp;rsquo;s artists, labels and publishers to promote their music in exchange for &lt;a href=&#34;https://newsroom.spotify.com/2020-11-02/amplifying-artist-input-in-your-personalized-recommendations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a cut in royalty rates&lt;/a&gt;. While felt by many artists injust and even corrupt, it is an answer to the growing need to influence how the recommendation algorithms are promoting certain music at the expense of tens of millions of sound recordings that are not recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that algorithms create value for the users, and if artists are not happy to pay for corporations to influence black box algoritms, thatn they must collaborate and share data, and build large enough data pools so that they can deploy white, transparent algorithms that work for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Feasibility Study shows why it is important that creators have a &lt;code&gt;control over what data describes their music&lt;/code&gt;, their biographies and other information online, because corporate streaming platforms use this information for their algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should that with relatively little effort creators can &lt;code&gt;pool enough information&lt;/code&gt; to create alternative recommendation systems that follow a more agreeable goal, that is sensitive to local content requirements and more access to new artists, women or black performers, or which suppress hateful lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit of an &lt;code&gt;open algorithm&lt;/code&gt; and pooled data is that artists can actively look for audiences in various age groups or in cities that are accessible for them on a performing tour after the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, we want to show that regulating black box, private algorithms and data monopolies is only a first step to damage control. Deploying white, transparent algorithms and building collaborative or open data pools can only guarantee fairness in the digital platforms, in recommendations, and generally in the use of AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; is developing transparent algorithms and open source solutions to find new audiences for independent music. We want to correct the injustice and inherent bias of market leading big data algorithms. If you want&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;your music and audience&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;to be analysed in Listen Local, fill&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in. We will include you in our demo application for local music recommendations and our analysis to be revealed in December.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Rooms: A Label That Connects DIY Scenes</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-wwwtinyroomnl&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;www.tinyroom.nl&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/tiny_rooms_banner_hu0af4357b4903bf8e7dfce6d118dc51d7_803354_0183175c414d020480bf7baef9063450.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/tiny_rooms_banner_hu0af4357b4903bf8e7dfce6d118dc51d7_803354_4678d1a54fc2b471405e07a36be6de1f.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/tiny_rooms_banner_hu0af4357b4903bf8e7dfce6d118dc51d7_803354_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/tiny_rooms_banner_hu0af4357b4903bf8e7dfce6d118dc51d7_803354_0183175c414d020480bf7baef9063450.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;310&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tinyroom.nl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.tinyroom.nl&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interview with Utrecht recording artist, performer, composer, and producer Stefan Breuer, manager of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tinyroom.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tiny Room Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For fans browsing the city after a given show, what do artists in Utrecht recommend as far as things to see, do, listen to, or other advice for visitors?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone checking out one of my shows in Utrecht, I definitely recommend a walk around the city if they have some down time. Nearby our space, one can stop at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deklub.nl/menu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;De Klub&lt;/a&gt; for a bite to eat, the local brewery &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dekrommeharing.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;De Kromme Haring&lt;/a&gt; for a beer, or the record store / coffee bar Koffie Leute around the corner. For those with more time during the day, I also recommend a few local record stores like Dig It or Plato or maybe a walk around Utrecht centre. For the full Utrecht experience, I recommend a dive into the postrock, slowcore, indiefolk vibes of this friendly city with bands if you can catch bands like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefireharvest.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Fire Harvest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iamoak.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;I am Oak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://homemadeempire.bandcamp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Homemade Empire&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tinyroom.nl/artists/this-leo-sunrise/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This Leo Sunrise&lt;/a&gt;, among others. And of course there’s the Nijntje Museum, the Dom tower, and the canals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/2H9SBcpNrUg8Ymbf3hR88C&#34; width=&#34;710&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where do your artists hope to play next year? Where do they hope to find new fans?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’d like to play in any city with a vibrant DIY scene. In the Netherlands, I’d like to rebook all the shows in Haarlem, Amsterdam, Eindhoven and in Liège (BE) that were cancelled due to COVID. I’d also like to add some shows in Groningen, Nijmegen, Enschede, Maastricht and Arnhem because I know they also have some small DIY scenes there, too.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-stefan-breuer--tiny-rooms&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Stefan Breuer / Tiny Rooms.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/Stefan_Breuer_hud1f10558df68ad54f84cb64478a39875_1317232_de6aecc8c7508f462fcf21a9014e454b.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/Stefan_Breuer_hud1f10558df68ad54f84cb64478a39875_1317232_cd168815c484fa8641746b0a487a0ab2.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/Stefan_Breuer_hud1f10558df68ad54f84cb64478a39875_1317232_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/Stefan_Breuer_hud1f10558df68ad54f84cb64478a39875_1317232_de6aecc8c7508f462fcf21a9014e454b.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;507&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Stefan Breuer / Tiny Rooms.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to play in any city with a vivid DIY scene. In the Netherlands, I&amp;rsquo;d like to re-book our shows that were all cancelled in Haarlem, Amsterdam, Eindhoven, and Liège. I&amp;rsquo;d like to add some shows in Groningen, Nijmegen, Enschede, Maastricht and Arnhem because I know they have small DIY scenes there too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do you and your artists see the role of YouTube, Spotify, Facebook, algorithms, big data?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We try to make sure all our bands are present on all of these platforms and actively engage with content as much as possible, but there’s not really enough time to get the most out of YouTube, for example, when you are also trying to write and record music, book shows, not to mention that artists involved with my label all have other work and families to be with. I’d say we all know the potential of the internet and big data, but the best we can do right now is just let as much happen with that as we can. We don’t really feel like we have any control over what happens in that area or our overall “success” on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much is your label really focused on Utrecht specifically? Where would you say the true home base of your label is, whether geographically or spiritually? Where do you have the strongest audience?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Tiny Room Records is actually based in Utrecht and Bilthoven. Utrecht is a city. That’s where the scene happens and that’s what we’re part of. I live in Bilthoven, which is 5 kilometers away from Utrecht. It’s next to the woods. It’s quiet. It’s small. It’s perfect for focusing on creating beautiful music and art. There’s inspiration from the sight and smell of nature and not a lot of distractions like pubs and venues. So as a musician, my home base is Bilthoven. Running a label, it’s Utrecht because all the shows, recordings, and rehearsals happen there. It’s also where we’ve held most of the Tiny Room nights, and our 5th year anniversary festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How important is touring for your label’s roster? How do artists select touring locations? Where do you think your label’s strongest potential for finding a new audience would be?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our rehearsal space and venue Studio Patrick generates a DIY scene which is unique for Utrecht but not necessarily Europe. In the NL, we’ve always had a strong connection with Subblicious in Leiden, Lepel Concerts in Groningen, Roodkapje in Rotterdam, Vondelbunker in Amsterdam, Katzwijm Studio in Voorhout, De Ruimte in Amsterdam, the art scene around Danielle Papenborg in Nijmegen, and the Van Onderen festival. We’re also connected to labels like Subroutine, Moving Furniture, Snowstar, Coaster, Narrowminded, Geertruida and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/64MRjQF17SHJPX17Zsx42d&#34; width=&#34;710&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use these contacts to set up tours and other possibilities long the way. Sometimes it doesn’t work out wen you have a Canadian artist playing for two people in Heerhugowaard, but you don’t know until you try. That’s how I stumbled upon the scene around &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/honesthousemusic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Honest House&lt;/a&gt;, a label and booking agency in Liège, Belgium a couple years ago. It turned out to be perfect for all our bands and we still maintain a good partnership with them in order to regularly produce a few nights of live music. We will start working with them again around live music, of course, when we are post-COVID. Same goes for &lt;a href=&#34;https://lousymoon.bandcamp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lousy Moon Records&lt;/a&gt; in Köln. I think there are a lot more places like this and it would be great to have more insight about where the super DIY/indie/arty/folk/postpunk/kraut/experimental songwriting stuff is happening. I know it’s there in a lot of cities in its own form, but the audience is so small that it’s hard to get to know all the cool places. I’d like to focus on NL, Belgium, Germany, and France since these areas are the most doable for a weekend or week long tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s more important? Belonging to a scene, a genre, a subculture, or a location? How are these connected?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, it’s important to belong to a scene. These are the people here in Utrecht that care about what we do, our shows, and our releases. They come to support the bands, have a great time, and we all know each other, have the same values, and we’re good friends, too. Maybe some call that a “subculture” too, but no one I know calls it by a particular name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need a location to get together, but you can build a scene anywhere, I guess. My dad even built a vibrant music scene in the middle of nowhere in France in a village of 200 people. About genre, I don’t want to focus on one thing. For the label, I have a specific thing in mind — music that I really love — which is based on my own taste. Most people at the shows we host are most interested in music that’s more experimental, unique, even a bit raw and unusual. I can be ambient, indie rock, punk, sloppy folk, doom songwriters, slowcore, noise, etc. If it’s too catchy or a “normal” radio friendly singer/songwriter, the audience scratches their heads and I won’t have a good time either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What kind of insight and intelligence would you like from Listen Local, which tries to crunch a lot of data about location, language, and the genre of small acts?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to know where similar scenes are in other cities, where they host shows, and who books them, mainly in the Netherlands and surrounding countries, but also possibly in Italy, Switzerland. The bonus is that this also gives me some cool new bands to listen to as well. They would probably have a good audience here in Utrecht and we could probably do a “gig swap.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally it would make booking easier so that you won’t have to reinvent the wheel each time and hunt for new places, although that can also lead to some great adventures and memories, so I would not rule that out entirely. About genres, I hope to find bands that look beyond genre and experiment with sound, culture, and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/playlist?list=PLtTWwCg-saGYSzZVd5X4O3YDDLyxETIC-&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: The Youniverse from East to Southwest</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-guitarist-jerguš-oravec-and-singer-tammy-nižňanska&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Guitarist Jerguš Oravec and singer Tammy Nižňanska&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-11-30-youniverse/Youniverse_bw_hu058abfd6177ddd8e71df0e608d9f6cd1_975961_336438933badeb8a76910cd0b748680c.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-11-30-youniverse/Youniverse_bw_hu058abfd6177ddd8e71df0e608d9f6cd1_975961_915c0f074ad0a8c16b04b6f0a8a776c9.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-11-30-youniverse/Youniverse_bw_hu058abfd6177ddd8e71df0e608d9f6cd1_975961_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/Youniverse_bw_hu058abfd6177ddd8e71df0e608d9f6cd1_975961_336438933badeb8a76910cd0b748680c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Guitarist Jerguš Oravec and singer Tammy Nižňanska
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Youniverse as a band and creator collective was formed in 2015 around guitarist Jerguš Oravec and singer Tammy Nižňanska. Changing genres and forms, creating musical and visual worlds spiced up with BDSM attire they have been playing shows in Slovakia and releasing a full-length album in 2018.  Tammy is a bilingual Slovak, who is more comfortable in the English language due to her upbringing than in the country’s language, and against what she feels to be the expectation of the local audience, she sings in English.  No wonder that she is also looking for ways to expand their universe beyond the country borders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bYsOnmUeLHE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tammy believes that The Youniverse it at a crossroads.  To be more successful at home, they would have to switch to their native Slovak language, and to be more successful in English they would have to connect better to foreign audiences.  She believes that the local audiences often seek a different quality than what she offers – the purity of her voice instead of auto-tune, or the native language instead of the language of rock and roll. Therefore, their main targets are the Southwestern part of the United States, particularly Los Angeles in California and Austin in Texas, and they believe that their eccentric show would probably create interest in Japan, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do they know or think of big data algorithms? The Youniverse hired a Google Analytics manager and they try to figure out how they could reach out to fans in far away places, or to understand how their songs occasionally find their ways to people in different countries.  Tammy knows that Spotify employs playlist curators who are helped with computer-based algorithms to find new music, but she is not familiar with the process – that is why she volunteered to participate in our Listen Local project and our Feasibility Study for the creation of a Slovakian music promotion service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/artist/1TIOHaY7eRJ6jZVA1NLYrk&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; is developing transparent algorithms and open source solutions to find new audiences for independent music. We want to correct the injustice and inherent bias of market leading big data algorithms. If you want&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;your music and audience&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;to be analysed in Listen Local, fill&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in. We will include you in our demo application for local music recommendations and our analysis to be revealed in December.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-artists&#34;&gt;Other artists:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Kestner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Duka Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katarzia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-18-where-they-understand-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twentees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-04-04-wdekrey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Willemijn de Krey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-15-marie_de_la_montagne/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marie de la Montagne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a label:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tiny Rooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: Katarzia</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 15:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-katarzia-photography-by-ladislav-kyllar&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Katarzia. Photography by Ladislav Kyllar&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2020-11-25-katarzia/katarzia_avatar_hud68522c4bd457ff5afa5d5ebf9bd39ef_5502842_e23424738ddff70eaec2e3c531d4c84b.webp 400w,
               /post/2020-11-25-katarzia/katarzia_avatar_hud68522c4bd457ff5afa5d5ebf9bd39ef_5502842_6c33c8a80c9b9876902342a873af4ef1.webp 760w,
               /post/2020-11-25-katarzia/katarzia_avatar_hud68522c4bd457ff5afa5d5ebf9bd39ef_5502842_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/katarzia_avatar_hud68522c4bd457ff5afa5d5ebf9bd39ef_5502842_e23424738ddff70eaec2e3c531d4c84b.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;326&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Katarzia. Photography by Ladislav Kyllar
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katarzia, or &lt;em&gt;Katarína Kubošiová&lt;/em&gt;, is a Slovak singer, lyricist and producer. In 2020 she released her fourth album &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slnkorecords.sk/en/katarzia/celibat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Celibát&lt;/a&gt; with the main themes of loneliness and self-appreciation. Album was created in collaboration with the producer &lt;em&gt;Jonatán Pastirčák&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katarzia started her career as a folk singer. In the past years she moved on towards electronic music. She describes her current sound can as a mix of folk and electropop. The tour to promote her newest album &lt;em&gt;Celibát&lt;/em&gt; had been planned for spring 2020, unfortunately due to the Covid-19 pandemic had to be postponed indefinitely. As many other artists, Katarzia thinks that the current situation is not easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the moment, I am not working on any new projects. I am looking for a new job. Once the pandemic is over, I would like to stay where I am now, and return to the clubs to play for my audience. As I sing in Slovak, I know where my place is – I don&amp;rsquo;t want to perform abroad, of course, unless I turn to techno music. On a more personal level, I would like to live in New York – not as a musician, tough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katarzia is originally from Nitra, Slovakia and she has been living in Prague for a couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I live in Dejvice – there is a nice clubroom there, but I don&amp;rsquo;t visit that much. I enjoy going to National Theatre, Dejvice Theatre, Meetfactory, Archa Theatre and Rudolfinum. All the old classics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the restrictions during the pandemic, Katarzia managed to shoot a video for her song &lt;em&gt;Hoří i voda&lt;/em&gt; from &lt;em&gt;Celibát&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xVPDZEa0wjU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music video is a short film, directed by Jay Walker, an American who lives and works in Prague. &lt;a href=&#34;http://girlsinfilm.net/network&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Girls in film&lt;/a&gt; –- an organization that supports women in the film industry –- participated in the production of the video. The song is about women rights and equality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous albums:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generácia Y (2013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agnostika (2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antigona (2018).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/artist/5EssQRYnIgCOcvPauVySR1&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; is developing transparent algorithms and open source solutions to find new audiences for independent music. We want to correct the injustice and inherent bias of market leading big data algorithms. If you want&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;your music and audience&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;to be analysed in Listen Local, fill&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in. We will include you in our demo application for local music recommendations and our analysis to be revealed in December.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-artists&#34;&gt;Other artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Kestner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-18-where-they-understand-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twentees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-04-04-wdekrey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Willemijn de Krey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Youniverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-15-marie_de_la_montagne/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marie de la Montagne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a label:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tiny Rooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twentees: The Mountains Are Higher Next Door And They Understand Our Lyrics</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-18-where-they-understand-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 08:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-18-where-they-understand-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Living in their mid-twenties, just got out from the university to the life with the capital L. Having crisis in their workplace, try to find their identity, falling in love or getting heartbroken and anyway, just trying to be happy in this chaotic world. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://twentees.bandcamp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twentees&lt;/a&gt; writes their indie-pop songs about the typical issues and problems of the Y-generation, so it is easy to understand when you are in the same shoes, what are they singing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2015 the band released &lt;a href=&#34;https://twentees.bandcamp.com/album/sing-dance-cry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;their first album&lt;/a&gt; in English, partly as a respect to their idols like &lt;em&gt;Editors,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Bloc Party&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Vaccines&lt;/em&gt;, but also, because they were a bit afraid to write their lyrics in their native Hungarian. For their second album &lt;a href=&#34;https://twentees.bandcamp.com/album/m-land&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Múlandó&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Transient&lt;/em&gt;
they found their sound in their mother tongue, and kept releasing in Hungarian since 2018. Their next EP is just arriving&amp;hellip; soon. If you ever catch up with them after the pandemic somewhere, don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you do not understand Hungarian, just dance with the catchy rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you should do if you are in Budapest and where to go during the night? What’s on abroad for twentees? Kátya talked with their front man, Balázs Konrád &amp;ndash; or in Hungarian name order, Konrád Balázs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-are-you-coming-from&#34;&gt;Where are you coming from?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually from a town that nobody knows about outside Hungary, called Hódmezővásárhely. Try to pronounce it! Let’s just say we are from Budapest, I live here. Craft beer bars are highly recommended, but the city has pretty great pubs in general. Walking alongside the river on the Buda side offers a great panorama to the city, which includes the best looking parliament building of Europe. For daytime activities, getting on a bike and going to less busy parts, like the Danube banks &lt;em&gt;Római-part&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Kopaszi-gát&lt;/em&gt; are nice, or maybe do some downtown record store shopping. For the night time, cruising around the 6th, 7th, and 8th districts will result in good fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ncAHqleHLX4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-are-you-heading-to&#34;&gt;Where are you heading to?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Romania, particularly in the direction of Oradea, Cluj Napoca, Timișoara, because there are lots of people interested in checking out their Hungarian friends from the other side of the border and because their mountains are lovely. Bratislava and any towns with a relevant Hungarian-speaking population in Slovakia, for the same reason mentioned before, and because their mountains are also nice. There’s Serbia, too, with towns like Senta, Subotica and Novi Sad, where I was born: the local audience is the most grateful one I’ve ever seen, they are really curious for new music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we sing in Hungarian, we try to target regions where our songs can be understood, and of course it would make no sense to go and play in Berlin with our lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; is developing transparent algorithms and open source solutions to find new audiences for independent music. We want to correct the injustice and inherent bias of market leading big data algorithms. If you want&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;your music and audience&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;to be analysed in Listen Local, fill&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in. We will include you in our demo application for local music recommendations and our analysis to be revealed in December.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-artists&#34;&gt;Other artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Kestner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katarzia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Duka Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-04-04-wdekrey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Willemijn de Krey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Youniverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-15-marie_de_la_montagne/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marie de la Montagne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a label:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tiny Rooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Is Not Recommended On Spotify?</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-17-recommendation-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 11:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-17-recommendation-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are analysing how recommendations work for the artists involved in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; experiment. We created a testing database with their music and other artists from their cities, regions and countries. We need new recommendation engines to dig out from a pile of international hits the local artists.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Avoid landing on &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt;, in the universe of never listened-to-songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Understand how artists and their songs can find audience in the region relevant to their career goals, tour destinations, export opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our preliminary analysis is not representative for nationality, though we believe that we will find serious regional, linguistic and national patterns. We are using examples from Spotify. To be fair to Spotify, while their algorithm has many problems, their API is at least very open, as opposed to Apple Music where we do not really know what is going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our main concern is that some artists and their songs seem to be never recommended. Moreover, if artists and songs from a city, region or country are rarely or never recommended, then they risk losing their home market: the local audience will be recommended music that is coming outside of the city, region or country.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-artist-has-more-related-artists-as-number-popularity-and-number-of-followers-grows-nationality-may-affect-related-artists&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;streaming/spotify_related_artists_corrplot_no_title.png&#34; alt=&#34;Artist has more related artists as number popularity and number of followers grows. Nationality may affect related artists.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Artist has more related artists as number popularity and number of followers grows. Nationality may affect related artists.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important way recommendations work is via &lt;code&gt;related artists&lt;/code&gt;. If an artist has &lt;em&gt;no related artists&lt;/em&gt;, it is very unlikely that either via user browsing interaction or via the algorithm that artists or her songs will be discovered by anybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want &lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;your music and audience&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to be analysed in Listen Local, fill out&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. We will include you in our demo application and our analysis to be revealed in December.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because big data algorithms learn from user behaviour, more popular, more often selected songs, and songs selected by more users are more likely to be recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-algorithm-can-learn-more-about-popular-music-because-the-song-is-more-often-selected-by-a-larger-number-of-people&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;streaming/spotify_related_artists_popularity.png&#34; alt=&#34;The algorithm can learn more about popular music, because the song is more often selected by a larger number of people&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The algorithm can learn more about popular music, because the song is more often selected by a larger number of people
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the algorithm finds more related music, it means that it &amp;ldquo;learned&amp;rdquo; the repertoire of the artist. Artists with very little popularity tend to be related to 20-30 artists, but at a popularity level of 40-60 they are related to 30-40 artists. Seems simple, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that much. If you want the algorithm to learn your music well, you really have to go &amp;ldquo;viral&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-artist-with-less-than-1000-followers-risk-not-being-to-recommended-at-all-doubling-your-chances-to-be-discovered-requires-1000x-more-followers&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;streaming/spotify_related_artists_followers.png&#34; alt=&#34;Artist with less than 1000 followers risk not being to recommended at all. Doubling your chances to be discovered requires 1000x more followers.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Artist with less than 1000 followers risk not being to recommended at all. Doubling your chances to be discovered requires 1000x more followers.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doubling your routes to being recommended via other artists&amp;rsquo; music requires exponential growth.  You need to have &lt;code&gt;1000x&lt;/code&gt; more followers to double the routes leading to your artist profile and recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have shown, the current recommendation engines are re-enforcing the existing status quo, and they can &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;re-enforce the marginal status&lt;/a&gt; of subcultures, artists from a nation, city or region. In other words, as we often say, &lt;code&gt;big data creates injustice&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; for larger organizations and with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; analytics and recommendations for artists, managers and labels, we want to fight exactly this injustice. We are creating &lt;code&gt;transparent&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;open source&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;responsible&lt;/code&gt; tools and algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robin Kester: This Is Not Democracy</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 11:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Robin Kester is a rising star of the Dutch music scene. She released her first mini-album &lt;a href=&#34;https://robinkester.bandcamp.com/album/this-is-not-a-democracy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This is Not a Democracy&lt;/a&gt; on 11 September 2020 and received many positive reviews from the press. Despite the pandemic she managed to play several concerts throughout the country, although concerts abroad were cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Utrecht-based musician is planning her first full-length album to be released next year. How is a newly recorded artist handling the Covid-crisis? How is she palnning hear career?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where are you heading to?  What would be a city or city-based scene where you would like to play after COVID and start building your local fan base, e.g. Vienna, Antwerpen, Zürich, or other cities. Why? What attracts you there professionally or personally?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure where I’m heading. I’d like to tour internationally with my music. (But who doesn’t?) I find it very difficult to pinpoint one exact place to start building a fan base. I have always loved travelling in the UK and Ireland and I admire a lot of artists from those countries, but I can’t narrow it down to one specific location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where do you come from? What would you recommend to visit in your hometown for a fan who is coming to see your show? And are there other artists in your area/city that you would like to recommend?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m from the Netherlands and I’m currently living in Utrecht. I’d advise you to go for a nice walk around the city centre, follow the Catharijnesingel and go to a movie during the day in Springhaver or Louis Hartlooper Complex. There are plenty of other artists I’d recommend. Moon Moon Moon for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Could you recommend one of your videos from YouTube or Vimeo?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, I like this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yF5qFuFsK0E&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yF5qFuFsK0E&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Kester - Live at 3voor12 Radio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A longer interview in Dutch: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parool.nl/kunst-media/robin-kester-ik-ben-niet-dat-meisje-met-die-gitaar~b278dd59/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Kester: ‘Ik ben niet dat meisje met die gitaar’&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;I am not that girl with that guitar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The idea of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local Initiative&lt;/a&gt; to create transparent, well-documented recommendations in various apps, music education games, and to make new personal and radio  that work differently from the current streaming algorithms. We do not try to find yet another similar song to user, but we would like to find audience to a song. We want to avoid that new artists are ending up on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt; list, or among hundreds of thousands of artists that the streaming platform algorithms recommend to no-one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are an independent artist, band, label, or publisher, we encourage you to add your very short bio into our database (form &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to add several bands/artists, get in touch with us and we&amp;rsquo;ll provide you a spreadsheet), and try out our demo application. Our system will be transparent: we try to make big data algorithms work for you, not against you. We want to help you find your audience in the UK or Ireland, like for Robin, or anywhere you want to go after the pandemic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/4l5igewpicaDDBdcZlyV90&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
[Robin Kester official website](https://showcase.fm/robinkester)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not a democracy&lt;/em&gt; is a line from the closing song &lt;em&gt;Empty Head&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-artists&#34;&gt;Other artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Youniverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Duka Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katarzia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-18-where-they-understand-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twentees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-04-04-wdekrey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Willemijn de Krey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-15-marie_de_la_montagne/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marie de la Montagne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a label:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tiny Rooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Racist Music Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We want big data algorithms to work for small venues, undiscovered bands, and all artists coming from diverse walks of life. We often find that big data works against such types of users, and our Listen Local Initiative was designed to change this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big data algorithms will increase injustice and breach social norms if they are trained on biased data, or if the algorithms themselves are biased — this is why we place so much emphasis on algorithm transparency and input data transparency. Facebook, Apple, and Spotify are often criticized for helping the spread of hate, for example. But how can an algorithm turn racist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Kraemer &amp;amp; Steve Holden reported on BBC recently that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/newsbeat-54613907&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spotify, Apple Music, Deezer and YouTube found recently hosting racist music&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; and they removed it after the BBC’s investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Spotify, public playlists and “suggested artist” algorithms make it easier to find extreme content. In some cases, users created playlists that collated songs and bands associated with the National Socialist Black Metal (NSBM) movement, mainly from Eastern Europe and Russia. Anti-Semitism and glorification of the Holocaust is common in their lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can an algorithm become racist?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an algorithm is trained on the tastes and habits of white users, it will less likely recommend Black music (i.e. genres with histories in Black communities such as hip-hop or jazz, or Black artists making any genre of music) to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If music is coming from a Black community (based on genre, location, or artists with a Black identity), a racist algorithm will be less likely to recommend it to white users, according to what the algorithm predicts white users typically listen to and like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the algorithm learns that certain users have listened to and liked music with racist content, it will provide them with more racist material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can replace &lt;code&gt;black&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;white&lt;/code&gt; with any &lt;code&gt;minority&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;majority&lt;/code&gt; group.  Take &lt;code&gt;Slovak&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;American&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;major release&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;independent release&lt;/code&gt;. European independent music makers may feel a minority compared to international majors. The problem with algorithms is that they can ruthlessly reinforce injustice, because they are focused on learning how to do things better, faster, and more — but not in qualitatively different ways — than they were done before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fight for the removal of inappropriate content from the &lt;em&gt;training set&lt;/em&gt;. If you see any non-English hateful songs on these platforms, let us know, because English-language moderation is just the tip of the iceberg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the training sets of the algorithms behind sales or listening recommendations are inclusive. Our  &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local Initative&lt;/a&gt; is an early beta of a recommendation system that makes sure that locally relevant music gets recommended to locally relevant audiences, and does not need to engage in a David and Goliath fight against international giants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the external verification of the algorithm and its results. We allow multiple levels of audit for all our algorithms, and we make all critical elements of our data products open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few examples that the tides are turning:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justin Joffe: &lt;a href=&#34;https://observer.com/2017/02/capitalism-has-suppressed-black-musicians&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Capitalism Has Long Suppressed the Contributions of Black Musicians&lt;/a&gt;  2017/02/02&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Sisaro: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/01/arts/music/music-industry-black-lives-matter.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Music Industry Is Wrestling With Race. Here’s What It Has Promised&lt;/a&gt; 2020/07/01&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kali187/29537032568/in/photolist-M161Jd-Fb3bBZ-2hL9Zw2-oHvory-oHvRMx-oZY9Gw-oZZXBz-oHvMod-oZZXzR-oHvMrj-oHvo5w-7a1jrw-HmVzFz-W45Mq3-GMhHU5-26MJg25-29hg18w-vv7kap-24mAJA5-2dRDUMa-8Hk58E-7UskvS-akZE6J-E6kKTp-2V2uSq-2gsHaES-2gsGZ1K-2gsH2Ct-2gsGZre-2gsHdvw-2gsHg6G-2gsHfpX-2gsH2ok-2gsHcrY-2gsHd3c-2gsHdnf-2gsGXKt-2gsGVJV-2gsGW3R-2gsHe7S-2gsHgAK-2gsGWvu-2gsGXmx-2gsGVCc-yUw5E2-2gsGYPx-2gsGZSe-818JBs-FBqXev-gYrUWa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Janusz Kaliszczak&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was slightly edited for additional clarity by &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/author/emily-hansell-clark/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Emily&lt;/a&gt; on 25 February 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duka’s Mission: Collaborate With Musicians From Every Country On Earth</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cologne-based musician and film producer,
Damir Bašić aka Duka decided to try to collaborate with recording artists from all over the world in his new project.  Originally from Sarajevo, Bosnia-Herzegovina, he finished last year putting their former band’s songs into a 40-minute feature film &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OvJ0NlAFjCQ&amp;amp;t=1715s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Delta wave (2019) with English subtitles&lt;/a&gt; and started to look for a new music film challenge.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjcWWrl-DEnNg-qOxRZfRSg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Propeler&lt;/a&gt;, with one Bosnian ‘l’, had to move on with a new drummer, and Duka wanted to find himself a new music project in his new town, Cologne, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is now making a series of songs, where he is the author of all music and lyrics, but he is inviting recording artists from all over the word to make recorded audio and video performances. He gives much freedom to the performing artists to interpret his songs the way they like, and he dreams that one day, when the pandemia is gone, he will be able to perform the entire set live. These songs are released on all platforms that Distroid covers under the name Duka Base (see for example Spotify &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/album/1YX2VxJe0ecWwVvvdY19Jg?si=KbObLWXgR4yCKY0ZBd7DGg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/36cf6MBy60g&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=36cf6MBy60g&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Duka Base - Watch Me (feat. Amina Kamran)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duka was initially struggling with the same problem as we do in Data &amp;amp; Lyrics when we try to explain our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; projects. “It was hard at the beginning to convince artists to take a part in the show, because it was hard to describe the whole idea. After the first show, everything went better, because the artist could see exactly what I wanted from them. Now, the response is way better of course.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then it started to go smoothly. “All those artists have had their own home studios, and it went quick and well. But it&amp;rsquo;s a bit harder to record the video, because all the artists with whom I worked are musicians, and not filmmakers. All in all, I am very happy with the willingness of the artists to do it as best they can, and at the end, I am happy with the outcome. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting for me how I talked with everyone the same way I would talk with someone in Cologne. The core of producing something is the same, or at least very similar no matter where you live.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FI2KoWkeR3M&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FI2KoWkeR3M&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#3 DMM Podcast Show / PAKISTAN / Amina Kamran / &amp;ldquo;Watch Me&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of the global ambition, Duka does not make a living from creating music. He has a dayjob as a motion designer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.denkwerk.com/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Denkwerk&lt;/a&gt;, which is not connected to his musician career. He just moved to Cologne in 2018, so he is not yet integrated in the scene of the German town while he continues to follow the Sarajevo scene as much he can &amp;mdash; though, of course, his musician friends are as much stranded as anybody else in Europe in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/1YX2VxJe0ecWwVvvdY19Jg&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-artists&#34;&gt;Other artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Kestner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katarzia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Duka Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-18-where-they-understand-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twentees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-04-04-wdekrey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Willemijn de Krey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-30-youniverse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Youniverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-15-marie_de_la_montagne/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marie de la Montagne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a label:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-12-14-tinyrooms/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tiny Rooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgetify: Popular Music That Nobody Listens To</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you work on recommendation engines, particularly recommendation engines that are different from the ones developed by large media or streaming platforms, you do not want to consider goals and directions that you follow, but also the road where you do not want to end up at all. For me, Forgetify has always been a puzzling and wonderful application, because it shows purely where your artists do not want to end up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forgotify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful application that is “recommending” you songs that have never been played on Spotify.  Music from artists that has not been played by their fans, their friends or foes, brothers and sisters, children and grandchildren! I use recommendations in quotation marks, because their recommendations are usually based on your taste. Forgetify just picks you a song that has not been played on Spotify ever. (Never been played means that somebody may have started it, but very soon stopped playing the song.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What connects me to Forgetify particularly is their motto: “We love music.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can learn from their website, there are millions of Spotify songs that have been played only partially or never at all. And that is exactly the opposite that our partners want to achieve when they work with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to create several playlists with Forgetify.  All I did is that I took their “recommendation” and put it on a list, then hit next.  I skipped tracks that were not licensed to the Netherlands, or which were not music tracks but spoken words, for example sound recordings of stand-up comedies. Then I put these tracks on three lists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;something that I felt was appropriate called &lt;code&gt;classical music&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;another that is &lt;code&gt;popular music&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and another which is a mix of historical recordings, and other music which I think has such a special audience that it would not make a good mix with the other two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3Gs4kJzmFiMNMfPAuhmC6P&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eightsome Reel Pt 1&lt;/a&gt; by the &lt;em&gt;Bob Smith&amp;rsquo;s Ideal Band&lt;/em&gt; is a digitalized re-release of the LP re-release of 78&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; records from the 1930s, and it is obviosuly no competitor for a modern classical or pop music track. Even the labels &lt;code&gt;popular music&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;classical music&lt;/code&gt; would call for further explanation, but we&amp;rsquo;ll get there another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s see what we have after removing historical, traditional folk, spoken word and classical music tracks in the supposedly &lt;code&gt;popular music&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ldquo;recommendations&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/1kxZfYZBsDSdWhMVXQMCss&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to the use of the the word “recommendations”, the expression of “popular music” is a bit ironic here, because we are talking about music that is anything but popular, at least not on Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First let&amp;rsquo;s make a very short &lt;a href=&#34;#comparison&#34;&gt;comparison&lt;/a&gt; of the current global hits, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a subjective list&lt;/a&gt; that I created for this month and started to use for explaining our recommendations, my &lt;em&gt;Forgetify Pop October 2020&lt;/em&gt; list.  I will follow these songs in the coming years, and will keep adding new forgotten songs to my list. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll reflect on why these songs are &lt;a href=&#34;#forgotten&#34;&gt;forgotten&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparison&#34;&gt;A Quick Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next comparison uses some musicology and sound engineering
“features” of the songs on the three lists. These characteristics
are themselves recognized by algorithms, and they are used for Spotify’s own recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_comparison_forgetify.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything is clear from these boxplots is that there is nothing clear about forgotten songs. The boxplot&amp;rsquo;s box show the typical values of popularity or other features, and the line starting from the box still relatively frequent values.  The long boxes of the Forgetify Pop list show that there are all sorts of music on Forgetify: screechy and not, danceable and not, cheerful and sad. My subjective list is shorter and more pronounced: it contains songs that I found to be a good match to listen together.  The current global hits are less similar than my personal selection, but far more homogeneous than all those millions of songs that end up in the forgotten long tail of the catalogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;forgetify_october_features.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the only thing that connects this playlist is that the songs are not classical or world/folk music, and that they are forgotten. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/62y0aOSPRK1rL7lo780cgH&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This Time&lt;/a&gt; single from 2009 by the Intonated (3 listeners this month, including myself) is heavy guitar music. It is dark. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/album/6cCHMZdMkfhpebJ0s6rRNR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Perdido&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;em&gt;Candido Featuring Al Cohn&lt;/em&gt; album released in 1956 by the
Cándido Camero (6945 monthly listeners) is a cheerful jazz song. It is likely that this song actually has an audience, but not on Spotify. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C%C3%A1ndido_Camero&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cándido&lt;/a&gt; was born as Candido de Guerra Camero in 1921 in Havana, and with his 99 years he is one of the oldest living artists on Spotify. He recorded this album almost 40 years before the internet was opened for the public. For his life long achievement in Afro-Cuban jazz he received the National Endowment for the Arts Jazz Masters Award in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal favorite from the Forgetify Pop list is &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/21nQDfg5BMxp7vGARpOBmo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Groovy &amp;amp; Linda&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;em&gt;Neon Princess&lt;/em&gt; album released in 1968 by Tom Parrott (39 monthly listeners). It is a nice hippy song with the favorite effect of &amp;lsquo;68, the inclusion of a sitar.  The song is not very good, the sitar and the guitar make a rather chaotic mix, but Tom Parrott (born in 1944, Washington DC, United States) is not forgotten because he was bad. There are many songs on Forgetify that I would like to skip in seconds, but Parott&amp;rsquo;s music can stay with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgotten&#34;&gt;Why Are Songs Forgotten?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One seemingly trivial reason is the age of the music. The current global hits are very new releases. The songs I curated for this months were released 2-25 years ago, though some of them are featured with newer re-releases on Spotify. Many songs on Forgetify are much older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;october_popularity_age.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research and other&amp;rsquo;s research show that people &lt;em&gt;typically&lt;/em&gt; listen less and less music as they age. There are many people who listen to music lifelong, but others do it less and less, or completely drop the habit. And a large majority of the people tend to listen to similar music that she liked in her teenage years. For most young women and men, the music discovery period ends with school,  &lt;em&gt;typically&lt;/em&gt; in some post-secondary education institution. Later, they are no longer together with ther cohort peer-grew, but with people from all age and demographic groups when they work. Very few songs become perennial hits, and most of them lose their audience as the fans are getting older, and drop the habit of listening to music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can you make sure that your music will have a healthy audience for many years to come? Make sure that teenagers in your country get access to local music, for example, via the school radios, and by bringing them to local shows. That people have a chance to discover it. Build a large enough audience while your band is active who will stay loyal to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important factor is the country where the music was released. Most of the current global hits come from the United States, and some from the United Kingdom, South Korea, Germany and Russia. My personal selection included the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deus.be/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dEUS&lt;/a&gt; from Antwerpen, Belgium, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davidkitt.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;David Kitt&lt;/a&gt; from Dublin, Ireland, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theharmaleighs.com/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Harmaleighs&lt;/a&gt; Nashville, TN, are Americans who were released by
Nettwerk Music Group in Vancouver, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;country_of_origin_forgetify.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forgotten tracks come from all over the world.  Many of them are Americans, because the US has the biggest recording industry and recorded far the most songs in the last 100-120 years. But on Forgetify my first 50 finds contained songs from Brazil, Finland, France, India, Palestine and Spain, not to mention plenty of classical recordings made all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify has a global audience, but it&amp;rsquo;s main audiences are in the US, Japan, South Korea, Germany and the United Kingdom.  It&amp;rsquo;s algorithms are trained to serve these audiences, and its new content is coming from these countries. And it recommends very goods songs from these places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because concert and festival promoters, and even radio editors are often basing their decisions on YouTube, Spotify, Apple Music followers, streams and likes, the global platforms may make it extremely difficult for niche genres (for example, ancient or classical music), or small nation artists (such as Slovaks, Belgians) or older artists to get heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally do not believe that it is entirely the platform&amp;rsquo;s fault. Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local initiative&lt;/a&gt; is aiming to use these platforms better, and find global audiences for great music made in small nations and small towns, or niche genres.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: Open Collaboration Experiment &amp; Feasibility Study</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Big data creates injustice.”&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil, author of &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/roots-of-unity/review-weapons-of-math-destruction/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can train machine learning algorithms on millions of music fans, then you can very precisely find listeners in Bratislava, entire Slovakia, in the Slovak diaspora in the United States.  In Utrecht, in Flanders, in Japan. If you cannot, then your sales will be driven by Spotify, Apple, Amazon or Google’s YouTube. And you fill compete with millions, tens of million of songs in your own city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have access to the entire analytics toolkit to fine-tune your mastering, your instruments, your tempo, when you know how to plug into the radio editors pre-screening, then you have chance for airplay. If you are all small, even local content guidelines, such as national radio quotas or public radio targets will not help you, because you remain invisible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the support of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://sgda.sk/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Arts Council&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soza.sk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SOZA&lt;/a&gt;, non-profit civic association representing more than 2,600 rights holders in Slovakia and over 1 million abroad (musical works composers, lyrics and publishers), and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ci-info.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Consolidated Independent&lt;/a&gt;, a music distributor platform &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/reprexbv/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reprex&lt;/a&gt; is preparing a feasibility study for the collaborative, transparent research tool and application that helps you to find your way to radio playlists, connect to fans in your own city, country, and in other towns along viable tour routes.  Make music export more of a science than a guessing game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;listen_local_mindmap.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first step, &lt;em&gt;until the end of 2020&lt;/em&gt;, we are going to create a demo application and a feasibility study with quantitative musicologists and data scientists. The demo application will show how to use AI to place the music of the volunteering bands and labels’s repertoire on radio lists and personal playlists.  Our feasibility study will show how different local content guidelines (radio quotas, public broadcaster targets, and other tools) can affect the market share of small local and national repertoires, and will provide culture policymakers and competition authorities with insight how to make the algorithm-driven music streaming, broadcasting marketplace more even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-you-participate-in-the-experiment&#34;&gt;How can you participate in the experiment?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first phase of the experiment, &lt;strong&gt;only artists and their groups released on Spotify&lt;/strong&gt; can participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation in the experiment is free&lt;/strong&gt;.  The research findings, including potential targets for your music, will be fully open, transparent and free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an artist, you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;simply fill in a form&lt;/a&gt; identifying your music on Spotify, filling in a few biographical data about yourself (or your band, ensemble, group). We do not ask any financial data, and only very limited personal information. We only ask about city affiliations, targeted cities, age, experience level, and language of your lyrics, if you do not play instrumental music. In our experience, these factors are very important among musicology and sound engineering quality measures. (Read a bit more about our data &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/#data-use&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data use&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a &lt;strong&gt;fan of independent music&lt;/strong&gt;, please, &lt;strong&gt;forward this post&lt;/strong&gt; to a band that you would love to see in our project, or a local music venue that you would like to visit again after the covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_analysis.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project originally started out of Slovakia, Hungary, Czechia and Poland, but we only found funding in Slovakia for a low-budget, open source, open data, open collaboration experiment. &lt;strong&gt;Participation is open anywhere in the world&lt;/strong&gt;, but we are &lt;strong&gt;focusing on a viable post-covid tour route&lt;/strong&gt; around Budapest – Bratislava – Vienna – Salzburg – Munich – Ruhr – the Netherlands – Belgium. We hope to give guidance on targeting both recorded and live music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you represent several artists&lt;/strong&gt; as a talent manager, music publisher, record label, granting agency or music export office, please get in &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;touch with us&lt;/a&gt; for onboarding. We will ask you to contribute a small sum on a crowdsourcing basis to expand our experimental project, but the small financial contribution is not a mandatory requirement. (See budget and &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/#transparency&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;transparency&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October Playlist: Wounded Egos</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every month I create a playlist for my friends and myself – a habit that I have started with mixtapes. This month reflects our team’s journey into one of the world’s most prestigious &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;startup validation
lab&lt;/a&gt; in the AI field, in a year when the recession is deeper than ever since the World War 2, the music business is devastated by the pandemic, and our team is forced to lockdown, follow this excellent validation lab on Zoom screens, meet our first clients online, and learn to work together in a socially distanced way. The songs I chose are subjectively important to me, a bit maybe even controversial ones, and probably very different from the music that you are listening to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to use this example as a start of series how we are
thinking about connecting musicians and their fans in new ways with the help of AI and big data. How we are planning to bring back life to the small venues after the pandemic? How we try to keep the link between musicians and their audience alive in this very sad year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_analysis.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this chart you can see a short analysis of my &lt;code&gt;Wounded Egos&lt;/code&gt; playlist. It is a very personal, subjective playlist. Subjectivity is very important to us, because we want to use the
insights from big data and machine learning in a very personal way to
the music community: fans, artists, technicians, managers, labels,
publisher and all the ecosystem. You can play my playlist in Spotify’s embedded player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below the music player you find a very short &lt;a href=&#34;#comparison&#34;&gt;comparison&lt;/a&gt; of the current global hits and the current hits in the Netherlands on Spotify. This time I would like to illustrate the difference of my listening habits from the global mainstream, and I won&amp;rsquo;t go in depth to how we want to make more relevant recommendations. These are the difference that we are trying to capture for local music scenes, cities, countries in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen_local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you find it interesting why I chose these songs in October 2020, you read about &lt;a href=&#34;#october-playlist&#34;&gt;my choices&lt;/a&gt; as a personal recommendation at the end of the post&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/3WyQdQgSipGzQ9a7N5xC1s&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparison&#34;&gt;A Quick Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My playlist is a very subjective and curated playlist&amp;hellip; (&lt;em&gt;I curated it myself, after all!&lt;/em&gt;) These songs are very different from the songs that people are more likely listening to around me in the Netherlands, or all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My subjective list for October 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: 1. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/14LSfvkF3PS0k81FAe6PFk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wounded Egos&lt;/a&gt;  -  2. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3MKXdtTufdX4BwVbuJqFGW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sirens&lt;/a&gt;  -  3. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3A8ZDfxmb75kFl5Cqr2pIf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Panic&lt;/a&gt;  -  4. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3ezOmKfYasIe0QeWyWiucU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t Stop&lt;/a&gt;  -  5. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2rvxQwn7rGR0ZmHvwP4AmG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Michael And Heather At The Baggage Claim&lt;/a&gt;  -  6. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/6Uhhwk8oJc8SLloZIAQksB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Machinist&lt;/a&gt;  -  7. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7lBpCteEdS5WbOnzbVmWiR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Royal Screw Up&lt;/a&gt;  -  8. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/49UDOG8DoBajXTJSTqfRMg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kyoto&lt;/a&gt;  -  9. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0qZ9rwAonJvO91GK9nqqma&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Yours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Netherlands Top 50 on Spotify (3rd week of October 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;: 1. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3tjFYV6RSFtuktYl3ZtYcq&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mood (feat. iann dior)&lt;/a&gt;  -  2. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7hxHWCCAIIxFLCzvDgnQHX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lemonade (feat. Gunna, Don Toliver &amp;amp; NAV)&lt;/a&gt;  -  3. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/6cx06DFPPHchuUAcTxznu9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Head &amp;amp; Heart (feat.  MNEK)&lt;/a&gt;  -  4. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0NuAnAqjZjuGtcWXJOxUyl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;In De Schuur&lt;/a&gt;  -  5. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2MlOUXmcofMackX3bxfSwi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jerusalema (feat. Nomcebo Zikode)&lt;/a&gt;  -  6. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/5u1n1kITHCxxp8twBcZxWy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Holy (feat. Chance The Rapper)&lt;/a&gt;  -  7. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/32Q0JiYuVr2mcxfRIPyEBS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Más Más Más&lt;/a&gt;  -  8. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/4afGO0WTInDhK2C3dolz8z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;De Overkant&lt;/a&gt;  -  9. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/58trym7xUwRuXnBY7hKqC9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Door De Wind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Top 50 on Spotify (3rd week of October 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;: 1. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3tjFYV6RSFtuktYl3ZtYcq&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mood (feat. iann dior)&lt;/a&gt;  -  2. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7hxHWCCAIIxFLCzvDgnQHX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lemonade (feat. Gunna, Don Toliver &amp;amp; NAV)&lt;/a&gt;  -  3. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/4Oun2ylbjFKMPTiaSbbCih&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WAP (feat. Megan Thee Stallion)&lt;/a&gt;  -  4. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/1yoMvmasuxZfqHEipJhRbp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hawái&lt;/a&gt;  -  5. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0t1kP63rueHleOhQkYSXFY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dynamite&lt;/a&gt;  -  6. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/1tkg4EHVoqnhR6iFEXb60y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;What You Know Bout Love&lt;/a&gt;  -  7. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0PvFJmanyNQMseIFrU708S&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;For The Night (feat. Lil Baby &amp;amp; DaBaby)&lt;/a&gt;  -  8. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0VjIjW4GlUZAMYd2vXMi3b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blinding Lights&lt;/a&gt;  -  9. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/5u1n1kITHCxxp8twBcZxWy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Holy (feat. Chance The Rapper)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The most streamed songs in the Netherlands overlap with the most streamed songs all over the world, but there is no overlap with my list.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to create locally relevant recommendations. If you live in
Antwerpen, and you are looking for bands that you can see on a small
stage after the pandemic, we will recommend you great music from
Northwestern Belgium and the South of Holland. If you want to visit San Diego after the pandemic, we’ll recommend you music from the San Diego scene. If you want to fill up with good music a local content quota, such as a national and city relevant quota in your radio, we will help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next comparison uses some musicology and sound engineering
“features” of the songs on the three lists. These characteristics
are themselves recognized by algorithms, and they are used for Spotify’s own recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_comparison.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt; My songs
are independent songs, far less popular than the global hits. My
playlist is mainly indie rock, so far less danceable, less loud than the current hits, but it is more energetic! The average tempo is similar to the hits, but I tend to chose slower songs, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s &lt;code&gt;valence&lt;/code&gt; is a quantitative measure that aims to capture the
positiveness conveyed by the a sound recording(e.g.happy, cheerful,
euphoric on the positive side, and sad, depressed, angry on the negative side). Another striking difference among my list and the two hitlists is the far broader scale of emotions conveyed by the songs that I selected for October 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next blogposts we will explain some details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-playlist&#34;&gt;Wounded Egos: Daniel’s October Playlist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Gaz Coombes - &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/14LSfvkF3PS0k81FAe6PFk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wounded Egos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting up a company, building a team in the times of corona, social
distancing, zoom calls and narcissistic world leaders is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. dEUS - &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3MKXdtTufdX4BwVbuJqFGW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sirens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“You gotta pick your fights, you’ve got work to do”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which makes you think that you have to resist the Sirens call. This
record came out the day before I went to my CFA exam, which was the most gruelling test in my life. I just downloaded it, put it on the car hifi, pressed play and did the 8 hour test without error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Harmaleighs - &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3A8ZDfxmb75kFl5Cqr2pIf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Don’t Panic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“But what if that’s all I’m good at?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t Panic surprised me so much that it found its way to my September
and October playlist, too. If something is perfect, it is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon Spencer Blues Explosion - &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3ezOmKfYasIe0QeWyWiucU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Can’t
Stop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I just can’t stop”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I need to go back to the basics. Jon Spencer is as good as
Elvis must have been on stage. I never saw Elvis on stage, I am too
young for that, but old enough to have seen Jon Spencer on a large and
small stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fountains of Wayne - &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2rvxQwn7rGR0ZmHvwP4AmG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Michael And Heather At The Baggage Claim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Michael &amp;amp; Heather at the baggage claim tired of playing the waiting
game”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The covid pandemic not only froze the entire music industry, and put
many artists, venues, managers, technicians on life support, but claimed many lives in the audience and in the music community. I still come to tears when I recall that early March day when I learned that Adam Schlesinger, my favourite lyricist and songwriter died. I was alwayshoping that I will show him what we were doing. We will certainly dedicate something to his memory along the way. For 15 years, when I was sad, I just picked one of the Fountains of Wayne records, and put it on. For this playlist, I chose a bittersweet song, which probably has the best poetry written in independent music ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify falls for the typical Schlesinger trick: the melody is very
upbeat, the lyrics is bittersweet. Spotify risks to put it into the
positive and danceable category, at least, within my list, though I find it just a bit less gloomy than &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3A8ZDfxmb75kFl5Cqr2pIf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Don’t
Panic&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7lBpCteEdS5WbOnzbVmWiR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Royal Screw
Up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japanese Breakfast - &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/6Uhhwk8oJc8SLloZIAQksB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Machinist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How can I fight a kingdom of your demons?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t complain about the big algorithms of the big company. Spotify’s algorithm brought Japanese Breakfast to me. We just want to take a less individualist approach to making recommendations. Michelle Zauner is on the feminine side of this list, and I just can’t get enough of her music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s analysis finds this song to be less danceable and dark, which is exactly why Japanese Breakfast is such a curious artist project. It is experimental pop music that twists well-known pop clichés into original new songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soccer Mommy - &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7lBpCteEdS5WbOnzbVmWiR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Royal Screw Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“And I want an answer to all my problems”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Soccer Mommy’s new record came out in March, I could not resist
reaching out to the sound engineering team to convey my congratulations. Soccer Mommy is the youngest artist on this list with a huge talent, and the team that she works with is just world class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phoebe Bridgers - &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/49UDOG8DoBajXTJSTqfRMg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kyoto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You called me from a payphone / They still got pay phones”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular song on the playlist, a true global independent hit.
Phoebe Bridgers is hot, and she &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/155586901702555/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;may be a
killer&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Kitt - &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0qZ9rwAonJvO91GK9nqqma&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;It’s Yours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify sees this song as the most danceable and most positive song. And it is so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/initiatives/listen-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/initiatives/listen-local/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Big data creates injustice.”&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil, author of &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/roots-of-unity/review-weapons-of-math-destruction/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Listen Local project is aiming to create better radio playlisting, personal playlisting and concert promotion in a local context: within Slovakia or at a more specific level, Flanders or even the city of Utrecht or Budapest. We aim to place our partner’s music in local radio lists, personal playlists, and grow their fan base during the COVID-19 pandemic so that in 2021 they can eventually meet in the venues again, and carry out longer, more successful tours than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Signing up for artists, labels, talent managers&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#signup&#34;&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-problem&#34;&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are listening to music on Spotify or Apple Music, and at home on YouTube.  They are following advice from algorithms tested on hundreds of millions of people. Anybody can create playlists, but mainly Spotify, Apple, or YouTube create the playlists with their AI algorithms and their staff and their interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local: Open Collaboration Experiment &amp;amp; Feasibility Study&lt;/a&gt; - how you can participate in the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify: Popular Music That Nobody Listens To&lt;/a&gt; - because you do not want to end up on the list of 0 streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-17-recommendation-analysis/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Who Is Not Recommended On Spotify&lt;/a&gt; - you need to have 1000x more followers to double the routes leading to your artist profile and recordings with the current algorithms. We need new recommendation engines to dig out the local artists buried under a pile of international hits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Racist Music Algorithm&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; big data algorithms will increase injustice and breach social norms if they are trained on improper data, or the algorithms are biased. This is why we are working on transparent, peer-reviewed, open source alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This Is Not Democracy&lt;/a&gt; - Robin Kester is one of the first artists who is looking for alternative recommendation routes towards the UK and Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-18-where-they-understand-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Mountains Are Higher Next Door And They Understand Our Lyrics&lt;/a&gt; - the Twentees are flying under the radar in Slovakia, Serbia, Romania, because they sing in a minority language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;October Playlist: Wounded Egos&lt;/a&gt; - a short case study of a playlist analysis and comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;signup&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Do This Together!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are an artist, you can&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;simply fill in a form&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;identifying your music on Spotify, filling in a few biographical data about yourself (or your band, ensemble, group). If you represent several artists as a talent manager, music publisher, record label, granting agency or music export office, please get in&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;touch with us&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;for onboarding.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aiming to create an alternative market measurement, marketing and recommendation engine tool that is based on open source software, open collaboration, full scientific transparency in an open collaboration with artists, small businesses and the entire music ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;create new playlists&lt;/strong&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s build up a weekly, relevant, non-exclusive playlists for music coming from Utrecht, Antwerpen, Rotterdam, Den Haag, Flanders or the Netherlands that smoothly blend in local music with relevant, spiritually or musically matching songs that fans of the Utrecht, Antwerpen, Rotterdam, Den Haag bands like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;create apps&lt;/strong&gt;!  If &lt;a href=&#34;https://forgotify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt; can pick out songs that nobody, ever, ever listened to on Spotify, not even the performer&amp;rsquo;s mother, sister, friends, not even their enemies, than we can must create new apps that allows fans in Utrecht, visitors or Rotterdam and the virtual community of Den Haag to find relevant music, and to connect with music created in these communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;We are&lt;/a&gt; a bunch of musicians, musicologists, music analysts, music journalists, producers who want to make this happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-use&#34;&gt;Data Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From participating artists we only ask questions that they usually post on their websites or would tell to music journalists or bloggers. We will put all this information (with some clearly stated exceptions in the registration form) on the website of the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use similar data used to analyze &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this playlist&lt;/a&gt; about the participants&amp;rsquo; music. This data is an analysis of their released music, not about the persons who play the music, or their earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not ask for any financial data, and we do not have access to any financial data of the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transparency&#34;&gt;Transparency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; grew out of a large, collaborative project of collective management societies, grant managers, music distributors, venues, and other music stakeholders who joined forces to collect more royalties from 2014 onwards starting with three, and eventually encompassing more than a dozen countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire budget of our project is 10,000 euros, co-funded by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://sgda.sk/about-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Arts Council&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://soza.sk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SOZA&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ci-info.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Consolidated Independent&lt;/a&gt;, a distributor of independent music. We hope that this will be enough to create a demonstration and a detailed feasibility study that makes the user needs of Slovak managers, labels, publishers and artists themselves to continue this project in 2021. The project will be carried out by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/reprexbv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reprex&lt;/a&gt;, a Dutch start-up co-founded by the author of the Slovak Music Industry Report, the first Hungarian Music Industry Report, Private Copying in Croatia, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation for artists and music venues is &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; in the experiment. In 2020, we would like to find a viable business model that keeps this tool a good value for money for anybody in the independent music scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are asking labels, publishers, talent managers to contribute to our experimental budget on a crowdsourcing basis at a later stage, if they will continue to use this service in 2021. Currently our experiment is free.  &lt;em&gt;Signing up for artists, labels, talent managers&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#signup&#34;&gt;above&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!---
[[gallery_item]]
album: &#34;gallery&#34;
image: &#34;spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915.png&#34;
caption: &#34;National repertoire market shares on national Spotify hitlists, 15 September 2019.&#34;

[[gallery_item]]
album: &#34;gallery&#34;
image: &#34;eu_cross_border_hits_20190915.png&#34;
caption: &#34;European hits on an other European country&#39;s Spotify hitlist, 15 September 2019.&#34;
---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we take a look at the streaming charts of the region, we usually find that the vast majority of the streamed songs are foreign songs - except for Austria, U.S. songs.  For comparison, we added a similar, middle-income emerging market (Argentina) and a rich, small-population English-speaking country, Australia to the chart. These countries seem to be in a similar position to the CEE countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/dataanimation/domestic_market_share_animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Market shares August-September 2019&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably, the strongest countries of songwriting are the United States and Brazil - these are the countries that have ran out of the ISRC recording identifier range. Their charts are full with their domestic songs, but they are not alone.  Japan, France, and the bigger EU countries, France, Germany and Poland have very strong domestic performance, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are many factor at play here. Large countries with large artist populations generate a lot more recordings, so they local fans always have thousands of new songs to select from.  In small countries, the total annual creations, from pop to jazz, from authentic folk to classical amounts to a few thousand tracks. But it is not only size that matters.  Sweden&amp;rsquo;s population is similar to that of Austria, Hungary and Czechia, yet the Swedish repertoire performs better in Sweden, and as we will see in the next chart, abroad, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created a second data animation to visualize how hits were travelling across the borders in the summer of 2ö19. To make the chart easier to read, we omitted the United States, Brazil and Japan as countries of origin, and concentrated only on intra-European hit flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/dataanimation/cross_border_plot-animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Cross-border hits August-September 2019&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second week of September 2019 was not an exceptional week. Most EU countries&amp;rsquo; producers did not score any hits in any other EU countries&amp;rsquo; Spotify Top 50 hits.  The UK exported many great hits to all over Europe, as usual, but there were other important hit flows. These hits mainly follow cultural proximity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France exported hits to the two Francophone countries of Europe, Belgium and Romania, and furthermore to Greece, a Southern country with particularly unique chart composition. Germany exported many hits to Austria, another German-speaking country, and some hits to other Germanic countries. Dutch producers placed a few hits in the Germanic countries and in Belgium, where the Dutch-speaking Flemish community has its own radios, TVs, press and hitlists. The Netherlands is a powerhouse of electronic popmusic that are not bound by language which finds audience in several countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strength and competitive position of the national market where an artists is most known and has a fan base is usually a determining factor of track performance and revenue.  The overall revenue prospects and competition situation of a Hungarian or Croatian song is very different from a British or even a Polish song.  But overall, most European recordings are not bound to a domestic country. Because of cultural proximity, the presence of native minorities or new immigrant diasporas, even small-language songs are being listened to on a much wider territory than the artists&amp;rsquo; original country. Some relatively small EU countries, such as Sweden and the Netherlands successfully export their music on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, as the streaming services slowly overtake all other forms of use, the charts above depict a very fundamental market change.  Whereas in the traditional channels of physical sales, digital downloads and broadcasting, the CEE countries, like other small- and medium-sized EU countries, enjoyed 30-50% market share, among the streaming hits their producer&amp;rsquo;s share is below 10%. It is not unusual to find only domestic recordings in physical sales hitlists, while domestic songs rarely enter the streaming charts in the region, with the exception of Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional sales channels protected CEE markets in several ways.  After EU accession most import duties are gone, but physical products have very significant logistics costs, which gives local producers a competitive edge.  Because physical products are increasingly sold on concerts and festivals, where the market share of domestic performers is usually very high, the traditional, mechanically licensed sales had a protected market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The broadcasting channel, which used the be the most important promotion channel, too, was protected in many European countries by national content quotas, or supported with generously funded national, regional, local public broadcasters who gave a preference to national composers, producers and performers. These market barriers are not present in the streaming markets, which poses many questions. Our research is aiming to answer these questions, but it took several years to build a data infrastructure that can help producing an accurate market overview.&lt;/p&gt;












&lt;div class=&#34;gallery-grid&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-2019-09-23_cross-border-europe&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/2019-09-23_cross-border-europe/eu_cross_border_hits_20190915.png&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/2019-09-23_cross-border-europe/eu_cross_border_hits_20190915_hu87f5dcff746518fbceefbd4abed84ec5_40449_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;eu_cross_border_hits_20190915.png&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;536&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-2019-09-23_cross-border-europe&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/2019-09-23_cross-border-europe/spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915.png&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/media/albums/2019-09-23_cross-border-europe/spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915_hu781d82e369311575b56de92db7530f5f_19890_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915.png&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;536&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These findings will be open to discussion on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/waves_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Waves Music Showcase Festival and Conference&lt;/a&gt; [click for details] &lt;em&gt;on 27 September 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
