<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>listen-local | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>listen-local</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 08:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>listen-local</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Racist Music Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We want big data algorithms to work for small venues, undiscovered bands, and all artists coming from diverse walks of life. We often find that big data works against them, and our Listen Local Initiative was designed to change this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big data algorithms will increase injustice and breach social norms if they are trained on improper data, or the algorithms are biased &amp;ndash; this is why we place so much emphasis on algorithm transparency and input data transparency. Facebook, Apple or Spotify are often criticized for helping the spread of hate, for example.  But how can an algorithm turn racist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Kraemer &amp;amp; Steve Holden reported on BBC recently that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/newsbeat-54613907&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spotify, Apple Music, Deezer and YouTube found recently hosting racist music&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; and they removed it after the BBC’s investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Spotify, public playlists and &amp;ldquo;suggested artists&amp;rdquo; did make it easier to find extreme content: In some cases, users created playlists that collated songs and bands associated with the National Socialist Black Metal (NSBM) movement, mainly from Eastern Europe and Russia. Anti-Semitism and glorification of the Holocaust was commonn in their lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can an algorithm become racist?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is trained on the tastes and habits of “white people”, it will less likely recommend “black music.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a music is coming from a “black” community, it will probably not recommend it in the “white community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the algorithm learns that taste of racists people, it will provide them with more racist material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can replace &lt;code&gt;black&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;white&lt;/code&gt; with any &lt;code&gt;minority&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;majority&lt;/code&gt; group.  Take &lt;code&gt;Slovak&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;American&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;major release&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;independent release&lt;/code&gt;. European independent music makers may feel a minority compared to international majors.  The problem with algorithms is that they can ruthlessly reinforce injustice, because they just learn how to do something better, faster, and more than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fight for the removal of inappropriate content from the &lt;em&gt;training set&lt;/em&gt;. If you see any non-English hateful songs on these platforms, let us know, because English-language moderation is just the tip of the iceberg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the training sets of the algorithms behind sales or listening recommendations are inclusive. Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local Initative&lt;/a&gt; is an early beta of a recommendation system that makes sure that locally relevant music gets recommended to locally relevant audiences, and does not need to go into an uneven fight with giants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the external verification of the algorithm and its results. We will allow multiple levels of audit for all our algorithms, and we make all critical elements of our data products open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few examples that the tides are turning:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justin Joffe: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://observer.com/2017/02/capitalism-has-suppressed-black-musicians&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Capitalism Has Long Suppressed the Contributions of Black Musicians&lt;/a&gt;  2017/02/02&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Sisaro: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/01/arts/music/music-industry-black-lives-matter.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Music Industry Is Wrestling With Race. Here’s What It Has Promised&lt;/a&gt; 2020/07/01&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kali187/29537032568/in/photolist-M161Jd-Fb3bBZ-2hL9Zw2-oHvory-oHvRMx-oZY9Gw-oZZXBz-oHvMod-oZZXzR-oHvMrj-oHvo5w-7a1jrw-HmVzFz-W45Mq3-GMhHU5-26MJg25-29hg18w-vv7kap-24mAJA5-2dRDUMa-8Hk58E-7UskvS-akZE6J-E6kKTp-2V2uSq-2gsHaES-2gsGZ1K-2gsH2Ct-2gsGZre-2gsHdvw-2gsHg6G-2gsHfpX-2gsH2ok-2gsHcrY-2gsHd3c-2gsHdnf-2gsGXKt-2gsGVJV-2gsGW3R-2gsHe7S-2gsHgAK-2gsGWvu-2gsGXmx-2gsGVCc-yUw5E2-2gsGYPx-2gsGZSe-818JBs-FBqXev-gYrUWa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Janusz Kaliszczak&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duka’s Mission: Collaborate With Musicians From Every Country On Earth</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-28-duka-mission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cologne-based musician and film producer, 
Damir Bašić aka Duka decided to try to collaborate with recording artists from all over the world in his new project.  Originally from Sarajevo, Bosnia-Herzegovina, he finished last year putting their former band’s songs into a 40-minute feature film 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OvJ0NlAFjCQ&amp;amp;t=1715s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Delta wave (2019) with English subtitles&lt;/a&gt; and started to look for a new music film challenge.  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjcWWrl-DEnNg-qOxRZfRSg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Propeler&lt;/a&gt;, with one Bosnian ‘l’, had to move on with a new drummer, and Duka wanted to find himself a new music project in his new town, Cologne, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is now making a series of songs, where he is the author of all music and lyrics, but he is inviting recording artists from all over the word to make recorded audio and video performances. He gives much freedom to the performing artists to interpret his songs the way they like, and he dreams that one day, when the pandemia is gone, he will be able to perform the entire set live. These songs are released on all platforms that Distroid covers under the name Duka Base (see for example Spotify 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/album/1YX2VxJe0ecWwVvvdY19Jg?si=KbObLWXgR4yCKY0ZBd7DGg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/36cf6MBy60g&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=36cf6MBy60g&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Duka Base - Watch Me (feat. Amina Kamran)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duka was initially struggling with the same problem as we do in Data &amp;amp; Lyrics when we try to explain our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; projects. “It was hard at the beginning to convince artists to take a part in the show, because it was hard to describe the whole idea. After the first show, everything went better, because the artist could see exactly what I wanted from them. Now, the response is way better of course.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then it started to go smoothly. “All those artists have had their own home studios, and it went quick and well. But it&amp;rsquo;s a bit harder to record the video, because all the artists with whom I worked are musicians, and not filmmakers. All in all, I am very happy with the willingness of the artists to do it as best they can, and at the end, I am happy with the outcome. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting for me how I talked with everyone the same way I would talk with someone in Cologne. The core of producing something is the same, or at least very similar no matter where you live.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FI2KoWkeR3M&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FI2KoWkeR3M&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#3 DMM Podcast Show / PAKISTAN / Amina Kamran / &amp;ldquo;Watch Me&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of the global ambition, Duka does not make a living from creating music. He has a dayjob as a motion designer at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.denkwerk.com/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Denkwerk&lt;/a&gt;, which is not connected to his musician career. He just moved to Cologne in 2018, so he is not yet integrated in the scene of the German town while he continues to follow the Sarajevo scene as much he can &amp;mdash; though, of course, his musician friends are as much stranded as anybody else in Europe in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/1YX2VxJe0ecWwVvvdY19Jg&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgetify: Popular Music That Nobody Listens To</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you work on recommendation engines, particularly recommendation engines that are different from the ones developed by large media or streaming platforms, you do not want to consider goals and directions that you follow, but also the road where you do not want to end up at all. For me, Forgetify has always been a puzzling and wonderful application, because it shows purely where your artists do not want to end up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forgotify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful application that is “recommending” you songs that have never been played on Spotify.  Music from artists that has not been played by their fans, their friends or foes, brothers and sisters, children and grandchildren! I use recommendations in quotation marks, because their recommendations are usually based on your taste. Forgetify just picks you a song that has not been played on Spotify ever. (Never been played means that somebody may have started it, but very soon stopped playing the song.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What connects me to Forgetify particularly is their motto: “We love music.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can learn from their website, there are millions of Spotify songs that have been played only partially or never at all. And that is exactly the opposite that our partners want to achieve when they work with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to create several playlists with Forgetify.  All I did is that I took their “recommendation” and put it on a list, then hit next.  I skipped tracks that were not licensed to the Netherlands, or which were not music tracks but spoken words, for example sound recordings of stand-up comedies. Then I put these tracks on three lists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;something that I felt was appropriate called &lt;code&gt;classical music&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;another that is &lt;code&gt;popular music&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and another which is a mix of historical recordings, and other music which I think has such a special audience that it would not make a good mix with the other two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3Gs4kJzmFiMNMfPAuhmC6P&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eightsome Reel Pt 1&lt;/a&gt; by the &lt;em&gt;Bob Smith&amp;rsquo;s Ideal Band&lt;/em&gt; is a digitalized re-release of the LP re-release of 78&#39;&#39; records from the 1930s, and it is obviosuly no competitor for a modern classical or pop music track. Even the labels &lt;code&gt;popular music&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;classical music&lt;/code&gt; would call for further explanation, but we&amp;rsquo;ll get there another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s see what we have after removing historical, traditional folk, spoken word and classical music tracks in the supposedly &lt;code&gt;popular music&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ldquo;recommendations&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/1kxZfYZBsDSdWhMVXQMCss&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to the use of the the word “recommendations”, the expression of “popular music” is a bit ironic here, because we are talking about music that is anything but popular, at least not on Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First let&amp;rsquo;s make a very short 
&lt;a href=&#34;#comparison&#34;&gt;comparison&lt;/a&gt; of the current global hits, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a subjective list&lt;/a&gt; that I created for this month and started to use for explaining our recommendations, my &lt;em&gt;Forgetify Pop October 2020&lt;/em&gt; list.  I will follow these songs in the coming years, and will keep adding new forgotten songs to my list. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll reflect on why these songs are 
&lt;a href=&#34;#forgotten&#34;&gt;forgotten&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparison&#34;&gt;A Quick Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next comparison uses some musicology and sound engineering
“features” of the songs on the three lists. These characteristics
are themselves recognized by algorithms, and they are used for Spotify’s own recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_comparison_forgetify.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything is clear from these boxplots is that there is nothing clear about forgotten songs. The boxplot&amp;rsquo;s box show the typical values of popularity or other features, and the line starting from the box still relatively frequent values.  The long boxes of the Forgetify Pop list show that there are all sorts of music on Forgetify: screechy and not, danceable and not, cheerful and sad. My subjective list is shorter and more pronounced: it contains songs that I found to be a good match to listen together.  The current global hits are less similar than my personal selection, but far more homogeneous than all those millions of songs that end up in the forgotten long tail of the catalogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;forgetify_october_features.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the only thing that connects this playlist is that the songs are not classical or world/folk music, and that they are forgotten. The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/62y0aOSPRK1rL7lo780cgH&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This Time&lt;/a&gt; single from 2009 by the Intonated (3 listeners this month, including myself) is heavy guitar music. It is dark. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/album/6cCHMZdMkfhpebJ0s6rRNR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Perdido&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;em&gt;Candido Featuring Al Cohn&lt;/em&gt; album released in 1956 by the 
Cándido Camero (6945 monthly listeners) is a cheerful jazz song. It is likely that this song actually has an audience, but not on Spotify. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C%C3%A1ndido_Camero&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cándido&lt;/a&gt; was born as Candido de Guerra Camero in 1921 in Havana, and with his 99 years he is one of the oldest living artists on Spotify. He recorded this album almost 40 years before the internet was opened for the public. For his life long achievement in Afro-Cuban jazz he received the National Endowment for the Arts Jazz Masters Award in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal favorite from the Forgetify Pop list is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/21nQDfg5BMxp7vGARpOBmo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Groovy &amp;amp; Linda&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;em&gt;Neon Princess&lt;/em&gt; album released in 1968 by Tom Parrott (39 monthly listeners). It is a nice hippy song with the favorite effect of &amp;lsquo;68, the inclusion of a sitar.  The song is not very good, the sitar and the guitar make a rather chaotic mix, but Tom Parrott (born in 1944, Washington DC, United States) is not forgotten because he was bad. There are many songs on Forgetify that I would like to skip in seconds, but Parott&amp;rsquo;s music can stay with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgotten&#34;&gt;Why Are Songs Forgotten?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One seemingly trivial reason is the age of the music. The current global hits are very new releases. The songs I curated for this months were released 2-25 years ago, though some of them are featured with newer re-releases on Spotify. Many songs on Forgetify are much older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_popularity_age.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research and other&amp;rsquo;s research show that people &lt;em&gt;typically&lt;/em&gt; listen less and less music as they age. There are many people who listen to music lifelong, but others do it less and less, or completely drop the habit. And a large majority of the people tend to listen to similar music that she liked in her teenage years. For most young women and men, the music discovery period ends with school,  &lt;em&gt;typically&lt;/em&gt; in some post-secondary education institution. Later, they are no longer together with ther cohort peer-grew, but with people from all age and demographic groups when they work. Very few songs become perennial hits, and most of them lose their audience as the fans are getting older, and drop the habit of listening to music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can you make sure that your music will have a healthy audience for many years to come? Make sure that teenagers in your country get access to local music, for example, via the school radios, and by bringing them to local shows. That people have a chance to discover it. Build a large enough audience while your band is active who will stay loyal to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important factor is the country where the music was released. Most of the current global hits come from the United States, and some from the United Kingdom, South Korea, Germany and Russia. My personal selection included the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deus.be/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dEUS&lt;/a&gt; from Antwerpen, Belgium, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davidkitt.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;David Kitt&lt;/a&gt; from Dublin, Ireland, and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theharmaleighs.com/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Harmaleighs&lt;/a&gt; Nashville, TN, are Americans who were released by 
Nettwerk Music Group in Vancouver, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;country_of_origin_forgetify.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forgotten tracks come from all over the world.  Many of them are Americans, because the US has the biggest recording industry and recorded far the most songs in the last 100-120 years. But on Forgetify my first 50 finds contained songs from Brazil, Finland, France, India, Palestine and Spain, not to mention plenty of classical recordings made all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify has a global audience, but it&amp;rsquo;s main audiences are in the US, Japan, South Korea, Germany and the United Kingdom.  It&amp;rsquo;s algorithms are trained to serve these audiences, and its new content is coming from these countries. And it recommends very goods songs from these places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because concert and festival promoters, and even radio editors are often basing their decisions on YouTube, Spotify, Apple Music followers, streams and likes, the global platforms may make it extremely difficult for niche genres (for example, ancient or classical music), or small nation artists (such as Slovaks, Belgians) or older artists to get heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally do not believe that it is entirely the platform&amp;rsquo;s fault. Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local initiative&lt;/a&gt; is aiming to use these platforms better, and find global audiences for great music made in small nations and small towns, or niche genres.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: Open Collaboration Experiment &amp; Feasibility Study</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Big data creates injustice.”&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil, author of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/roots-of-unity/review-weapons-of-math-destruction/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can train machine learning algorithms on millions of music fans, then you can very precisely find listeners in Bratislava, entire Slovakia, in the Slovak diaspora in the United States.  In Utrecht, in Flanders, in Japan. If you cannot, then your sales will be driven by Spotify, Apple, Amazon or Google’s YouTube. And you fill compete with millions, tens of million of songs in your own city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have access to the entire analytics toolkit to fine-tune your mastering, your instruments, your tempo, when you know how to plug into the radio editors pre-screening, then you have chance for airplay. If you are all small, even local content guidelines, such as national radio quotas or public radio targets will not help you, because you remain invisible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the support of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sgda.sk/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Arts Council&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soza.sk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SOZA&lt;/a&gt;, non-profit civic association representing more than 2,600 rights holders in Slovakia and over 1 million abroad (musical works composers, lyrics and publishers), and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ci-info.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Consolidated Independent&lt;/a&gt;, a music distributor platform 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/reprexbv/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reprex&lt;/a&gt; is preparing a feasibility study for the collaborative, transparent research tool and application that helps you to find your way to radio playlists, connect to fans in your own city, country, and in other towns along viable tour routes.  Make music export more of a science than a guessing game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;listen_local_mindmap.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first step, &lt;em&gt;until the end of 2020&lt;/em&gt;, we are going to create a demo application and a feasibility study with quantitative musicologists and data scientists. The demo application will show how to use AI to place the music of the volunteering bands and labels’s repertoire on radio lists and personal playlists.  Our feasibility study will show how different local content guidelines (radio quotas, public broadcaster targets, and other tools) can affect the market share of small local and national repertoires, and will provide culture policymakers and competition authorities with insight how to make the algorithm-driven music streaming, broadcasting marketplace more even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-you-participate-in-the-experiment&#34;&gt;How can you participate in the experiment?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first phase of the experiment, &lt;strong&gt;only artists and their groups released on Spotify&lt;/strong&gt; can participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation in the experiment is free&lt;/strong&gt;.  The research findings, including potential targets for your music, will be fully open, transparent and free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an artist, you can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;simply fill in a form&lt;/a&gt; identifying your music on Spotify, filling in a few biographical data about yourself (or your band, ensemble, group). We do not ask any financial data, and only very limited personal information. We only ask about city affiliations, targeted cities, age, experience level, and language of your lyrics, if you do not play instrumental music. In our experience, these factors are very important among musicology and sound engineering quality measures. (Read a bit more about our data 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/#data-use&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data use&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a &lt;strong&gt;fan of independent music&lt;/strong&gt;, please, &lt;strong&gt;forward this post&lt;/strong&gt; to a band that you would love to see in our project, or a local music venue that you would like to visit again after the covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_analysis.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project originally started out of Slovakia, Hungary, Czechia and Poland, but we only found funding in Slovakia for a low-budget, open source, open data, open collaboration experiment. &lt;strong&gt;Participation is open anywhere in the world&lt;/strong&gt;, but we are &lt;strong&gt;focusing on a viable post-covid tour route&lt;/strong&gt; around Budapest – Bratislava – Vienna – Salzburg – Munich – Ruhr – the Netherlands – Belgium. We hope to give guidance on targeting both recorded and live music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you represent several artists&lt;/strong&gt; as a talent manager, music publisher, record label, granting agency or music export office, please get in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;touch with us&lt;/a&gt; for onboarding. We will ask you to contribute a small sum on a crowdsourcing basis to expand our experimental project, but the small financial contribution is not a mandatory requirement. (See budget and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/#transparency&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;transparency&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October Playlist: Wounded Egos</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every month I create a playlist for my friends and myself – a habit that I have started with mixtapes. This month reflects our team’s journey into one of the world’s most prestigious 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;startup validation
lab&lt;/a&gt; in the AI field, in a year when the recession is deeper than ever since the World War 2, the music business is devastated by the pandemic, and our team is forced to lockdown, follow this excellent validation lab on Zoom screens, meet our first clients online, and learn to work together in a socially distanced way. The songs I chose are subjectively important to me, a bit maybe even controversial ones, and probably very different from the music that you are listening to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to use this example as a start of series how we are
thinking about connecting musicians and their fans in new ways with the help of AI and big data. How we are planning to bring back life to the small venues after the pandemic? How we try to keep the link between musicians and their audience alive in this very sad year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_analysis.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this chart you can see a short analysis of my &lt;code&gt;Wounded Egos&lt;/code&gt; playlist. It is a very personal, subjective playlist. Subjectivity is very important to us, because we want to use the
insights from big data and machine learning in a very personal way to
the music community: fans, artists, technicians, managers, labels,
publisher and all the ecosystem. You can play my playlist in Spotify’s embedded player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below the music player you find a very short 
&lt;a href=&#34;#comparison&#34;&gt;comparison&lt;/a&gt; of the current global hits and the current hits in the Netherlands on Spotify. This time I would like to illustrate the difference of my listening habits from the global mainstream, and I won&amp;rsquo;t go in depth to how we want to make more relevant recommendations. These are the difference that we are trying to capture for local music scenes, cities, countries in our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen_local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you find it interesting why I chose these songs in October 2020, you read about 
&lt;a href=&#34;#october-playlist&#34;&gt;my choices&lt;/a&gt; as a personal recommendation at the end of the post&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/3WyQdQgSipGzQ9a7N5xC1s&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparison&#34;&gt;A Quick Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My playlist is a very subjective and curated playlist&amp;hellip; (&lt;em&gt;I curated it myself, after all!&lt;/em&gt;) These songs are very different from the songs that people are more likely listening to around me in the Netherlands, or all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My subjective list for October 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: 1. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/14LSfvkF3PS0k81FAe6PFk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wounded Egos&lt;/a&gt;  -  2. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3MKXdtTufdX4BwVbuJqFGW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sirens&lt;/a&gt;  -  3. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3A8ZDfxmb75kFl5Cqr2pIf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Panic&lt;/a&gt;  -  4. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3ezOmKfYasIe0QeWyWiucU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t Stop&lt;/a&gt;  -  5. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2rvxQwn7rGR0ZmHvwP4AmG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Michael And Heather At The Baggage Claim&lt;/a&gt;  -  6. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/6Uhhwk8oJc8SLloZIAQksB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Machinist&lt;/a&gt;  -  7. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7lBpCteEdS5WbOnzbVmWiR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Royal Screw Up&lt;/a&gt;  -  8. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/49UDOG8DoBajXTJSTqfRMg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kyoto&lt;/a&gt;  -  9. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0qZ9rwAonJvO91GK9nqqma&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Yours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Netherlands Top 50 on Spotify (3rd week of October 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;: 1. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3tjFYV6RSFtuktYl3ZtYcq&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mood (feat. iann dior)&lt;/a&gt;  -  2. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7hxHWCCAIIxFLCzvDgnQHX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lemonade (feat. Gunna, Don Toliver &amp;amp; NAV)&lt;/a&gt;  -  3. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/6cx06DFPPHchuUAcTxznu9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Head &amp;amp; Heart (feat.  MNEK)&lt;/a&gt;  -  4. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0NuAnAqjZjuGtcWXJOxUyl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;In De Schuur&lt;/a&gt;  -  5. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2MlOUXmcofMackX3bxfSwi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jerusalema (feat. Nomcebo Zikode)&lt;/a&gt;  -  6. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/5u1n1kITHCxxp8twBcZxWy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Holy (feat. Chance The Rapper)&lt;/a&gt;  -  7. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/32Q0JiYuVr2mcxfRIPyEBS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Más Más Más&lt;/a&gt;  -  8. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/4afGO0WTInDhK2C3dolz8z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;De Overkant&lt;/a&gt;  -  9. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/58trym7xUwRuXnBY7hKqC9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Door De Wind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Top 50 on Spotify (3rd week of October 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;: 1. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3tjFYV6RSFtuktYl3ZtYcq&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mood (feat. iann dior)&lt;/a&gt;  -  2. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7hxHWCCAIIxFLCzvDgnQHX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lemonade (feat. Gunna, Don Toliver &amp;amp; NAV)&lt;/a&gt;  -  3. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/4Oun2ylbjFKMPTiaSbbCih&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WAP (feat. Megan Thee Stallion)&lt;/a&gt;  -  4. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/1yoMvmasuxZfqHEipJhRbp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hawái&lt;/a&gt;  -  5. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0t1kP63rueHleOhQkYSXFY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dynamite&lt;/a&gt;  -  6. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/1tkg4EHVoqnhR6iFEXb60y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;What You Know Bout Love&lt;/a&gt;  -  7. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0PvFJmanyNQMseIFrU708S&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;For The Night (feat. Lil Baby &amp;amp; DaBaby)&lt;/a&gt;  -  8. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0VjIjW4GlUZAMYd2vXMi3b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blinding Lights&lt;/a&gt;  -  9. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/5u1n1kITHCxxp8twBcZxWy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Holy (feat. Chance The Rapper)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The most streamed songs in the Netherlands overlap with the most streamed songs all over the world, but there is no overlap with my list.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to create locally relevant recommendations. If you live in
Antwerpen, and you are looking for bands that you can see on a small
stage after the pandemic, we will recommend you great music from
Northwestern Belgium and the South of Holland. If you want to visit San Diego after the pandemic, we’ll recommend you music from the San Diego scene. If you want to fill up with good music a local content quota, such as a national and city relevant quota in your radio, we will help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next comparison uses some musicology and sound engineering
“features” of the songs on the three lists. These characteristics
are themselves recognized by algorithms, and they are used for Spotify’s own recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_comparison.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt; My songs
are independent songs, far less popular than the global hits. My
playlist is mainly indie rock, so far less danceable, less loud than the current hits, but it is more energetic! The average tempo is similar to the hits, but I tend to chose slower songs, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s &lt;code&gt;valence&lt;/code&gt; is a quantitative measure that aims to capture the
positiveness conveyed by the a sound recording(e.g.happy, cheerful,
euphoric on the positive side, and sad, depressed, angry on the negative side). Another striking difference among my list and the two hitlists is the far broader scale of emotions conveyed by the songs that I selected for October 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next blogposts we will explain some details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-playlist&#34;&gt;Wounded Egos: Daniel’s October Playlist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Gaz Coombes - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/14LSfvkF3PS0k81FAe6PFk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wounded Egos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting up a company, building a team in the times of corona, social
distancing, zoom calls and narcissistic world leaders is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. dEUS - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3MKXdtTufdX4BwVbuJqFGW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sirens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“You gotta pick your fights, you’ve got work to do”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which makes you think that you have to resist the Sirens call. This
record came out the day before I went to my CFA exam, which was the most gruelling test in my life. I just downloaded it, put it on the car hifi, pressed play and did the 8 hour test without error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Harmaleighs - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3A8ZDfxmb75kFl5Cqr2pIf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Don’t Panic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“But what if that’s all I’m good at?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t Panic surprised me so much that it found its way to my September
and October playlist, too. If something is perfect, it is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon Spencer Blues Explosion - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3ezOmKfYasIe0QeWyWiucU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Can’t
Stop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I just can’t stop”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I need to go back to the basics. Jon Spencer is as good as
Elvis must have been on stage. I never saw Elvis on stage, I am too
young for that, but old enough to have seen Jon Spencer on a large and
small stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fountains of Wayne - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2rvxQwn7rGR0ZmHvwP4AmG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Michael And Heather At The Baggage Claim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Michael &amp;amp; Heather at the baggage claim tired of playing the waiting
game”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The covid pandemic not only froze the entire music industry, and put
many artists, venues, managers, technicians on life support, but claimed many lives in the audience and in the music community. I still come to tears when I recall that early March day when I learned that Adam Schlesinger, my favourite lyricist and songwriter died. I was alwayshoping that I will show him what we were doing. We will certainly dedicate something to his memory along the way. For 15 years, when I was sad, I just picked one of the Fountains of Wayne records, and put it on. For this playlist, I chose a bittersweet song, which probably has the best poetry written in independent music ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify falls for the typical Schlesinger trick: the melody is very
upbeat, the lyrics is bittersweet. Spotify risks to put it into the
positive and danceable category, at least, within my list, though I find it just a bit less gloomy than 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3A8ZDfxmb75kFl5Cqr2pIf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Don’t
Panic&lt;/a&gt; and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7lBpCteEdS5WbOnzbVmWiR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Royal Screw
Up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japanese Breakfast - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/6Uhhwk8oJc8SLloZIAQksB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Machinist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How can I fight a kingdom of your demons?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t complain about the big algorithms of the big company. Spotify’s algorithm brought Japanese Breakfast to me. We just want to take a less individualist approach to making recommendations. Michelle Zauner is on the feminine side of this list, and I just can’t get enough of her music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s analysis finds this song to be less danceable and dark, which is exactly why Japanese Breakfast is such a curious artist project. It is experimental pop music that twists well-known pop clichés into original new songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soccer Mommy - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/7lBpCteEdS5WbOnzbVmWiR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Royal Screw Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“And I want an answer to all my problems”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Soccer Mommy’s new record came out in March, I could not resist
reaching out to the sound engineering team to convey my congratulations. Soccer Mommy is the youngest artist on this list with a huge talent, and the team that she works with is just world class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phoebe Bridgers - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/49UDOG8DoBajXTJSTqfRMg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kyoto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You called me from a payphone / They still got pay phones”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular song on the playlist, a true global independent hit.
Phoebe Bridgers is hot, and she 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/155586901702555/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;may be a
killer&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Kitt - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/0qZ9rwAonJvO91GK9nqqma&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;It’s Yours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify sees this song as the most danceable and most positive song. And it is so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Big data creates injustice.”&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil, author of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/roots-of-unity/review-weapons-of-math-destruction/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Listen Local project is aiming to create better radio playlisting, personal playlisting and concert promotion in a local context: within Slovakia or at a more specific level, Flanders or even the city of Utrecht or Budapest. We aim to place our partner’s music in local radio lists, personal playlists, and grow their fan base during the COVID-19 pandemic so that in 2021 they can eventually meet in the venues again, and carry out longer, more successful tours than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; grew out of a large, collaborative project of collective management societies, grant managers, music distributors, venues, and other music stakeholders who joined forces to collect more royalties from 2014 onwards starting with three, and eventually encompassing more than a dozen countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-problem&#34;&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are listening to music on Spotify or Apple Music, and at home on YouTube.  They are following advice from algorithms tested on hundreds of millions of people.A band in Utrecht, a rapper in Rotterdam, a dance producer in the Hague is not aiming for hundreds of millions of people.  They want to be found by their fans and like-minded people, but their music is lost literally among 100,000,000 songs on these platforms. We want 
&lt;a href=&#34;#artists&#34;&gt;artists&lt;/a&gt; in the music scene to be found by their current and future 
&lt;a href=&#34;#fans&#34;&gt;fans&lt;/a&gt;, by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/localmedia.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;local media&lt;/a&gt;, and as soon the pandemic is over, to meet in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/venues.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;local venues and festivals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a music fan is interested what is going on in Utrecht, Rotterdam or Den Haag, or on a roadtrip via Antwerpen and Gent via Lille, will never find those amazing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/artists.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bands, performers, rappers, producers&lt;/a&gt; who create wonderful content along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anybody can create playlists, but mainly Spotify, Apple, or YouTube create the playlists with their AI algorithms and their staff and their interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related posts&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;October Playlist: Wounded Egos&lt;/a&gt; - a short case study of a playlist analysis and comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local: Open Collaboration Experiment &amp;amp; Feasibility Study&lt;/a&gt; - how you can participate in the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify: Popular Music That Nobody Listens To&lt;/a&gt; - becasue you do not want to end up on the list of 0 streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lets-do-this-together&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Do This Together!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aiming to create an alternative market measurement, marketing and recommendation engine tool that is based on open source software, open collaboration, full scientific transparency in an open collaboration with artists, small businesses and the entire music ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;create new playlists&lt;/strong&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s build up a weekly, relevant, non-exclusive playlists for music coming from Utrecht, Antwerpen, Rotterdam, Den Haag, Flanders or the Netherlands that smoothly blend in local music with relevant, spiritually or musically matching songs that fans of the Utrecht, Antwerpen, Rotterdam, Den Haag bands like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;create an app&lt;/strong&gt;!  If 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forgotify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt; can pick out songs that nobody, ever, ever listened to on Spotify, not even the performer&amp;rsquo;s mother, sister, friends, not even their enemies, than we can create an app that allows fans in Utrecht, visitors or Rotterdam and the virtual community of Den Haag to find relevant music, and to connect with music created in these communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;We are&lt;/a&gt; a bunch of musicians, musicologists, music analysts, music journalists, producers who want to make this happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an artist, you can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;simply fill in a form&lt;/a&gt; identifying your music on Spotify, filling in a few biographical data about yourself (or your band, ensemble, group). If you represent several artists as a talent manager, music publisher, record label, granting agency or music export office, please get in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;touch with us&lt;/a&gt; for onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-use&#34;&gt;Data Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From participating artists we only ask questions that they usually post on their websites or would tell to music journalists or bloggers. We will put all this information (with some clearly stated exceptions in the registration form) on the website of the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use similar data used to analyze 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this playlist&lt;/a&gt; about the participants&#39; music. This data is an analysis of their released music, not about the persons who play the music, or their earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not ask for any financial data, and we do not have access to any financial data of the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transparency&#34;&gt;Transparency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire budget of our project is 10,000 euros, co-funded by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sgda.sk/about-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Arts Council&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://soza.sk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SOZA&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ci-info.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Consolidated Independent&lt;/a&gt;, a distributor of independent music. We hope that this will be enough to create a demonstration and a detailed feasibility study that makes the user needs of Slovak managers, labels, publishers and artists themselves to continue this project in 2021. The project will be carried out by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/reprexbv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reprex&lt;/a&gt;, a Dutch start-up co-founded by the author of the Slovak Music Industry Report, the first Hungarian Music Industry Report, Private Copying in Croatia, and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation for artists and music venues is &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; in the experiment. In 2020, we would like to find a viable business model that keeps this tool a good value for money for anybody in the independent music scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are asking labels, publishers, talent managers to contribute to our experimental budget on a crowdsourcing basis.  We ask for a nominal contribution from as little as 10-1000 euros on a voluntary basis.  In return. We hope to develop a tool that can make the work of independent labels and publishers easier. Any extra funding will be spent on the project at cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If we take a look at the streaming charts of the region, we usually find that the vast majority of the streamed songs are foreign songs - except for Austria, U.S. songs.  For comparison, we added a similar, middle-income emerging market (Argentina) and a rich, small-population English-speaking country, Australia to the chart. These countries seem to be in a similar position to the CEE countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/dataanimation/domestic_market_share_animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Market shares August-September 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably, the strongest countries of songwriting are the United States and Brazil - these are the countries that have ran out of the ISRC recording identifier range. Their charts are full with their domestic songs, but they are not alone.  Japan, France, and the bigger EU countries, France, Germany and Poland have very strong domestic performance, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are many factor at play here. Large countries with large artist populations generate a lot more recordings, so they local fans always have thousands of new songs to select from.  In small countries, the total annual creations, from pop to jazz, from authentic folk to classical amounts to a few thousand tracks. But it is not only size that matters.  Sweden&amp;rsquo;s population is similar to that of Austria, Hungary and Czechia, yet the Swedish repertoire performs better in Sweden, and as we will see in the next chart, abroad, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created a second data animation to visualize how hits were travelling across the borders in the summer of 2ö19. To make the chart easier to read, we omitted the United States, Brazil and Japan as countries of origin, and concentrated only on intra-European hit flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/dataanimation/cross_border_plot-animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Cross-border hits August-September 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second week of September 2019 was not an exceptional week. Most EU countries&#39; producers did not score any hits in any other EU countries&#39; Spotify Top 50 hits.  The UK exported many great hits to all over Europe, as usual, but there were other important hit flows. These hits mainly follow cultural proximity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France exported hits to the two Francophone countries of Europe, Belgium and Romania, and furthermore to Greece, a Southern country with particularly unique chart composition. Germany exported many hits to Austria, another German-speaking country, and some hits to other Germanic countries. Dutch producers placed a few hits in the Germanic countries and in Belgium, where the Dutch-speaking Flemish community has its own radios, TVs, press and hitlists. The Netherlands is a powerhouse of electronic popmusic that are not bound by language which finds audience in several countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strength and competitive position of the national market where an artists is most known and has a fan base is usually a determining factor of track performance and revenue.  The overall revenue prospects and competition situation of a Hungarian or Croatian song is very different from a British or even a Polish song.  But overall, most European recordings are not bound to a domestic country. Because of cultural proximity, the presence of native minorities or new immigrant diasporas, even small-language songs are being listened to on a much wider territory than the artists&#39; original country. Some relatively small EU countries, such as Sweden and the Netherlands successfully export their music on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, as the streaming services slowly overtake all other forms of use, the charts above depict a very fundamental market change.  Whereas in the traditional channels of physical sales, digital downloads and broadcasting, the CEE countries, like other small- and medium-sized EU countries, enjoyed 30-50% market share, among the streaming hits their producer&amp;rsquo;s share is below 10%. It is not unusual to find only domestic recordings in physical sales hitlists, while domestic songs rarely enter the streaming charts in the region, with the exception of Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional sales channels protected CEE markets in several ways.  After EU accession most import duties are gone, but physical products have very significant logistics costs, which gives local producers a competitive edge.  Because physical products are increasingly sold on concerts and festivals, where the market share of domestic performers is usually very high, the traditional, mechanically licensed sales had a protected market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The broadcasting channel, which used the be the most important promotion channel, too, was protected in many European countries by national content quotas, or supported with generously funded national, regional, local public broadcasters who gave a preference to national composers, producers and performers. These market barriers are not present in the streaming markets, which poses many questions. Our research is aiming to answer these questions, but it took several years to build a data infrastructure that can help producing an accurate market overview.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/eu_cross_border_hits_20190915.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;European hits on an other European country&amp;amp;rsquo;s Spotify hitlist, 15 September 2019.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/eu_cross_border_hits_20190915_hu87f5dcff746518fbceefbd4abed84ec5_40449_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;266&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;National repertoire market shares on national Spotify hitlists, 15 September 2019.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/gallery/spotify_chart_mkt_share_20190915_hu781d82e369311575b56de92db7530f5f_19890_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;266&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These findings will be open to discussion on&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/talk/waves_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Waves Music Showcase Festival and Conference&lt;/a&gt; [click for details] &lt;em&gt;on 27 September 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
