<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deezer | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/deezer/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/deezer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deezer</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dataandlyrics.com/media/icon_hu5bfde8608118b47b475864b70fd224b4_21674_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Deezer</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/deezer/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/music_level_playing_field_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/publication/music_level_playing_field_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our article, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/music-streaming-is-it-a-level-playing-field/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Streaming: Is It a Level Playing Field?&lt;/a&gt; is published in the February 2021 issue of CPI Antitrust Chronicle, which is fully devoted to competition policy issues in the music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dramatic growth of music streaming over recent years is potentially very positive. Streaming provides consumers with low cost, easy access to a wide range of music, while it provides music creators with low cost, easy access to a potentially wide audience. But many creators are unhappy about the major streaming platforms. They consider that they act in an unfair way, create an unlevel playing field and threaten long-term creativity in the music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our paper describes and assesses the basis for one element of these concerns, competition between recordings on streaming platforms. We argue that fair competition is restricted by the nature of the remuneration arrangements between creators and the streaming platforms, the role of playlists, and the strong negotiating power of the major labels. It concludes that urgent consideration should be given to a user-centric payment system, as well as greater transparency of the factors underpinning playlist creation and of negotiated agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the entire issue and the full text of our article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Competition Policy International&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2-Music-Streaming-Is-It-a-Level-Playing-Field-By-Daniel-Antal-Amelia-Fletcher-14-Peter-L.-Ormosi.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What If Your Stream Count Would Count For The Artists?</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 09:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contrary to what many believe, your music streaming history plays a relatively small role in the payouts of the artists whose songs you are listening to. The streaming platforms use a MCPS, or market-centred payout system, which is biased towards large market listeners. Contrary to UCPS, or user-centred payout systems, where all streams by all users are tallied up to determine the final distribution of subscription and advertisement revenues, MCPS uses weighted averaging that very heavily favours major music distributors and the biggest global stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We analyze these competition policy problems with Amelia Fletcher and Peter L. Ormosi in our forthcoming publication in a special issue of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.competitionpolicyinternational.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Competition Policy International&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Music streaming: is it a level playing field?&lt;/em&gt;. But in the meantime, an interesting impact assessment emerged from France, because the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cnm.fr/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Centre National de la Musique&lt;/a&gt; commissioned Deloitte to make an impact assessment on &lt;a href=&#34;https://cnm.fr/le-cnm-evalue-limpact-dun-changement-eventuel-de-mode-de-remuneration-par-les-plateformes-de-streaming/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a possible change&lt;/a&gt;. Deezer provided a full overview of its 2019 payouts, while Spotify gave a sample of 100,000 artist payouts, and the other streaming services — for example, Apple Music — refused to cooperate with the French government-backed institution. You can read an English language summary and an excellent commentary from Emmanuel Legrand on his blog: &lt;a href=&#34;https://legrandnetwork.blogspot.com/2021/02/user-centric-model-would-not-lead-to.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;User-centric model would not lead to significant changes in the distribution of music streaming royalties&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-which-genres-would-be-winners-and-losers-in-the-fair-payout&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Which genres would be winners and losers in the fair payout?&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/featured_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_bef50eac0b0da091ee6cabca789d86db.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/featured_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_87a0f83e6f423d124f61b004d5e82322.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/featured_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-02-21-cnm-streaming/featured_huc90c01e306aa840b99af21d2eca24b0d_92397_bef50eac0b0da091ee6cabca789d86db.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;595&#34;
               height=&#34;437&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Which genres would be winners and losers in the fair payout?
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair distribution would completely alter the revenues of different genres. The biggest winner would be classical music, but various forms of pop, rock, jazz and disco artists would earn 15–25% more revenue. Currently, rap and hip-hop take about an extra 20% royalty revenue at the expense of these genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The streaming providers, which are directly or indirectly part-owned by major labels, are playing down the results, claiming that the difference would translate only to a few euros per artists at the bottom of the pyramid. In a sense, this is true, because streaming royalties are generally very low. But averaging is extremely misleading, because it includes millions of songs that are out-of-date or for another reason are never heard. In fact, entire scenes and labels would earn about 10% more revenue globally, considering that streaming revenues add up to half or even more of their total recording revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
