<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nitra | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>/tag/nitra/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/nitra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Nitra</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 15:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Nitra</title>
      <link>/tag/nitra/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: Katarzia</title>
      <link>/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 15:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/</guid>
      <description>




  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-katarzia-photography-by-ladislav-kyllar&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/katarzia_avatar_hud68522c4bd457ff5afa5d5ebf9bd39ef_5502842_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Katarzia. Photography by Ladislav Kyllar&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-11-25-katarzia/katarzia_avatar_hud68522c4bd457ff5afa5d5ebf9bd39ef_5502842_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;5320&#34; height=&#34;2280&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Katarzia. Photography by Ladislav Kyllar
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katarzia, or &lt;em&gt;Katarína Kubošiová&lt;/em&gt;, is a Slovak singer, lyricist and producer. In 2020 she released her fourth album 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slnkorecords.sk/en/katarzia/celibat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Celibát&lt;/a&gt; with the main themes of loneliness and self-appreciation. Album was created in collaboration with the producer &lt;em&gt;Jonatán Pastirčák&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katarzia started her career as a folk singer. In the past years she moved on towards electronic music. She describes her current sound can as a mix of folk and electropop. The tour to promote her newest album &lt;em&gt;Celibát&lt;/em&gt; had been planned for spring 2020, unfortunately due to the Covid-19 pandemic had to be postponed indefinitely. As many other artists, Katarzia thinks that the current situation is not easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the moment, I am not working on any new projects. I am looking for a new job. Once the pandemic is over, I would like to stay where I am now, and return to the clubs to play for my audience. As I sing in Slovak, I know where my place is – I don&amp;rsquo;t want to perform abroad, of course, unless I turn to techno music. On a more personal level, I would like to live in New York – not as a musician, tough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katarzia is originally from Nitra, Slovakia and she has been living in Prague for a couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I live in Dejvice – there is a nice clubroom there, but I don&amp;rsquo;t visit that much. I enjoy going to National Theatre, Dejvice Theatre, Meetfactory, Archa Theatre and Rudolfinum. All the old classics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the restrictions during the pandemic, Katarzia managed to shoot a video for her song &lt;em&gt;Hoří i voda&lt;/em&gt; from &lt;em&gt;Celibát&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xVPDZEa0wjU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music video is a short film, directed by Jay Walker, an American who lives and works in Prague. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://girlsinfilm.net/network&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Girls in film&lt;/a&gt; –- an organization that supports women in the film industry –- participated in the production of the video. The song is about women rights and equality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous albums:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generácia Y (2013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agnostika (2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antigona (2018).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/artist/5EssQRYnIgCOcvPauVySR1&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; is developing transparent algorithms and open source solutions to find new audiences for independent music. We want to correct the injustice and inherent bias of market leading big data algorithms. If you want&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;your music and audience&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;to be analysed in Listen Local, fill&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in. We will include you in our demo application for local music recommendations and our analysis to be revealed in December.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
