<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Réka Szentirmay | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/author/reka-szentirmay/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/author/reka-szentirmay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Réka Szentirmay</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 15:31:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Réka Szentirmay</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/author/reka-szentirmay/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product/Market Fit Validation in Yes!Delft</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 15:31:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate our product market/fit in two segments, business/policy research and scientific research, with a supporting role given to data journalism. Because we want to follow a bootstrapping strategy, we must focus on those clients where we find the highest value proposition, which is of course easier said than done.  We see much interest in our offering from other continents, therefore we truly welcome the opportunity that we can do this on a truly global business canvas in one of the worlds’ 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/news/yesdelft-among-the-top-5-business-incubators-in-the-world/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;top five incubators&lt;/a&gt;, the number 2 university-backed incubator in the world, second to none in Europe, in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/focus-areas/artificial-intelligence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain&lt;/a&gt; Validation Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Europe hundreds of thousands of microenterprises, such as record labels, video producers or book publishers are facing data and AI giants like Google’s YouTube, Apple Music, Spotify, Netflix or Amazon. If the recommendation engines of these giants do not recommend their songs, films or books, then their investments are doomed to fail, because about half of the global sales are driven by AI algorithms. When they make a claim for the missing money, they will immediately find themselves in a dispute with gigabytes of data that they can only handle with a data scientist, even though they do not even have an IT professional or an HR professional to make the hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An awful lot of money, creativity and real values are at stake, and we want to be on the creator’s side, their technician’s side, their manager’s side when they want to get a fair share from the pie and they want to help these industry leader to make the pie grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unesco.org/new/en/culture/themes/creativity/arts-education/research-cooperation/observatories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UNESCO&lt;/a&gt; and the EU have been promoting as an organizational solution the fragmentation problem with the so-called data observatories that are pooling the business, policy, and scientific research needs of various domains, like music. This is an idea that we really like, and we believe that our research automation solutions can help these observatories to grow faster as ecosystems, create better quality and more timely data and research products and a far lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define ourselves as a reproducible research company inspired by the philosophy of open collaboration, based on open-source software and open data. We want to explore various revenue models around these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not committed to open source licensing if more permissive licensing policies provide us with better opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to explore various data-as-service models, because we do not want to be locked into the position of cheap open data vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to deploy AI applications that really help earning money in these sectors with playlisting, recommendation engines, forecasting applications, or royalty valuations, because our open collaboration approach brings up enough data sooner to than its alternatives, because it manages inherent conflicts of interests, fragmentation, and decentralization better than hierarchical solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January CEEMID reached its peak: we introduced a 12-country 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproducible research project&lt;/a&gt; made with only freelancers in Brussels, presented as best use case of evidence-based policy design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February Daniel visited the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/yes-delft-co-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft Co-Lab&lt;/a&gt; to find out who would be the best co-founder to re-launch CEEMID as an enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April we started to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;release our data&lt;/a&gt; as open data for validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month ago we 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started-up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we launched the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few other 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/annex.html#other-observatories&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data observatories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.palato.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Palato&lt;/a&gt; in the Hague, where we took our selfie and had an absolutely amazing dinner after the pitch. Check them out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching Our Demo Music Observatory</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 08:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, on 15 September 2020, we officially launched our &lt;code&gt;minimal viable product&lt;/code&gt; as we promised to partners back in February. This was a particularly difficult period for everybody. We aspired to deliver by September in a very different environment, our hopes for commissioned work went up in flames with the pandemic, and our targeted users, musicians and music entrepreneurs, talent managers, music venues lost most of their income. The organizations helping them, granting authorities, export offices and collective management societies are overwhelmed with the problem. During these troublesome times, our team expanded, attracted great new talent, and kept working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first product is the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, a collaborative, automated research-based 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/faq/observatories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;observatory&lt;/a&gt; for the music industry, one that is particularly hard hit by the COVID19 crisis. Not only great artists, composers, technicians, managers fell victim to the virus, but musicians lost about 50–90% of their income from live music. This translates to a 100% loss for the live music technicians and managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fQJHflWPS34&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

See our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-09-11-creating-automated-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;earlier blogpost&lt;/a&gt; on what you see on the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry was never a place for great job security. For putting up a show, you usually need a network of 10–200 artists, technicians and managers to work together as freelancers without all those social benefits that many people enjoy in other walks of life. We have been trying to figure out how to help this microenterprise and freelancer-network based industry with research for five years. Our aim is to make them competitive when they are talking with their buyers: Google, Apple, Spotify, who are really heavy-weight data and AI pros. Our better plan their tours, when they will be back on the road, to understand what sort of audiences and purchasing power waits for them in different European cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are launching at a time when the music industry is crying for help.Therefore, we have decided to make our demo observatory open and unfinished. Over the last 7 years, we have built up about 2000 music and creative sector indicators to be used for business KPIs, forecasting targets, grant evaluations, royalty valuations, concert demography target group analysis and other professional uses. We would like to open up, based on your needs, about 50 well-designed indicators, and pledge to keep it daily refreshed, corrected, documented, citaable, downloadable. Also, feel free to use our most valuable source code—use it for your own purposes, even modify it, as long as you keep it open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our smaller partners, we follow what musicians do these days on Bandcamp: name your price. We make a pledge to our small partners: if you need reliable data to plan your next grant calls, calculate royalties, compensations, predict hit candidates, give us the job—and name your price. Post-corona, you can take for a dollar the best music from Bandcamp. You can take our research products, for a limited period, for any amount you name, as long as  it is for a good cause and serves the industry, musicians, technicians or managers. In return, we ask for your feedback. Help us validate whether we are on the right track, tell us how we can cooperate after the pandemic, in better times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our larger and better funded partners? We ask you to pay the price we name, because we believe that it is a well-justified, fair and competitive price, set by pricing experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appreciate it if you take a look at our offering, or if you pass this blogpost on to your colleagues in the industry.  Our main target audience initially are music professional in broader Europe, but we are planning to cover all major global markets very soon, too. Feedback from the U.S., Australia, Canada, Colombia, Brazil &amp;amp; Argentina is particularly welcome as we have great plans over there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-we-are&#34;&gt;Who we are?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/post/2020-08-24-start-up/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; our operations on 1 September 2020 on the basis of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://documentation.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt;, a pan-European data observatory that created about 2000 music and creative industry indicators for its users. In the coming days, we are gradually opening up about 50 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music industry&lt;/a&gt; and 50 broader creative industry indicators in a fully reproducible workflow, with daily re-freshed, re-processed, well-formatted and documented indicators for business and policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to validate this approach in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious university-backed incubator programs, in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesdelft.com/yes-programs/ai-blockchain-validation-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI/Blockchain Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re finalist on their selection, and all help before 23 September from our friends in the music industry is more than appreciated. If we get there, we can rely on probably the best pros in Europe to make our offering better tailored and financially sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-in-touch&#34;&gt;Get in touch!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the very simple and extremely secure &lt;strong&gt;keybase.io&lt;/strong&gt;, a kind of mix of Whatsapp, Skype, Google Drive, One Drive and zoom. You can get in touch on that platform with us in anytime 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/team/reprexcommunity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily contact on LinkedIn 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/k%C3%A1tya-nagy-a9447730/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kátya&lt;/a&gt; and of course, we have a usually working 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;email contact form&lt;/a&gt;, too. Our email is name.surname at our main domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-credits&#34;&gt;Video credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data acquisition and processing: Daniel Antal, CFA and Marta Kołczyńska, PhD (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/economy.html#demand&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;survey data&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation automation: Sandor Budai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video art: Line Matson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/moonmoonmoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting-up</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-08-24-start-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-08-24-start-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big day has come: the co-founders singed off the documents at the public notary and started the registration of a reproducible research start-up in Leiden.  We got a lot of support from our friends! Your encouragement gives us a lot of energy to accomplish our first milestones, and to get Reprex B.V. going!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex means &amp;lsquo;reproducible example&amp;rsquo; in data science.  When you are stuck with a problem, creating a reproducible example allows other computer scientists, statisticians, programmers or data users to solve it. In 80% of the cases, you usually find the solution while creating a generalized example.  In the 20% other cases, you can reach out for help easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming days, we are launching demo versions of our headline products, data observatories. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; will be a fully automated online service that every day collects, processes, cleans, and publishes scientifically valid data about European music.  Very soon after we will launch two other observatories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative and cultural sector, NGOs, most research institutions, data journalism teams are usually very small, and they do not have internal IT or data science capacities.  We would like to provide them a transparent, high quality, and fully open source solution to acquire data, process it without errors, document it and make sense of it. We would like to embrace the idea of open collaboration among creative enterprises, scientific researchers, NGOs, data journalists and policymakers with our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work will comply with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/opa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Policy Analysis&lt;/a&gt; standards developed by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkeley Initiative for Transparency in the Social Sciences&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cega.berkeley.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Effective Global Action&lt;/a&gt; and the four principles of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/reproducible/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproducible research&lt;/a&gt;: reviewability, replicability, confirmability and auditability.  We believe that these standards apply in reproducible finance, empirical evidence presentation in courts, or advocating sound policies and producing high-quality journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;help&#34;&gt;Do you want to help our start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to enter into the Validation Lab of one of the best artificial intelligence incubators in early September. Talented team members, letters of intents and assignments from organizations will give a lot of credibility to our start 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/team/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Meet our team »&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put as in contact with people who love to write code in R and interested in automating business and social science research and primary data collection such as surveying. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataobservatory.eu/#featured&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out what sort of code we create »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduce us to people who need data and information to make better informed decision and analysis in music, film, book publishing, photography services or socially responsible finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share contacts of data journalists who would like to develop stories from big survey programs like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/commfrontoffice/publicopinion/index.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.afrobarometer.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Afrobarometer&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latinobarometro.org/lat.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lationbarometro&lt;/a&gt;, or base their storytelling on data and its visualizations. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://retroharmonize.satellitereport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;See our survey harmonization examples »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know such people?  Send over this post or connect us in an email or social media message!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks again for your good wishes and encouragements, and hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
