<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>racism | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/racism/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/racism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>racism</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 08:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>racism</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/racism/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Racist Music Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We want big data algorithms to work for small venues, undiscovered bands, and all artists coming from diverse walks of life. We often find that big data works against them, and our Listen Local Initiative was designed to change this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big data algorithms will increase injustice and breach social norms if they are trained on improper data, or the algorithms are biased &amp;ndash; this is why we place so much emphasis on algorithm transparency and input data transparency. Facebook, Apple or Spotify are often criticized for helping the spread of hate, for example.  But how can an algorithm turn racist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Kraemer &amp;amp; Steve Holden reported on BBC recently that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/newsbeat-54613907&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spotify, Apple Music, Deezer and YouTube found recently hosting racist music&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; and they removed it after the BBC’s investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Spotify, public playlists and &amp;ldquo;suggested artists&amp;rdquo; did make it easier to find extreme content: In some cases, users created playlists that collated songs and bands associated with the National Socialist Black Metal (NSBM) movement, mainly from Eastern Europe and Russia. Anti-Semitism and glorification of the Holocaust was commonn in their lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can an algorithm become racist?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is trained on the tastes and habits of “white people”, it will less likely recommend “black music.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a music is coming from a “black” community, it will probably not recommend it in the “white community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the algorithm learns that taste of racists people, it will provide them with more racist material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can replace &lt;code&gt;black&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;white&lt;/code&gt; with any &lt;code&gt;minority&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;majority&lt;/code&gt; group.  Take &lt;code&gt;Slovak&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;American&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;major release&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;independent release&lt;/code&gt;. European independent music makers may feel a minority compared to international majors.  The problem with algorithms is that they can ruthlessly reinforce injustice, because they just learn how to do something better, faster, and more than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fight for the removal of inappropriate content from the &lt;em&gt;training set&lt;/em&gt;. If you see any non-English hateful songs on these platforms, let us know, because English-language moderation is just the tip of the iceberg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the training sets of the algorithms behind sales or listening recommendations are inclusive. Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local Initative&lt;/a&gt; is an early beta of a recommendation system that makes sure that locally relevant music gets recommended to locally relevant audiences, and does not need to go into an uneven fight with giants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the external verification of the algorithm and its results. We will allow multiple levels of audit for all our algorithms, and we make all critical elements of our data products open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few examples that the tides are turning:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justin Joffe: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://observer.com/2017/02/capitalism-has-suppressed-black-musicians&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Capitalism Has Long Suppressed the Contributions of Black Musicians&lt;/a&gt;  2017/02/02&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Sisaro: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/01/arts/music/music-industry-black-lives-matter.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Music Industry Is Wrestling With Race. Here’s What It Has Promised&lt;/a&gt; 2020/07/01&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kali187/29537032568/in/photolist-M161Jd-Fb3bBZ-2hL9Zw2-oHvory-oHvRMx-oZY9Gw-oZZXBz-oHvMod-oZZXzR-oHvMrj-oHvo5w-7a1jrw-HmVzFz-W45Mq3-GMhHU5-26MJg25-29hg18w-vv7kap-24mAJA5-2dRDUMa-8Hk58E-7UskvS-akZE6J-E6kKTp-2V2uSq-2gsHaES-2gsGZ1K-2gsH2Ct-2gsGZre-2gsHdvw-2gsHg6G-2gsHfpX-2gsH2ok-2gsHcrY-2gsHd3c-2gsHdnf-2gsGXKt-2gsGVJV-2gsGW3R-2gsHe7S-2gsHgAK-2gsGWvu-2gsGXmx-2gsGVCc-yUw5E2-2gsGYPx-2gsGZSe-818JBs-FBqXev-gYrUWa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Janusz Kaliszczak&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
