<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>turning-tide | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>/tag/turning-tide/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/turning-tide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>turning-tide</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>turning-tide</title>
      <link>/tag/turning-tide/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Tide: hCaptcha Competes With Big Tech On Privacy And Market Share</title>
      <link>/post/2020-11-26-hcaptcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-11-26-hcaptcha/</guid>
      <description>














&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-hcaptcha&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;featured.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;hCaptcha&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    hCaptcha
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you tried to fill out forms, find product information, you are have filled out many riddles, captchas.  These captchas are there to prevent robots filling out the forms with funny data, steal your email address or to pretend to be human viewers for paid traffic, because who wants to pay for bots visiting the website?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with the captcha business is that until now, Google was the main provider of them, which created an inherent conflict of interests. Google, as the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest advertising agency, has an interest in letting robots viewing advertisements - something that the &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; captchas are supposed to stop.  And Google let&amp;rsquo;s them do it in a small percent of the cases. Those small percent add up to billions of page views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots learned to fill in captchas, but Google did not fundamentally change the way they work, instead it released its 3rd version, which collects plenty of personal data about the viewer &amp;ndash; an important input again for its advertisment personalization business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And third, but not least, solving captchas became an industry itself.  Human understanding of pictures trains all sorts of AI applications from self-driving cars to medical diagnostics. People who solve billions and billions of captchas for Google actually carry out billions worth work for the advertising giant.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-hcaptchas-new-types-of-riddles-are-more-difficult-to-solve-for-robots&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-11-26-hcaptcha/hcaptcha_examples_hu1f72806249125aea927c666fc76bbf2c_375098_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;hCaptcha&amp;rsquo;s new types of riddles are more difficult to solve for robots.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-11-26-hcaptcha/hcaptcha_examples_hu1f72806249125aea927c666fc76bbf2c_375098_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1266&#34; height=&#34;444&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    hCaptcha&amp;rsquo;s new types of riddles are more difficult to solve for robots.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Competing with Google and other Big Tech companies seems like a tall order: their monopolistic market power, platform effects and army of highly paid developers are generally considered too powerful to tackle for anyone but other tech giants such as Facebook or Amazon. Our story shows that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be that way - you can beat Big Tech by focussing on privacy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eli-Shaoul Khedouri and Todd Anderson at Intuition Machines 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/90377406/suspicious-of-googles-recaptcha-heres-a-popular-alternative&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;built up&lt;/a&gt; hCaptha, with an &lt;em&gt;h&lt;/em&gt; for humans in three years to rival Google. They created an ethical AI alternative that currently has a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hcaptcha.com/post/hcaptcha-now-the-largest-independent-captcha-service&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;15% global market share&lt;/a&gt; in cybersecurity services focusing on privacy and re-inventing a business model, when they are actually paying for large webmasters to host their riddles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you embed their hCaptcha to your website, you will be offered either a cash-out after the recognition work your readers to for them, or you can opt to have the value of this work transferred to a charity &amp;ndash; currently to Wikimedia Foundation. As they write in their blogpost 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hcaptcha.com/ai-ethics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AI Ethics Policy&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; virtually every technology, from pencils to dynamite, is a dual use solution; it can be used for good or ill. Every company researching, building, or selling dual use solutions has an obligation to consider the consequences of their actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data observatories&lt;/a&gt; and our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; solutions have a similar aim: reduce inequality and unfair advantage from big data exploitation by joining many small data sources in our observatories, and creating recommendation systems and analytics solutions that empower local players to compete with Big Tech in their home markets. Challenge us with data request in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ethical questions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Racist Music Algorithm</title>
      <link>/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-10-30-racist-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We want big data algorithms to work for small venues, undiscovered bands, and all artists coming from diverse walks of life. We often find that big data works against such types of users, and our Listen Local Initiative was designed to change this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big data algorithms will increase injustice and breach social norms if they are trained on biased data, or if the algorithms themselves are biased — this is why we place so much emphasis on algorithm transparency and input data transparency. Facebook, Apple, and Spotify are often criticized for helping the spread of hate, for example. But how can an algorithm turn racist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Kraemer &amp;amp; Steve Holden reported on BBC recently that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/newsbeat-54613907&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spotify, Apple Music, Deezer and YouTube found recently hosting racist music&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; and they removed it after the BBC’s investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Spotify, public playlists and “suggested artist” algorithms make it easier to find extreme content. In some cases, users created playlists that collated songs and bands associated with the National Socialist Black Metal (NSBM) movement, mainly from Eastern Europe and Russia. Anti-Semitism and glorification of the Holocaust is common in their lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can an algorithm become racist?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an algorithm is trained on the tastes and habits of white users, it will less likely recommend Black music (i.e. genres with histories in Black communities such as hip-hop or jazz, or Black artists making any genre of music) to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If music is coming from a Black community (based on genre, location, or artists with a Black identity), a racist algorithm will be less likely to recommend it to white users, according to what the algorithm predicts white users typically listen to and like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the algorithm learns that certain users have listened to and liked music with racist content, it will provide them with more racist material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can replace &lt;code&gt;black&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;white&lt;/code&gt; with any &lt;code&gt;minority&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;majority&lt;/code&gt; group.  Take &lt;code&gt;Slovak&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;American&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;major release&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;independent release&lt;/code&gt;. European independent music makers may feel a minority compared to international majors. The problem with algorithms is that they can ruthlessly reinforce injustice, because they are focused on learning how to do things better, faster, and more — but not in qualitatively different ways — than they were done before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fight for the removal of inappropriate content from the &lt;em&gt;training set&lt;/em&gt;. If you see any non-English hateful songs on these platforms, let us know, because English-language moderation is just the tip of the iceberg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the training sets of the algorithms behind sales or listening recommendations are inclusive. Our  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local Initative&lt;/a&gt; is an early beta of a recommendation system that makes sure that locally relevant music gets recommended to locally relevant audiences, and does not need to engage in a David and Goliath fight against international giants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the external verification of the algorithm and its results. We allow multiple levels of audit for all our algorithms, and we make all critical elements of our data products open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few examples that the tides are turning:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justin Joffe: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://observer.com/2017/02/capitalism-has-suppressed-black-musicians&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Capitalism Has Long Suppressed the Contributions of Black Musicians&lt;/a&gt;  2017/02/02&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Sisaro: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/01/arts/music/music-industry-black-lives-matter.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Music Industry Is Wrestling With Race. Here’s What It Has Promised&lt;/a&gt; 2020/07/01&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kali187/29537032568/in/photolist-M161Jd-Fb3bBZ-2hL9Zw2-oHvory-oHvRMx-oZY9Gw-oZZXBz-oHvMod-oZZXzR-oHvMrj-oHvo5w-7a1jrw-HmVzFz-W45Mq3-GMhHU5-26MJg25-29hg18w-vv7kap-24mAJA5-2dRDUMa-8Hk58E-7UskvS-akZE6J-E6kKTp-2V2uSq-2gsHaES-2gsGZ1K-2gsH2Ct-2gsGZre-2gsHdvw-2gsHg6G-2gsHfpX-2gsH2ok-2gsHcrY-2gsHd3c-2gsHdnf-2gsGXKt-2gsGVJV-2gsGW3R-2gsHe7S-2gsHgAK-2gsGWvu-2gsGXmx-2gsGVCc-yUw5E2-2gsGYPx-2gsGZSe-818JBs-FBqXev-gYrUWa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Janusz Kaliszczak&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was slightly edited for additional clarity by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/author/emily-hansell-clark/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Emily&lt;/a&gt; on 25 February 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
