<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Netherlands | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/netherlands/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/netherlands/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Netherlands</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 11:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Netherlands</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/netherlands/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: Robin Kester, Utrecht, the Netherlands</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 11:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-11-11-listen-local-robin-kester/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Robin Kester is a rising star of the the Dutch music scene. The musician, currently based in Utrecht, the Netherlands, released her mini-album 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://robinkester.bandcamp.com/album/this-is-not-a-democracy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This is Not a Democracy&lt;/a&gt; in September this year and received many positive reviews from the press. Despite the pandemic she managed to play several concerts throughout the country, although concerts abroad were cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are artists currently handling the COVID crisis and how are they currently planning their careers? We sat down with Robin and asked her point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where are you heading to?  What would be a city or city-based scene where you would like to play after COVID and start building your local fan base, e.g. Vienna, Antwerpen, Zürich, or other cities. Why? What attracts you there professionally or personally?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure where I’m heading. I’d like to tour internationally with my music. (But who doesn’t?) I find it very difficult to pinpoint one exact place to start building a fan base. I have always loved travelling in the UK and Ireland and I admire a lot of artists from those countries, but I can’t narrow it down to one specific location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where do you come from? What would you recommend to visit in your hometown for a fan who is coming to see your show? And are there other artists in your area/city that you would like to recommend?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m from the Netherlands and I’m currently living in Utrecht. I’d advise you to go for a nice walk around the city centre, follow the Catharijnesingel and go to a movie during the day in Springhaver or Louis Hartlooper Complex. There are plenty of other artists I’d recommend. Moon Moon Moon for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Could you recommend one of your videos from YouTube or Vimeo?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, I like this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yF5qFuFsK0E&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yF5qFuFsK0E&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robin Kester - Live at 3voor12 Radio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The idea of our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local Initiative&lt;/a&gt; to create transparent, well-documented recommendations in various apps, music education games, and to make new personal and radio  that work differently from the current streaming algorithms. We do not try to find yet another similar song to user, but we would like to find audience to a song. We want to avoid that new artists are ending up on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt; list, or among hundreds of thousands of artists that the streaming platform algorithms recommend to no-one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are an independent artist, band, label, or publisher, we encourage you to add your very short bio into our database (form 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to add several bands/artists, get in touch with us and we&amp;rsquo;ll provide you a spreadsheet), and try out our demo application. Our system will be transparent: we try to make big data algorithms work for you, not against you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/4l5igewpicaDDBdcZlyV90&#34; width=&#34;740&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
[Robin Kester official website](https://showcase.fm/robinkester)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local: Open Collaboration Experiment &amp; Feasibility Study</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Big data creates injustice.”&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil, author of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/roots-of-unity/review-weapons-of-math-destruction/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can train machine learning algorithms on millions of music fans, then you can very precisely find listeners in Bratislava, entire Slovakia, in the Slovak diaspora in the United States.  In Utrecht, in Flanders, in Japan. If you cannot, then your sales will be driven by Spotify, Apple, Amazon or Google’s YouTube. And you fill compete with millions, tens of million of songs in your own city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have access to the entire analytics toolkit to fine-tune your mastering, your instruments, your tempo, when you know how to plug into the radio editors pre-screening, then you have chance for airplay. If you are all small, even local content guidelines, such as national radio quotas or public radio targets will not help you, because you remain invisible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the support of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sgda.sk/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Arts Council&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soza.sk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SOZA&lt;/a&gt;, non-profit civic association representing more than 2,600 rights holders in Slovakia and over 1 million abroad (musical works composers, lyrics and publishers), and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ci-info.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Consolidated Independent&lt;/a&gt;, a music distributor platform 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/reprexbv/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reprex&lt;/a&gt; is preparing a feasibility study for the collaborative, transparent research tool and application that helps you to find your way to radio playlists, connect to fans in your own city, country, and in other towns along viable tour routes.  Make music export more of a science than a guessing game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;listen_local_mindmap.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first step, &lt;em&gt;until the end of 2020&lt;/em&gt;, we are going to create a demo application and a feasibility study with quantitative musicologists and data scientists. The demo application will show how to use AI to place the music of the volunteering bands and labels’s repertoire on radio lists and personal playlists.  Our feasibility study will show how different local content guidelines (radio quotas, public broadcaster targets, and other tools) can affect the market share of small local and national repertoires, and will provide culture policymakers and competition authorities with insight how to make the algorithm-driven music streaming, broadcasting marketplace more even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-you-participate-in-the-experiment&#34;&gt;How can you participate in the experiment?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first phase of the experiment, &lt;strong&gt;only artists and their groups released on Spotify&lt;/strong&gt; can participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation in the experiment is free&lt;/strong&gt;.  The research findings, including potential targets for your music, will be fully open, transparent and free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an artist, you can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;simply fill in a form&lt;/a&gt; identifying your music on Spotify, filling in a few biographical data about yourself (or your band, ensemble, group). We do not ask any financial data, and only very limited personal information. We only ask about city affiliations, targeted cities, age, experience level, and language of your lyrics, if you do not play instrumental music. In our experience, these factors are very important among musicology and sound engineering quality measures. (Read a bit more about our data 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/#data-use&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data use&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a &lt;strong&gt;fan of independent music&lt;/strong&gt;, please, &lt;strong&gt;forward this post&lt;/strong&gt; to a band that you would love to see in our project, or a local music venue that you would like to visit again after the covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;october_playlist_analysis.png&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project originally started out of Slovakia, Hungary, Czechia and Poland, but we only found funding in Slovakia for a low-budget, open source, open data, open collaboration experiment. &lt;strong&gt;Participation is open anywhere in the world&lt;/strong&gt;, but we are &lt;strong&gt;focusing on a viable post-covid tour route&lt;/strong&gt; around Budapest – Bratislava – Vienna – Salzburg – Munich – Ruhr – the Netherlands – Belgium. We hope to give guidance on targeting both recorded and live music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you represent several artists&lt;/strong&gt; as a talent manager, music publisher, record label, granting agency or music export office, please get in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;touch with us&lt;/a&gt; for onboarding. We will ask you to contribute a small sum on a crowdsourcing basis to expand our experimental project, but the small financial contribution is not a mandatory requirement. (See budget and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/#transparency&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;transparency&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Websites Is Not Easy</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-14-making_websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-14-making_websites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often find myself in a crossfire between artists and managers who want more transparency and innovation and collective management societies that see themselves as the last stable pillar for music composers, producers and performers to collect their royalties. I was in Bratislava preparing a project with the Slovak societies when a Belgian music professional, Suzanne Verschueren working in the Slovak music industry showed my Moon Moon Moon’s Journal Entry 10. A letter of complaint to the Dutch collective management societies, Buma and Stemra. In a song.  With video animation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaEKUy6KGE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-14-making_websites/playjournal10.png&#34; alt=&#34;Click on image to play video&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaEKUy6KGE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click on image to play video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately contacted Moon Moon Moon, because I had a better laugh at a music industry insider joke, and because I realized that this is one of the many bridges that we need to close if we want to build the European Music Observatory. (See our Demo Music Observatory 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Buma/Stemra reached out to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/moonmoonmoontheband&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon&lt;/a&gt; within a day of the release, and within a week they figured out where did the 1500 euro go, apologized for the mistake. The band and the collective management organization have been working together ever since as best friends forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this story is not over.  A year later, the video had less than 1000 views on YouTube.  How is it possible, when the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLA58ktFjlFijWiHTbTju4-OnswRmjKTC9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon Journal Entries&lt;/a&gt; are so good?  My 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataobservatory.eu/team/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;startup team&lt;/a&gt; decided to team up with the MMM collective to figure out how it is possible that with all the might of the artificial intelligence of YouTube’s and Spotify’s algorithms this gem is not world famous yet.  And yes, we are working with a sister society of Buma/Stemra in Slovakia to make this happen, who, in spite of their bad rep among artists, have been fighting with me side by side since 2016 to make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to design an app that connects artists and their fans in a better way, using the same might of the algorithms, but working for the small band.  We will re-release the Journal Entries as an album, and we will create algorithms that will find audiences for MMM all over in the Netherlands and Belgium, and in Japan, and probably in many other countries on the way from Utrecht to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tw0zYd0eIlk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kyoto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-links&#34;&gt;Further links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bumastemra.nl/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Buma/Stemra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/moonmoonmoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/v3upRs7?fbclid=IwAR04uKn_1TurL6cZArdwMigw9BDXpVqp9AXL3W12U94a69SeobDBT6jCbSo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moon Moon Moon on Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaEKUy6KGE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal Entry 10: Growing a Beard While Using The New Buma/Stemra Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://icons8.com/icons/set/play&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Play icon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
