<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dataandlyrics.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grants</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/grants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Governments, the EU, international organizations, and private donors often support causes of public interest with grants and donations. In some cases, these grants are aimed to help starting or sustaining economic activities. In other cases, they are supporting artistic activities or education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/author/daniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt; had been involved in the professional assessment of granting schemes and grant applications since 2000. He has learned and taught various assessment methods to evaluated EU and national grants to support valuable public infrastructure, energy savings, health investments and other causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2013 in the CEEMID project he has transferred some of this methodology to supporting music and film creation. Grants are essential to maintain the diversity and artistic quality of European music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-experience-with-grant-in-select-countries-based-on-our-music-professionals-survey-in-2019&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/music/isgrantplot-1.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Experience with grant in select countries based on our music professionals survey in 2019.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/img/music/isgrantplot-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Experience with grant in select countries based on our music professionals survey in 2019.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;em&gt;The chart is taken from the Conclusions of the  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/conclusions-policy-business-strategy-recommendations.html#support-schemes-for-developing-the-music-scene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; based on our survey in 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Anonymously surveying of musicians, their managers and music technicians about their granting experience in more than 10 countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Help granting agencies with setting realistic grant targets and grating parameters with budgeting and marketing information. (See an example 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2015-11-12-cstp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Grant design in a comprehensive, logical framework, supported by empirical evidence, artist and ecosystem data and needs, direct and indirect (effect) indicators for program controls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; We would like to persuade grant managers that &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; evaluation must be followed by &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; valuation. Original expectations must be contrasted with the effects of the grant and fed back to design better grants in the following year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/tag/grants/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;grants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Big data creates injustice.”&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil, author of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/roots-of-unity/review-weapons-of-math-destruction/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Listen Local project is aiming to create better radio playlisting, personal playlisting and concert promotion in a local context: within Slovakia or at a more specific level, Flanders or even the city of Utrecht or Budapest. We aim to place our partner’s music in local radio lists, personal playlists, and grow their fan base during the COVID-19 pandemic so that in 2021 they can eventually meet in the venues again, and carry out longer, more successful tours than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; grew out of a large, collaborative project of collective management societies, grant managers, music distributors, venues, and other music stakeholders who joined forces to collect more royalties from 2014 onwards starting with three, and eventually encompassing more than a dozen countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-problem&#34;&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are listening to music on Spotify or Apple Music, and at home on YouTube.  They are following advice from algorithms tested on hundreds of millions of people.A band in Utrecht, a rapper in Rotterdam, a dance producer in the Hague is not aiming for hundreds of millions of people.  They want to be found by their fans and like-minded people, but their music is lost literally among 100,000,000 songs on these platforms. We want 
&lt;a href=&#34;#artists&#34;&gt;artists&lt;/a&gt; in the music scene to be found by their current and future 
&lt;a href=&#34;#fans&#34;&gt;fans&lt;/a&gt;, by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/localmedia.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;local media&lt;/a&gt;, and as soon the pandemic is over, to meet in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/venues.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;local venues and festivals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a music fan is interested what is going on in Utrecht, Rotterdam or Den Haag, or on a roadtrip via Antwerpen and Gent via Lille, will never find those amazing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://listenlocal.community/artists.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bands, performers, rappers, producers&lt;/a&gt; who create wonderful content along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anybody can create playlists, but mainly Spotify, Apple, or YouTube create the playlists with their AI algorithms and their staff and their interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related posts&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;October Playlist: Wounded Egos&lt;/a&gt; - a short case study of a playlist analysis and comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-19-listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local: Open Collaboration Experiment &amp;amp; Feasibility Study&lt;/a&gt; - how you can participate in the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify: Popular Music That Nobody Listens To&lt;/a&gt; - becasue you do not want to end up on the list of 0 streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lets-do-this-together&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Do This Together!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aiming to create an alternative market measurement, marketing and recommendation engine tool that is based on open source software, open collaboration, full scientific transparency in an open collaboration with artists, small businesses and the entire music ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;create new playlists&lt;/strong&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s build up a weekly, relevant, non-exclusive playlists for music coming from Utrecht, Antwerpen, Rotterdam, Den Haag, Flanders or the Netherlands that smoothly blend in local music with relevant, spiritually or musically matching songs that fans of the Utrecht, Antwerpen, Rotterdam, Den Haag bands like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;create an app&lt;/strong&gt;!  If 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forgotify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt; can pick out songs that nobody, ever, ever listened to on Spotify, not even the performer&amp;rsquo;s mother, sister, friends, not even their enemies, than we can create an app that allows fans in Utrecht, visitors or Rotterdam and the virtual community of Den Haag to find relevant music, and to connect with music created in these communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;We are&lt;/a&gt; a bunch of musicians, musicologists, music analysts, music journalists, producers who want to make this happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an artist, you can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/ll_collector_2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;simply fill in a form&lt;/a&gt; identifying your music on Spotify, filling in a few biographical data about yourself (or your band, ensemble, group). If you represent several artists as a talent manager, music publisher, record label, granting agency or music export office, please get in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;touch with us&lt;/a&gt; for onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-use&#34;&gt;Data Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From participating artists we only ask questions that they usually post on their websites or would tell to music journalists or bloggers. We will put all this information (with some clearly stated exceptions in the registration form) on the website of the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use similar data used to analyze 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-18-october_playlist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this playlist&lt;/a&gt; about the participants&#39; music. This data is an analysis of their released music, not about the persons who play the music, or their earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not ask for any financial data, and we do not have access to any financial data of the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transparency&#34;&gt;Transparency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire budget of our project is 10,000 euros, co-funded by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sgda.sk/about-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovak Arts Council&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://soza.sk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SOZA&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ci-info.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Consolidated Independent&lt;/a&gt;, a distributor of independent music. We hope that this will be enough to create a demonstration and a detailed feasibility study that makes the user needs of Slovak managers, labels, publishers and artists themselves to continue this project in 2021. The project will be carried out by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/reprexbv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reprex&lt;/a&gt;, a Dutch start-up co-founded by the author of the Slovak Music Industry Report, the first Hungarian Music Industry Report, Private Copying in Croatia, and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceereport2020.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation for artists and music venues is &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; in the experiment. In 2020, we would like to find a viable business model that keeps this tool a good value for money for anybody in the independent music scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are asking labels, publishers, talent managers to contribute to our experimental budget on a crowdsourcing basis.  We ask for a nominal contribution from as little as 10-1000 euros on a voluntary basis.  In return. We hope to develop a tool that can make the work of independent labels and publishers easier. Any extra funding will be spent on the project at cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Observatory</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data is power, and &lt;code&gt;big data creates injustice&lt;/code&gt;.  Organizations that control large amounts of data, for example, the entire listening history of hundreds of millions of people in all major countries of the world, can train algorithms and robots that drive most of the music in the world.  They can make your investment into a sound recording successful or doomed. They can circumvent or help a local content regulation, reinforce, or disable a national cultural policy goal.  A country may introduce national artist quotas on radio, if all the youth will be personally recommended foreign songs in their music discovery age in the very same country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;We want big data to work for small venues, independent labels, startups, great and undiscovered artists.&lt;/code&gt; We believe that you cannot make a successful album launch, a market entry or introduce a successful cultural policy without large amounts of well processed and correctly analysed data. We want to create a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; that integrates the small data of many small bands, small labels, small venues, small countries, and mount correct the injustice. Make algorithms transparent and the competition fair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020 most of the data is proprietary to a few, U.S.-based companies, while most of the paying audience is the European Union. This year, many European governments started to challenge the competition conditions. The tide is turning, and we do not see this as an EU-US rivalry, because many players of the American music industry share all the pains of the European music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-15-music-observatory-launch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; in September 2020 and got into the presitgious 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI Validation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. Our demo observatory is an example how we believe the European Data Observatory should be built. An observatory is a permanent observation point for social and economic data. We want to prove that this process can be made cost-effectively and efficiently, providing a high-quality, valuable and timely product by employing best practices in research automation and open source software, using open data in open collaboration with the music industry, artists, technicians and managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to support the European music industry and our friends in North America, Australia, and all over the world to turn the tables with @ref(innovation) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/innovation.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;innovation&lt;/a&gt; coming from the open source community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to help you to create alternative recommendation engines that actually recommend songs from your country, and we want to give you very clear export market targets with the help of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/innovation.html#ai&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AI&lt;/a&gt;. Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local Initiative&lt;/a&gt; is aiming to create recommendation engines for cities and regions, and make sure that local bands are recommended to local audiences and audiences in the regions where they will be touring after the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want your evidence to stand a fighting chance against large teams of professional legal and economics teams on the other side with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/innovation.html#valuation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;proper valuations and damage claims&lt;/a&gt;.  And we want to present all those hundreds and thousands of pages automatically, going through dozens and dozens of automated &amp;ldquo;unit-tests&amp;rdquo; until nobody can find errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want you to be able to prove to your fans, the press, your economy minister that music in many countries has not been at the mercy of the taxpayer, but has been carrying far heavier tax burdens than manufacturers.  We want to make your case that the music industry plays a vital role in the European economic recovery and job creation, because we can create 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/innovation.html#valuation#eia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;economic impact assessments&lt;/a&gt; on GDP, employment, tax, import and export effects automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because music and culture are often managed at the level of cities, regions and communities, we want to give you all the data on sub-national levels, whether for regions, metropolitan areas or smaller divisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why we are launching now or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; and soon its twin, the Creative and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ccs.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cultural Sectors Demo Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, because video producers, book authors, magazine publishers, film distributors and public broadcasters are sharing the pains of the music industry. We believe that the tides are turning because both regulators and these industries have started to fight back, and there is an awful lot of value, money and creativity is at stake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; The &lt;code&gt;European Music Observatory&lt;/code&gt; should fully exploit the EU&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;open data&lt;/strong&gt; regime. (See our examples: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;our first open data release&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; It should be transparent, the indicator design should be based on open-source statistical software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; The European Music Observatory must embrace evidence-based 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/approach.html#opa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;open Policy Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; The observatory must allow a seamless 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/approach.html#dataintegration&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data integration&lt;/a&gt; between open data, and highly confidential proprietary data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; The open collaboration principle must allow an easy opt-in and opt-out for small and larger, public and private organizations, and offer for full transparency for all users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; It should not re-collect data that already exists. Instead it should create policies, synergies and incentives that bring that data to light.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Exports &amp; Imports</title>
      <link>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-export/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dataandlyrics.com/project/music-export/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Europe, like most regions of the world, is a net importer of music, but has very signficant export potential. Intra-European export is also very significant, especially from Germany, France, Sweden and the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Central and Eastern European region is relatively weak in exporting recorded and live performances, but it is among global leaders in creating export revenues from festivals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I am involved in creating predicitve models that help finding the best potential foreign market for music, and I make economic impact assessments of cultural tourism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
