<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reporting</title>
      <link>/project/reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;strong&gt;reproducible reports&lt;/strong&gt; are automated, self-refreshing documents, that contain data pipelines to the original data sources, the analytical code and the narrative assessment in a single file.  These reports are saving potentally thousands of error-prone human working during the compilation of very complex technical documentations, such as regulatory filings or complex research documentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because they are retrieving the latest available data from the Client&amp;rsquo;s internal systems and from external data sources, they can be re-freshed daily, weekly, monthly or annually. The program is refreshing the data visualizatoin, the data tables, the data citations and bibliography, and they re-create the statistical and descriptive technical annexes at every compilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages-of-reproducible-reporting&#34;&gt;Advantages of reproducible reporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reproducible report allows independent assessment and duplication of the programmatic results. This is a guarantee of high quality and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviewability&lt;/strong&gt; means that our application’s results are can be assessed and judged by our user’s experts, or experts they trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducibility&lt;/strong&gt; means that we are providing data products and tools that allow the exact duplication of our results during assessments.  This makes sure that all logical steps can be verified. Reproducibility ensures that there is no lock-in to our applications. You can always chose a different data and software vendor, or compare our results with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are creating applications that are confirmable and auditable. These are usually required by the ethical guidelines and professional standards of our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmability&lt;/strong&gt; means that using our applications findings leads to the same professional results as other available software and information. Our data products use the open-source statistical programming language R. We provide details about our algorithms and methodology to confirm our results in SPSS or Stata or sometimes even in Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auditability&lt;/strong&gt; means that our data and software is archived in a way that external auditors can later review, reproduce and confirm our findings.  This is a &lt;em&gt;stricter form of data retention&lt;/em&gt; that most organizations apply, because we do not only archive results step-by-step but all computational steps – as if your colleagues would not only save every step in Excel but also their keystrokes. While auditability is a requirement in accounting, but we are extending this approach to all the quantiative work of a professional organization in an advisory or consulting capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because our data applications are confirmable and auditable, they are the best suited to meet the internal or external regulatory compliance of organizations, for example, reporting to external regulators or supervisory boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;internationalization-and-localization&#34;&gt;Internationalization And Localization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the tables, visualizations, citations and repeating technical documentations are created programatically, they are ideally suited for multi-language environments. Our reproducible research reports are capable of creating a master (English or generic) report and the skeletons of translations with translated and well-placed, translated illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; is based on our data collection in 12 countries. Every visualization and data cited in the report is programatically created, and can be refreshed or translated automatically. It was 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;presented&lt;/a&gt; as a good case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Observatory</title>
      <link>/project/music_observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/music_observatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most important technical guideline on cultural statistics is the &lt;em&gt;Final Report of the Woking Group European Statistical System Network on Culture&lt;/em&gt; (in short: ESSnet-Culture) [@frank_guy_essnet-culture_2012].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESSnet-Culture gave a thorough overview of cultural data sources, guidelines on standardizing data, and a technical definition of the domain, including an exact mapping of cultural and creative activities and occupations to statistical nomenclatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;icet&#34;&gt;ICET model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultural participation extends beyond the market-oriented forms of &amp;ldquo;cultural consumption&amp;rdquo; and include non-market forms, such as private copying or liturgical events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ESSnet-Culture working group endorsed the ICET model of quantifying cultural participation.   The aim of the ICET model is to create representative surveys, but it is a very good framework to join survey data with other data sources.  For example, the music industry and the audiovisual sector usually has extensive transaction data on most market-oriented activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Information&lt;/em&gt;: to seek, collect and spread information on culture;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communication and community&lt;/em&gt;: to interact with others on cultural issues and to participate in cultural networks;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoyment and expression&lt;/em&gt;: to enjoy exhibitions, art performances and other forms of cultural expression, to practice the arts for leisure, and to create online content;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transaction&lt;/em&gt;: to buy art and to buy or reserve tickets for shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The generic questionnaire was developed by Jos de Haan and Andries van den Broek at the Netherlands Institute for Social Research, originally for extending cultural participation surveys to digital forms of culture [@de_haan_virtuele_2008; @de_haan_nowadays_2012]. This methodology was endorsed by ESSnet-Culture, and a rather detailed guideline can be found in the report of the &lt;em&gt;Task Force on Cultural Practices And Social Aspects Of Culture&lt;/em&gt;, in the ESSNet-Culture technical report (in general: pp. 236-242, survey methodology and harmonization pp. 242-255, recommendations: pp. 273-274; with examples on how to use the question hierarchy on pp. 397-417.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;target-population&#34;&gt;Target Population&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the target population is representative members of the general public, such as in the case of audience surveys, we use 
&lt;a href=&#34;#cap&#34;&gt;CAP&lt;/a&gt; surveys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the target population is a professional or microenterprise group, such as performing artists or record labels, we use our 
&lt;a href=&#34;#professional&#34;&gt;Professional group surveys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap&#34;&gt;CAP surveys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESSnet-Culture has reviewed several pan-European CAP manifestations, and based on the recommendations, further CAP surveys were carried out in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2001: Europeans&amp;rsquo; Participation in Cultural Activities (2001)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEE CAP 2003:  Candidate Countries Eurobarometer 2003.1 New Europeans and Culture, all later EU member states of the EU27, except for Croatia, but including Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2006:  Within the EU-SILC Module 2006 On Social Participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2007:  Includes the EU27 + United Kingdom but not Croatia, Romania and Bulgaria, conducted within Eurobarometer European Cultural Values (2007)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2013: Includes the EU27 + Croatia (only few weeks before the country&amp;rsquo;s accession.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European CAP 2015: Within the EU-SILC Module 2015 On Social/Cultural Participation And Material Deprivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on these guidelines and examples, we have carried out several in-depth music and audiovisual domain oriented CAP surveys:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2014: a large, but non-representative online sample to test the methodology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2015:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slovakia CAP 2015:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Croatia CAP 2017:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2017:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary CAP 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slovakia CAP 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;professional&#34;&gt;Professional Group Surveys&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
