<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>/talk/</link>
      <atom:link href="/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 08:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>/talk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harness the Algorithm</title>
      <link>/talk/2021_04_30_harness_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 08:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/2021_04_30_harness_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will talk about our Feasibility Study for a trustworthy music recommendation system in the context of local content regulations (minimum quotas) on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://digitalhumanities.bilgi.edu.tr/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Algorithms in Film, Television and Sound Cultures: New Ways of Knowing and Storytelling&lt;/a&gt; conference organized by the  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bilgi.edu.tr/en/academic/faculty-of-communication/film/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Faculty of Communication, Department of Film and Television&lt;/a&gt; of the Istanbul Bilgi University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the study &lt;a href=&#34;/publications/Listen_Local_Feasibility_Study_2020_SK.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in Slovak&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;/publications/Listen_Local_Feasibility_Study_2020_EN.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the entire &lt;a href=&#34;/documents/Bilgi_Conference_Program_2021.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;conference program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-conference-program&#34;&gt;The Conference Program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contemporary visual and sound cultures which increasingly rely on algorithmic analytics raise important questions on subjectivity and creativity in our ways of seeing and hearing, the ethics of the visual and the aural, the quantified self, the aesthetics and the provenance of the image.The use of algorithmic analytics to create media content, including films, series, trailers and teasers have proliferated with the advent of networking and digital streaming platforms. Digital data sets have become commodities in the global media industry. The knowledge obtained from digital data sustains the flow of knowledge on the users’ choices, governing production and consumption processes. Although algorithmic data appears to be computationally generated, it is bound with actors, networks, businesses and their ways of thinking and imagining the world. A line of research focuses on how the algorithmic calculation of taste data in film, sound and television have transformed and possibly subverted the mediums. Hence, algorithms are objects of critical cultural and political analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithms shape and condition not only ways of knowing but also ways of storytelling. Although the use of algorithms (which can be traced back to early editing) is not new in film studies, their increasing use in the production of film, including footage organization and cutting as well as dramatic writing raises questions about new ways of storytelling. To illustrate with a few examples, companies such as Scriptbook in Belgium and Vault in Israel use algorithmic software to foresee films’ box office performances by analyzing scripts. Likewise, artificial intelligence that is used to produce images from texts is used in the production process of film. In 2018, the BAFTA-nominated director Oscar Sharp teamed up with an artificial intelligence expert to create the ~7-minute film Zone Out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilisation of algorithms in sound and music is also more and more visible in various forms. Regarding popular music consumption, algorithmic engines used by music streaming platforms such as Spotify and Apple Music to offer personalised recommendations is among the prominent of these applications. Similarly, there are attempts to build an algorithmic deep-learning tool called AutoFoley, that can design synchronised sound for videos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data Day 2021</title>
      <link>/talk/2021_03_06_ood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 10:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/2021_03_06_ood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open Data Day is an annual celebration of open data all over the world. It is an opportunity to show the benefits of open data and encourage the adoption of open data policies in government, business, and civil society. Reprex is a start-up that utilizes open data with open-source reproducible research: please challenge us with your data requests and participate in our web events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Reprex Open Data Day 2021&lt;/code&gt; will be two informal conversations based on a series of run up introductory blogposts centerred around two themes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are preparing with a series of blogposts, i.e. short interviews, research introductions, tutorials and inspiring ideas for the 6th of March.   We want to create an informal, inclusive, collaborative online event on International Open Data Day 2021. Please, grab a tea, coffee, or even a beer, and join us for an informal conversation. We hope that we will finish the afternoon with ideas on new, open-data driven collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;9.30 EST / 15.30 CET&lt;/code&gt;:  &lt;strong&gt;Open collaboration in business, policy and science.&lt;/strong&gt;   Creating evidence-based policy, business strategy or scientific research with small contributions with independent components with incentives.  Short introduction with examples:  joining environmental sensory data and public opinion data on maps; creating harmonized datasets across the Arab world.  Survey harmonization, mapping, data products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;11.00 EST / 17.00 CET&lt;/code&gt;:  &lt;strong&gt;Scaling up open collaboration: making small organizations competitive with big tech in the big data era.&lt;/strong&gt;  Data sharing, data pooling, data altruism and observatories. The new European trustworthy AI and data governance agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our collaborative agenda can be found 
&lt;a href=&#34;/presentations/00d21.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  If you want to add your name, works, blogposts, send a pull request to github or send Daniel a message on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt;, Whatsapp or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration&lt;/strong&gt; is not necessary, but if you want to include your topics, LinkedIn, Github or other credentials, please get in touch till 5th March, 2020 &lt;code&gt;12.00 EST / 18.00 CET&lt;/code&gt;. We will publish the video conference link here at &lt;code&gt;9.15 EST / 15.15 CET&lt;/code&gt; (and send it to all confirmed guests in an email beforehand.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://opendataday.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Data Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprex introduction in IVIR</title>
      <link>/talk/2021_04_09_ivirtual/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 10:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/2021_04_09_ivirtual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IViRtual 9 April 2021&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
