<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mapping | Data &amp; Lyrics</title>
    <link>/tag/mapping/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/mapping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mapping</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 09:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>mapping</title>
      <link>/tag/mapping/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Localities and Location Tags</title>
      <link>/post/2021-04-14-bandcamp-librarian-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021-04-14-bandcamp-librarian-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/data-lyrics/how-to-speak-about-music-in-the-digital-age-from-taxonomies-to-folksonomies-ac2d25ed29f7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;previous blogpost &lt;/a&gt; addressed two ways of classifying music in the digital age: on the one hand, subgenre taxonomies proposed by industry vendors; on the other hand, user-defined collaborative tagging systems or folksonomies, which are more suitable for exploring niche music genres and to delve into the intricacies of an ever-evolving musical landscape. The Bandcamp Dance Librarian project takes into account both classification systems, using the taxonomy of industry vendor Beatport to detect stylistic tendencies or repertoires within the Bandcamp libraries of grassroots electronic dance music labels. This is performed by identifying clusters within a Bandcamp library based on Beatport’s subgenre labels. For instance, a cluster from the library of Samurai Music is identifed as an amalgam of Drum&amp;amp;Bass, Leftfield Bass, and to a lesser extent Trap-Hip-Hop-R&amp;amp;B. The dimension of this cluster (i.e., the number of tracks) is then displayed on a timeline among other clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bandcamp is a reputable publishing platform aimed towards independent musicians that encourages the use of tags (folksonomies) by its users — accordingly, the Librarian takes into account the artist/label tags added to the Bandcamp pages. It is therefore possible to compare the industry taxonomy of Beatport with artist folksonomies, as long as such tags are provided on Bandcamp or further investigation around particular folksonomies is performed. For instance, a representative track from the cluster identified above is described, among others, as “homemade weaponry” by the eponymous artist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;homemade_weaponry.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;homemade weaponry&#34; title=&#34;homemade weaponry&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bandcamp link: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://homemadeweapons.bandcamp.com/track/hawkeye&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://homemadeweapons.bandcamp.com/track/hawkeye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few more (technical) details about the project: The classifier is based on the methodology of Caparrini et al. (2020), using 92 audio features extracted from electronic dance music tracks within Beatport’s Top-100 lists in various subgenres. Bandcamp offers freely available full-length (low-bitrate) streams as track previews, which are suitable for musical feature extraction and analysis. Complete Bandcamp libraries are processed, and each track’s class (subgenre) probabilities are determined by the classifier, which forms the basis for the clustering algorithm. The number of clusters can be set in advance or calculated automatically. Results are provided in a PDF file with links to up to three representative Bandcamp tracks (if possible, from different artists) in each group and their attached tags (folksonomies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remainder of this post presents two use cases focused on localities and location tags (signifying cities, countries and sometimes nationalities). Such tags help putting local music scenes on the map; in the case of particularly prolific or creative cities they can be connected to specific genres too. Most commonly, they identify the city or country where the music label or the artist is based. Electronic music production requires relatively accessible tools and is usually carried out entirely by the producer; prominent artists are often running record labels that are integral to promoting music and structuring scenes. These aspects contribute to the burgeoning of independent music communities across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first example draws on features extracted from 36 Bandcamp label libraries. The libraries are taken from a piece of music journalism (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cdm.link/2020/05/underground-techno-labels-a-bandcamp-guide/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://cdm.link/2020/05/underground-techno-labels-a-bandcamp-guide/&lt;/a&gt;) addressing some of Bandcamp’s “underground” techno labels that “have a sense of community, even [as] a small collective of a few friends unlikely to catch larger attention”. Such specialist music press is characterized by Canadian sociologist Sarah Thorton as &lt;em&gt;niche media&lt;/em&gt;, which is particularly efficient in categorizing social groups, classifying sounds, defining cultural distinctions and baptizing genres. The list of labels offered in the CDM article is suitable for our current aim: a blink into the sound of “underground” techno labels based on their Bandcamp location tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collection includes 14.200 tracks analyzed by the Librarian. A total of 97.334 tags are attached to the tracks, as illustrated by the word cloud below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image_2_tags.png&#34; alt=&#34;A total of 97.334 tags are attached to the tracks&#34; title=&#34;A total of 97.334 tags are attached to the tracks&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, 12000 tags refer to locations or nationalities. The majority of the location tags designate cities — more often than not, these are where the labels are based:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image3_location_tags.png&#34; alt=&#34;Location Tags&#34; title=&#34;Location Tags&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following table shows the total number of tags pertaining to each location (city), and the number of labels that tagged these cities at least once within their Bandcamp library:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;Tags per city&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note: United Kingdom has been conflated with London for the purposes of this illustration.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one way or another, the relative relevance of these cities within the global techno circuit can be inferred from these numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By instructing the Librarian to treat as a single cluster all tracks that are tagged with the same city label, an attempt can be made to delineate an overall — although not the only — sound that can be comfortably identified with a location. Berlin, for instance, can be classified as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;berlin_classification.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Berlin, for instance, can be classified like this&#34; title=&#34;Berlin, for instance, can be classified like this.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bandcamp links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pacou.bandcamp.com/track/dancer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://pacou.bandcamp.com/track/dancer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://flashrec.bandcamp.com/track/anml-mthr-alarm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://flashrec.bandcamp.com/track/anml-mthr-alarm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ostgut.bandcamp.com/track/scenario&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://ostgut.bandcamp.com/track/scenario&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK is another noteworthy example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image11.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bandcamp links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://perctrax.bandcamp.com/track/zelo-radial-remix&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://perctrax.bandcamp.com/track/zelo-radial-remix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://perctrax.bandcamp.com/track/ganymede-perc-dub-mix&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://perctrax.bandcamp.com/track/ganymede-perc-dub-mix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://planetaryassaultsystems.bandcamp.com/track/om-the-def&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://planetaryassaultsystems.bandcamp.com/track/om-the-def&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, defining a single cluster will not account for the sonic variety of such influential cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, the detected subgenres are concentrated on the various flavours of techno. For more stylistic variety, we can use the Librarian with different music styles and datasets. The following example concerns artists that could be affiliated with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://listenlocal.community/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local initiative&lt;/a&gt;. Our goal was to focus on Slovakian artists on Spotify that have Bandcamp presence too, and use the Librarian as support for the recommendations. A sample of 82 such artists was selected; their Bandcamp libraries included 2379 tracks. In total, 17.881 tags were attached to these tracks, among which 550 were unique. The tag frequencies are illustrated below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image12.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image13.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the word cloud also suggests, the tracks cover a variety of genres. Accordingly, our classifier should be more general in scope than in the case of the techno labels. A suitable option is the MSD-MusiCNN TensorFlow auto-tagging model supplied with the Essentia library [
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mtg.github.io/essentia-labs/news/tensorflow/2020/01/16/tensorflow-models-released/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://mtg.github.io/essentia-labs/news/tensorflow/2020/01/16/tensorflow-models-released/&lt;/a&gt;], which predicts LastFm’s top-50 music classification tags (a selection of 24 tags referring to music genres or styles were predicted for the purposes of this demonstration).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One can get a first feel of the stylistic tendencies within the sample by looking at the classification tags with the highest mean probability values:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;rock 0.169777&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hip-Hop 0.141943&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;electronic 0.136527&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;alternative 0.079971&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pop 0.066009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, the five most representative genres or styles in our collection are rock, hip-hop, electronic, alternative and pop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more refined perspective is gained after clustering the tracks based on their tag probability values. The algorithm proposes three clusters by default, crystallized around the rock (alternative/pop), hip-hop, and electronic (ambient/dance) genres:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image14.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image15.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bandcamp links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://papyllon.bandcamp.com/track/never-felt-so-pure&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://papyllon.bandcamp.com/track/never-felt-so-pure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ills.bandcamp.com/track/laugh-will-tear-us-apart&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://ills.bandcamp.com/track/laugh-will-tear-us-apart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://theswanbride.bandcamp.com/track/styx-travel-inc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://theswanbride.bandcamp.com/track/styx-travel-inc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image17.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bandcamp links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://piosquad.bandcamp.com/track/worldwide-feat-heltah-skeltah&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://piosquad.bandcamp.com/track/worldwide-feat-heltah-skeltah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://nirobaits.bandcamp.com/track/awesome-ft-candy-mane-otecko-and-mr-sulo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://nirobaits.bandcamp.com/track/awesome-ft-candy-mane-otecko-and-mr-sulo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://everydays.bandcamp.com/track/mal-m-sto-feat-sinuz-prod-by-sinuz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://everydays.bandcamp.com/track/mal-m-sto-feat-sinuz-prod-by-sinuz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image18.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image19.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bandcamp links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurkus.bandcamp.com/track/interstellar&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://kurkus.bandcamp.com/track/interstellar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://nightlines.bandcamp.com/track/udia-istoty&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://nightlines.bandcamp.com/track/udia-istoty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://noreligionlabel.bandcamp.com/track/go-outside-outro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://noreligionlabel.bandcamp.com/track/go-outside-outro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track examples provide the closest matches with the identified subgenres, and the complete clusters are not restricted to these styles. However, by increasing the cluster number it is possible to further refine the results. By increasing it to five groups, for example, a rock/electronic/pop fusion group is also identified, and metal appears as a new determining genre:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image20.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image21.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bandcamp links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://monikinokino.bandcamp.com/track/be-ky-radio-edit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://monikinokino.bandcamp.com/track/be-ky-radio-edit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://midilidi.bandcamp.com/track/koupali-t-tajemn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://midilidi.bandcamp.com/track/koupali-t-tajemn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://denaftb.bandcamp.com/track/if-its-written-outro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://denaftb.bandcamp.com/track/if-its-written-outro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image22.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image23.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt_text&#34; title=&#34;image_tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bandcamp links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://triggerband.bandcamp.com/track/treachery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://triggerband.bandcamp.com/track/treachery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://signumregis.bandcamp.com/track/unfold-the-mystery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://signumregis.bandcamp.com/track/unfold-the-mystery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hudba.zocivoci.sk/track/prehra-a-zmizn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://hudba.zocivoci.sk/track/prehra-a-zmizn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to have a look at these and other stylistic groups (or search based on location tags), a working demo of the Librarian loaded with the Listen Local dataset is available at: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/data-lyrics/bitly.com/bandcamp-librarian&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bitly.com/bandcamp-librarian&lt;/a&gt; . Happy discoveries!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alonso-Jiménez, Pablo, Dmitry Bogdanov, Jordi Pons and Xavier Serra. 2020. TensorFlow Audio Models in Essentia. arXiv:2003.07393.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besseny, Amelia. 2020. Lost in spotify: folksonomy and wayfinding functions in spotify’s interface and companion apps. &lt;em&gt;Popular Communication&lt;/em&gt;. no. 18 (1): 1–17.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caparrini, Antonio, Javier Arroyo, Laura Pérez-Molina and Jaime Sánchez-Hernández. 2020. “Automatic subgenre classification in an electronic dance music taxonomy.” Journal of New Music Research 49(12):1–16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles, Christopher. 2019. “Part of the Tribe: Crews, Residence, and Affiliation in Underground Dance Music Scenes”. IASPM Journal, no. (9) 2: 55–74.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thornton, Sarah. 1996. &lt;em&gt;Club Cultures: Music, Media, and Subcultural Capital&lt;/em&gt;. Hanover: University Press of New England.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save The Date: Open Data Day 2021 on 6th March</title>
      <link>/post/2021-02-03-save-the-date-odd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 09:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021-02-03-save-the-date-odd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open data is not only a cheap resource for scientists or NGOs, but a serious business opportunity for the business sector, too. The European Union has been promoting the business reuse of data collected at the taxpayer’s expense since 2003 – and our team members have been involved since the beginning. This is a particularly good deal opportunity for small businesses and organizations that do not have a big data infrastructure or budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;Open Data Day 2021&lt;/strong&gt;, our goal is to demonstrate how our open-source software can connect different sources and types of data to generate new knowledge about environmental sustainability by combining several perspectives: from air pollution sensors, public perceptions and opinions, and government policies. We will show how to connect environmental sensory data, environmental spending, and opinion polling data about the environment together with open-source software from open data sources, to follow the four highlighted topics of #ODD21. We’ll offer tutorials, webinars, and Q&amp;amp;A based around these topics.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-will-show-how-to-use-open-access-survey-data-and-how-to-plot-results-on-a-map-this-dataset-was-used-in-an-empirical-study-on-the-structural-conditions-of-book-piracy-in-global-and-european-academiahttpsreprexnlpublicationscholarly_pirate_libraries_2020-published-in-plos-one&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;We will show how to use open access survey data, and how to plot results on a map. This dataset was used in an empirical study on the structural conditions of book piracy in global and European academia published in PLOS One.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We will show how to use open access survey data, and how to plot results on a map. This dataset was used in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/publication/scholarly_pirate_libraries_2020/&#34;&gt;empirical study on the structural conditions of book piracy in global and European academia&lt;/a&gt; published in PLOS One.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who would think that you can use &amp;ldquo;raw inflation data components&amp;rdquo; to create &lt;em&gt;cultural&lt;/em&gt; indicators? Working with open data often feels like working with raw diamonds, because most open data was originally collected and processed for a different use that you would have in mind. But this is our expertise – if you want to see public financing, opinion polling or sensory information about environmental and sustainability issues, &lt;strong&gt;do challenge us&lt;/strong&gt;. Be part of our Open Data Day, tell us about your research needs, and we’ll bring some open data to the surface to start the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://opendataday.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Data Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/talk/open-data-day-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Our Event Page&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;ndash; with more details about guests and topics every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save The Date: Open Data Day 2021 on 6th March</title>
      <link>/post/2021-02-12-opendataday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 09:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021-02-12-opendataday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open data is not only a cheap resource for scientists or NGOs, but a serious business opportunity for the business sector, too. The European Union has been promoting the business reuse of data collected at the taxpayer’s expense since 2003 – and our team members have been involved since the beginning. This is a particularly good deal opportunity for small businesses and organizations that do not have a big data infrastructure or budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;Open Data Day 2021&lt;/strong&gt;, our goal is to demonstrate how our open-source software can connect different sources and types of data to generate new knowledge about environmental sustainability by combining several perspectives: from air pollution sensors, public perceptions and opinions, and government policies. We will show how to connect environmental sensory data, environmental spending, and opinion polling data about the environment together with open-source software from open data sources, to follow the four highlighted topics of #ODD21. We’ll offer tutorials, webinars, and Q&amp;amp;A based around these topics.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-will-show-how-to-use-open-access-survey-data-and-how-to-plot-results-on-a-map-this-dataset-was-used-in-an-empirical-study-on-the-structural-conditions-of-book-piracy-in-global-and-european-academiahttpsreprexnlpublicationscholarly_pirate_libraries_2020-published-in-plos-one&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;We will show how to use open access survey data, and how to plot results on a map. This dataset was used in an empirical study on the structural conditions of book piracy in global and European academia published in PLOS One.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/Eurobarometer_79_2_files/limitedlibrary-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We will show how to use open access survey data, and how to plot results on a map. This dataset was used in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/publication/scholarly_pirate_libraries_2020/&#34;&gt;empirical study on the structural conditions of book piracy in global and European academia&lt;/a&gt; published in PLOS One.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who would think that you can use &amp;ldquo;raw inflation data components&amp;rdquo; to create &lt;em&gt;cultural&lt;/em&gt; indicators? Working with open data often feels like working with raw diamonds, because most open data was originally collected and processed for a different use that you would have in mind. But this is our expertise – if you want to see public financing, opinion polling or sensory information about environmental and sustainability issues, &lt;strong&gt;do challenge us&lt;/strong&gt;. Be part of our Open Data Day, tell us about your research needs, and we’ll bring some open data to the surface to start the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://opendataday.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Data Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/talk/open-data-day-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Our Event Page&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;ndash; with more details about guests and topics every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
